<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sddc on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/sddc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sddc on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/sddc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The mobile SDDC and EUC lab environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/06/23/sddc-mobile-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 09:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/06/23/sddc-mobile-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>With my company I work for (Ictivity ), we decided to develop a mobile Software Defined Data Center (SDDC) and End User Computing (EUC) lab environment. This mobile lab environment will be used to demo the VMware SDDC and End User Computing (EUC) stack with integration of third party solutions. One of the reasons to use a physical lab environment instead of cloud services was flexibility and having no dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure VSAN on HP Servers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/06/09/vsan-hp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 10:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/06/09/vsan-hp/</guid>
      <description>For a new End User Computing (EUC) project I installed a Hybrid Virtual SAN (VSAN) configuration on HP Proliant server hardware. VSAN will be used as storage layer for VDIs. Each HP Proliant DL360 Gen9 server has the following components:&#xA;HP Workload Accelerator as caching device HP Smart Array P440 controller with several 10k SAS disks as capacity tier To enable VSAN the the first thing to do is to check the VSAN HCL(link )</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Europe 2013&amp;ndash;The Software-Defined Data Center (SDDC) recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/10/20/vmworld-europe-2013the-software-defined-data-center-sddc-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 20:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/10/20/vmworld-europe-2013the-software-defined-data-center-sddc-recap/</guid>
      <description>Last week i attended VMworld Europe in Barcelona. The theme was “Defy Convention”. Here’s an overview of the VMware focus for the coming year(s):&#xA;It’s all about delivering IT as a Service. IT as a Services gives the following answers:&#xA;On-demand access to any device; Cost transparency; Any cloud, any platform; Programmable and automated infrastructure. To deliver IT as a Service VMware has for the coming year(s) the following focus areas:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
