<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in VMware on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 13:23:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Searching for VMware resources?</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/09/14/vmware-resources-list/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:29:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/09/14/vmware-resources-list/</guid><description>Here’s an overview of VMware (Broadcom) resources I frequently use.
VMware Downloads Name Description Link VMware Product Downloads All VMware product downloads. https://customerconnect.vmware.com/en/downloads/#all_products VMware Patches VMware patches https://customerconnect.vmware.com/patch/ VMware Trials VMware Trials product downloads such as the https://www.vmware.com/trials-test-drives.html VMware Tools releases All VMware tools release https://packages.vmware.com/tools/releases/ VMware Flings Unofficial apps built by VMware employees to enhance VMware products https://flings.</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 32-2023</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/08/15/the-latest-technology-news-week-32-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:02:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/08/15/the-latest-technology-news-week-32-2023/</guid><description>The latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, VMware, and other partners with a focus on End User Computing (EUC).
Microsoft Azure
Generally available: Azure Blob Storage Cold Tier. Link Public preview: Azure Storage Mover support for SMB and Azure Files. Link Subscribe to the Azure Stack HCI Newsletter. Link Azure managed disk types overview.</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 28-31 2023</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/08/07/the-latest-technology-news-week-28-till-31-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:13:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/08/07/the-latest-technology-news-week-28-till-31-2023/</guid><description>After a great holiday an overview of the latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, VMware, and other partners with a focus on End User Computing (EUC).
Microsoft Azure
Hot patching is now available for Windows Server VMs on Azure with Desktop Experience! Link Windows Server end-of-support (EOS): Upgrade seamlessly with Azure Migrate (Public preview).</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 23-2023</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/06/10/the-latest-technology-news-week-23-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 06:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/06/10/the-latest-technology-news-week-23-2023/</guid><description>Here’s the weekly latest technology news from Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD), Windows 365, and VMware. The main focus is based on Cloud and End User Computing (EUC) technology.
Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD)
Nerdio Modeler for Azure Virtual Desktop. Modeler prompts for a handful of inputs and produces an easy-to-understand cost analysis, including auto-scale savings.</description></item><item><title>Remove expired root certificates from a vCenter Server the easy way</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/04/17/quick-tip-remove-expired-root-certificates-from-a-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 17:44:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/04/17/quick-tip-remove-expired-root-certificates-from-a-vcenter-server/</guid><description>I see a lot of vCenter Servers that have expired root certificates. In the vCenter Server Appliance Administration section under Certificate Management, you can see the expired certificates.
Cleaning up expired root certificates from the vCenter Server can be done by using the &amp;ldquo;vecs-cli&amp;rdquo; command on the vCenter Server Appliance (In the vSphere Client this is not possible).</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI cannot be installed or updated because the authenticode signature of the file error</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/03/07/powercli-cannot-be-installed-or-updated-because-the-authenticode-signature-of-the-file-error/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 17:38:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/03/07/powercli-cannot-be-installed-or-updated-because-the-authenticode-signature-of-the-file-error/</guid><description>On a new Windows Server 2022 VM I tried to install a fresh copy of VMware.PowerCLI (13.0.0) with the following PowerShell command:
Install-Module VMware.PowerCLI -Scope CurrentUser The following error occurred:
PackageManagement\Install-Package : The module &amp;lsquo;VMware.VimAutomation.License&amp;rsquo; cannot be installed or updated because the authenticode signature of the file &amp;lsquo;VMware.VimAutomation.License.cat&amp;rsquo; is not valid.</description></item><item><title>An unattended installation of VMware Tools 12 generates a 2711 error</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2022/04/14/vmware-tools-error-2711/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 11:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2022/04/14/vmware-tools-error-2711/</guid><description>For a new Windows 10 image build, I used the latest supported VMware Tools In this case that was VMware Tools 12.0.0. VMware Tools is deployed using an unattended installation such as:
e:\setup64.exe /S /v &amp;#34;/qb REBOOT=R ADDLOCAL=All REMOVE=AppDefense,Hgfs,CBHelper,VmwTimeProvider,VSS,NetworkIntrospection,FileIntrospection&amp;#34; /l c:\windows\temp\vmware_tools_install.log During the installation of VMware Tools, the following error occurred: &amp;ldquo;The installer has encountered an unexpected error installing this package.</description></item><item><title>Configure Microsoft Teams offloading in VMware Horizon</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/08/25/configure-microsoft-teams-offloading-in-vmware-horizon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 06:41:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/08/25/configure-microsoft-teams-offloading-in-vmware-horizon/</guid><description>With VMware Horizon 8 or the new naming format, Horizon 2006 (YYMM) Microsoft Teams offloading / media optimization is supported. Media Optimization for Microsoft Teams redirects audio calls, video calls, and viewing desktop shares for a seamless experience between the client system and the remote session without negatively affecting the virtual infrastructure and overloading the network.</description></item><item><title>NVMe SSDs are not recognized anymore after upgrading to VMware ESXi 7</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/04/09/nvme-ssds-are-not-recognized-anymore-after-upgrading-to-vmware-esxi-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:47:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/04/09/nvme-ssds-are-not-recognized-anymore-after-upgrading-to-vmware-esxi-7/</guid><description>Last week VMware released vSphere 7. The first thing I did was upgrading my homelab. My homelab has two hosts (Shuttle SH370R6 Plus and a Shuttle SH370R8 Plus). After upgrading my hosts from VMware ESXi 6.7 Update 3 to VMware ESXi 7, the NVMe SSDs are not recognized anymore. I Have the following NVMe SSD disks in the hosts:</description></item><item><title>VMware Tools pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers delivered by Windows Update</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/01/09/vmware-tools-pvscsi-and-vmxnet3-drivers-delivered-by-windows-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 13:20:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/01/09/vmware-tools-pvscsi-and-vmxnet3-drivers-delivered-by-windows-update/</guid><description>Today I was updating a Windows Server 2016 template VM with Windows Updates. During the update, I notice that the pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers are updated by the Windows Updates process.
In 10.3.10 of VMware Tools, the pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers available through Windows Update for Windows Server 2016 and Windows Server 2019 Operating Systems.</description></item><item><title>VMware Tools installation and upgrade tips and tricks</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/09/09/vmware-tools-installation-and-upgrade-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 08:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/09/09/vmware-tools-installation-and-upgrade-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>The VMware Tools package provides drivers (such as VMXNET3, PVSCSI, SVGA etc.) and services that enhance the performance of virtual machines and make several vSphere features easy to use. Here are some tips and tricks when working with VMware Tools:
An overview of the VMware Tools versions mapping can be found here, link The latest VMware Tools versions can be downloaded from the following links: link and link Within VMware ESXi, the VMware Tools are located under: /vmimages/tools-isoimages The latest VMware Tools version 10.</description></item><item><title>Blue circle in the vSphere client after upgrading to vCenter Server 6.7 Update 2</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/04/24/blue-circle-in-the-vsphere-client-after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-6-7-update-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:02:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/04/24/blue-circle-in-the-vsphere-client-after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-6-7-update-2/</guid><description>After upgrading the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to version 6.7 Update 2, I tried to log in using the vSphere Client. After entering the credentials an endless blue running circle appears.
In the VAMI interface (https://vcsa-fqdn:5480) of the VCSA, the health statistics of all the components are green (okay) so I decided to reboot the VCSA.</description></item><item><title>VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) 3.4 RADIUS license change</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/02/13/vmware-unified-access-gateway-uag-3-4-radius-license-change/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 07:25:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/02/13/vmware-unified-access-gateway-uag-3-4-radius-license-change/</guid><description>The VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) acts as reverse proxy and tunnels sessions (PCoIP and Blast) to desktops and remote apps. Besides Horizon support, new features are added for AirWatch and Identity Manager. With version 3.4, the VMware Unified Access Gateway is offered in three editions based on the Horizon or Workspace ONE licenses:</description></item><item><title>Announcements made at VMworld 2018 Europe</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/11/06/announcements-made-at-vmworld-2018-europe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 11:33:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/11/06/announcements-made-at-vmworld-2018-europe/</guid><description>In Augustus I did a blog post (link ) about the announcements made at VMworld 2018 US. This week it’s time for VMworld Europe in Barcelona with 12000 attendees. The vision of VMware is still the same as the last years: any cloud, any application, any device.
In this blog post an overview of new announcements made from VMworld Europe 2018:</description></item><item><title>Upgrading a vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to version 6.7</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/04/23/upgrade-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-to-version-6-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 06:48:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/04/23/upgrade-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-to-version-6-7/</guid><description>Last week VMware launched vSphere 6.7. In this blog post I show how easy it is to upgrade a vCenter Server 6.x appliance to a new vCenter Server 6.7 appliance using the graphical interface (GUI) upgrade. The GUI upgrade uses a two stage process:
Stage 1: Deploy a new vCenter Server 6.</description></item><item><title>Top vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) troubleshooting commands</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/03/06/top-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-troubleshooting-commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 14:17:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/03/06/top-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-troubleshooting-commands/</guid><description>During the configuration and troubleshooting of vCenter Server Appliances (VCSA) I maintain a list of commands that I frequently use. This list contains my top configuration and troubleshooting VCSA commands:
Enable access the Bash shell: shell.set –enabled true Permanently configure the default Shell to BASH for Root: chsh -s /bin/bash root Log location of the VCSA: /var/log/vmware/vsphere-client/logs/ VCSA service management: Check status service-control –status –all List services service-control –list Stop all services service-control –stop –all Start all services service-control –start –all Join the AD domain from PSC: /opt/likewise/bin/domainjoin-cli join domain.</description></item><item><title>What to know about Spectre and Meltdown with VMware environments</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/01/10/know-spectre-meltdown-vmware-environments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 21:08:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/01/10/know-spectre-meltdown-vmware-environments/</guid><description>You probably heard about the two massive security flaws: Spectre and Meltdown (link ). These security flaws allow attackers to access “secure” data by compromising privileged processor memory from major manufacturers, including Intel, AMD, and ARM. So the most CPUs are affected by Spectre and Meltdown security flaws! In this blogpost I highlight what to do in VMware environments.</description></item><item><title>Horizon Access Point / Unified Access Gateway (UAG) implementation tips</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/05/16/horizon-access-point-unified-access-gateway-uag-implementation-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 06:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/05/16/horizon-access-point-unified-access-gateway-uag-implementation-tips/</guid><description>In 2013 I created a blog post with some tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server (link ). Now the Unified Access Gateway (UAG) is replacing the VMware Security Server. So it’s time for a new blog post with some implementation tips about VMware Access Point / Unified Access Gateway (UAG).</description></item><item><title>Fix orphaned vSAN objects</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/03/21/fix-orphaned-vsan-objects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/03/21/fix-orphaned-vsan-objects/</guid><description>In the vSphere Web client an orphaned vSAN object was listed named:
/vmfs/volume/vsanuuid From the vSphere Web Client you cannot manage orphaned vSAN objects . To check and fix orphaned vSAN objects, the Ruby vSphere Console (RVC) is needed. The &amp;lsquo;vsan.check_state&amp;rsquo; command checks if VMs and Virtual SAN objects are valid and accessible.</description></item><item><title>Update the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) without internet</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/03/01/update-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-without-internet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 13:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/03/01/update-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-without-internet/</guid><description>In this blog post I highlight how to patch or update a single vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) without having an internet connection. The patch will be stored on a temporarily web server that is installed on a Windows machine. In this example we update the vCenter Server Appliance version from 6.</description></item><item><title>Patch VMware ESXi hosts by command line</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/02/15/patch-vmware-esxi-6-5-hosts-command-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 20:08:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/02/15/patch-vmware-esxi-6-5-hosts-command-line/</guid><description>There a several ways to patch a VMware ESXi server. vSphere Update Manager (VUM) can update for example a complete ESXi host cluster fully automatic. vSphere Update Manager requires a vCenter Server. When you don’t have a vCenter Server patching can be done from the command line.
Here is a quick overview of how to patch an ESXi 6.</description></item><item><title>Drive mapping not working with User Environment Manager (UEM)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/12/21/drive-mapping-not-working-user-environment-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 14:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/12/21/drive-mapping-not-working-user-environment-manager/</guid><description>During a Horizon View implementation with User Environment Manager (UEM) 9.1 the drive mappings don’t show up for some with a Windows 10 VDI. The flexEngine log shows the drive mapping was successfully.
2016-12-16 15:18:45.084 [INFO ] Successfully mapped drive ‘G:’ to ‘\filesrv-01\apps$’ (‘Applicaties.xml’)
When opening an elevated command prompt and type the command net use the drive mappings where displayed and accessible.</description></item><item><title>VMware extends the hybrid cloud with Amazon Web Services (AWS)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/10/13/vmware-extends-hybrid-cloud-amazon-web-services-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 21:43:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/10/13/vmware-extends-hybrid-cloud-amazon-web-services-aws/</guid><description>VMware and Amazon Web Services (AWS) will partnering together to bring a new a VMware vSphere-based service, running on the AWS Cloud, that will make it easier and faster to run applications, across a hybrid cloud environment.
It&amp;rsquo;s called the &amp;ldquo;VMware Cloud on AWS&amp;rdquo;. The infrastructure looks like:
The VMware Cloud on AWS includes the following components:</description></item><item><title>Upgrading VMware Update Manager to 5.5 U3e fails</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/10/12/upgrading-vmware-update-manager-5-5-u3e-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 12:24:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/10/12/upgrading-vmware-update-manager-5-5-u3e-fails/</guid><description>When upgrading VMware Update Manager (VUM) to 5.5 Update 3e the following error occurs:
VMware Workstation unrecoverable error: (vthread-3) GetProcAddress: Failed to resolve ENGINE_load_aesni: 127
This issue occurs when upgrading to VMware Update Manager to 5.5 Update 3e. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this error when upgrading to 5.5U3e at different customer sites.</description></item><item><title>Disable Virtual SAN health check alarms</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/09/07/disable-virtual-san-health-check-alarms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 06:38:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/09/07/disable-virtual-san-health-check-alarms/</guid><description>When using PCIE/NVMe SSDs in the capacity layer of Virtual SAN, the SSDs are generating a warning for the “Hardware Compatibility – SCSI Controller on Virtual SAN HCL” health check, even when the devices are on the Virtual SAN HCL.
The &amp;ldquo;Hardware Compatibility - SCSI Controller on Virtual SAN HCL**&amp;rdquo;** health check cannot detect the PCIE/NVMe SSDs because they do not use standard I/O controllers.</description></item><item><title>Horizon View Administrator displays a blank error window</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/03/29/horizon-7-blank-admin-screen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 06:29:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/03/29/horizon-7-blank-admin-screen/</guid><description>After upgrading to VMware Horizon View 7, the administrator webpage displays a blank error window when trying to connect using the IP address of the Connection Server.
Horizon View 7 adds new security features that checks for the original URL for the web request. If not, it rejects the request and display the blank error window.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Log Insight 3.3 available for free</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/03/03/log-insight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 18:55:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2016/03/03/log-insight/</guid><description>VMware released vRealize Log Insight 3.3. vRealize Log Insight is a log monitoring and analytics dashboarding tool like Splunk.
In version 3.3 a new product license is added. For each vCenter Server Standard license you will get a free 25 OSI pack license for vRealize Log Insight. So every customer with a vCenter standard license can use vRealize Log Insight with no additional costs.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Agent installation order</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/11/11/vmware-horizon-view-agent-installation-order/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 08:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/11/11/vmware-horizon-view-agent-installation-order/</guid><description>When configuring a Windows VDI desktop or RDSH session with Horizon, different software components must be installed such as the VMware Tools and the VMware Horizon View Agent. When using User Environment Manager and App Volumes they require an agent too. All these software components must be installed in the correct order in the master/golden image to prevent problems such as for example a black screen when connecting to a Windows VDI desktop using the PCoIP protocol.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESXi6 Password Policy</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/10/07/vmware-esxi6-password-policy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 10:08:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/10/07/vmware-esxi6-password-policy/</guid><description>With VMware ESXi 6 the password policy is changed and require to use more complex passwords. The password policy in ESXi 6 has the following requirements:
Passwords must contain characters from at least three character classes. Passwords containing characters from three character classes must be at least seven characters long. Passwords containing characters from all four character classes must be at least seven characters long.</description></item><item><title>Tested: VMware snapshot management with Snapwatcher</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/06/02/tested-vmware-snapshot-management-with-snapwatcher/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 07:56:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/06/02/tested-vmware-snapshot-management-with-snapwatcher/</guid><description>To monitor and manage VMware Virtual Machine Snapshots Opvizor has released a tool called Snapwatcher. As consultant I see often that admins don’t have an overview of all the snapshots that exists in their environment. The main concerns with Virtual Machine snapshots are:
Snapshots are created and forgot to remove Snapshots can very quickly grow in size Snapshots filling datastore space Delta files may cause decreased Virtual Machine and host performance In this review Opvizor Snapwatcher is tested.</description></item><item><title>The end of Tera1 zero client support in VMware Horizon View 6</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 14:01:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</guid><description>The Tera1 zero clients has reached their limits on new features that can be added and the ability to support new features of Horizon View such as RDSH. Teradici supports the following combinations:
ProcessorFirmwareHorizon View Version supportVMware CertifiedTera24.8.06.1YesTera24.7.16.0YesTera14.7.16.0.1No (*2)(*2) Tera1 zero clients are certified on VMware Horizon View 5.3 and earlier.</description></item><item><title>VMware tools update fails on ESXi 6 hosts with Dutch Operating System VMs</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/04/vmware-tools-update-fails-on-esxi-6-hosts-with-dutch-operating-systems-vms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 09:35:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/04/vmware-tools-update-fails-on-esxi-6-hosts-with-dutch-operating-systems-vms/</guid><description>After upgrading all the hosts in the lab environment to VMware ESXi 6, I tried to upgrade the VMware tools version of a Dutch Windows 7 golden VM used by VMware Horizon View. The VMware tools upgrade fails with the following message:
VMware Tools Setup Wizard ended prematurely
This is a known bug in VMware ESXi 6.</description></item><item><title>vCenter Server 6 and the vPostgres database</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/03/25/vcenter-server-6-and-the-vpostgres-database/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 13:53:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/03/25/vcenter-server-6-and-the-vpostgres-database/</guid><description>In vCenter Server 5.x the embedded SQL Express database supports a maximum of 5 hosts and 50 Virtual Machines. With vCenter Server 6 the embedded database is changes from SQL Express to a vPostgress database. The vPostgres database supports a maximum of 20 hosts and 200 VMs. In comparison the vPostgres database on the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 6 supports 1000 hosts and 10000.</description></item><item><title>VIBSearch Finding VIB versions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/12/17/vibsearch-finding-vib-versions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 09:28:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/12/17/vibsearch-finding-vib-versions/</guid><description>VIBSearch is a simple PowerShell script with a GUI that will search for a specified VIB or all the VIBS installed on the ESXi hosts. A VIB stands for vSphere Installation Bundle (VIB). VIBs are used to package and distribute ESXi software such as drivers. The GUI is designed with SAPIEN PowerShell Studio 2014.</description></item><item><title>Identify the Single Sign-On (SSO) deployment method for the vCenter Server</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/11/26/identify-single-sign-sso-deployment-method-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 14:20:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/11/26/identify-single-sign-sso-deployment-method-vcenter-server/</guid><description>With vSphere 5.5 you have the following deployment methods for Single Sign-On (SSO):
vCenter Single Sign-On for your first vCenter Server vCenter Single Sign-On for an additional vCenter Server in an existing site (formerly HA Cluster) vCenter Single Sign-On for an additional vCenter Server with a new site (formerly Multisite) Once SSO is installed it can be usefull to identify what deployment options are used for example in a Site Recovery Manager (SRM) deployment.</description></item><item><title>Reset the root password of an ESXi server</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/05/21/reset-the-root-password-on-an-esxi-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 14:02:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/05/21/reset-the-root-password-on-an-esxi-server/</guid><description>Some time ago I needed to make a SSH connection to a new installed ESXi server. The default root password the customer was using was not working. The admin who installed the ESXi server didn’t known the password anymore. So i needed to reset the password. The VMware Knowledge Base states the following on resetting the root password on ESXi:</description></item><item><title>Update the vCenter inventory in vCAC manually</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/23/update-the-vcenter-inventory-in-vcac-manually/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 09:58:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/23/update-the-vcenter-inventory-in-vcac-manually/</guid><description>When creating a new template in vCenter and want to use the new created template in a blueprint, the blueprint will not list the template because the vCenter inventory isn’t updated in vCAC. By default vCAC will update the vCenter inventory once a day. To manually update the vCenter inventory in vCAC 6.</description></item><item><title>What&amp;rsquo;s new in VMware Horizon 6</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 13:33:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware Horizon 6 has been today announced. VMware Horizon 6 has five major enhancements:
Cloud Pod Architecture. Remote Desktop Session Host (RDS) Hosted Apps Virtual SAN Application Catalog vCops for View 6 Here is an overview picture of the Horizon 6 architecture:
Cloud Pod Architecture In version 5 Horizon View supports 10.</description></item><item><title>vExpert for the fourth time!</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/01/vexpert-for-the-fourth-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 20:38:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/01/vexpert-for-the-fourth-time/</guid><description>The vExpert 2014 are announced. This year 754 people (including me) are awarded with the vExpert 2014 title.
Each of these vExperts have demonstrated significant contributions to the community and a willingness to share their expertise with others.
This is the fourth time I got the vExpert award. I would like to thank John Troyer, Corey Romero and the rest of the VMware Social &amp;amp; Community Team for making this possible.</description></item><item><title>Install a wildcard certificate on a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 20:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>On a View Security Server I needed to change the default self signed certificate to a signed wildcard certificate. The customer had a wildcard certificate that didn’t include the private key. A certificate that include the private key is a requirement for a VMware View Security server.
If you have the certificate (*.</description></item><item><title>VMware VSAN Launch Q&amp;A</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/03/06/vmware-vsan-launch-qa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 18:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/03/06/vmware-vsan-launch-qa/</guid><description>VMware has today announced VSAN. Here are some highlights from the Q&amp;amp;A session:
VSAN will be GA at March 10 2014 vSphere 5.5 Update 1 will support VSAN GA Beta VSAN upgrades to the GA release are not supported VSAN is not a VSA. Performance is much better than any VSA Pricing and packaging will covered on the GA date Performance of VSAN scales linear as you add more hardware (extra nodes with storage) Initial release of VSAN requires SSD and HDD.</description></item><item><title>vSphere 5.x NIC problems</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/02/27/vsphere-5-x-nic-problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 14:22:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/02/27/vsphere-5-x-nic-problems/</guid><description>Last week ik blogged about the “Broadcom adapter data corruption on ESXi/ESX hosts using the tg3 driver and TSO enabled” NIC problem. Link This week I found two new vSphere NIC issues worth to mention:
Hosts with virtual machines using the E1000/E1000E adapter have networking issues after upgrading to ESXi 5.</description></item><item><title>Display VMware Horizon View Pool information using PowerCLI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 21:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</guid><description>For a VMware View Horizon Healthcheck I needed to display all VMware View Pools created and export some settings for documentation. The easiest way to do this is using View PowerCLI on a VMware View Connection server.
Here are some examples to use:
Display all the pools and settings: get-pool</description></item><item><title>vCloud Networking and Security license in Evaluation Mode</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/18/vcloud-networking-and-security-license-in-evaluation-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 08:55:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/18/vcloud-networking-and-security-license-in-evaluation-mode/</guid><description>A customer has a VMware vSphere 5.1 environment with VMware Horizon View 5.2 environment and Trend Micro Deep Security installed. Trend Micro Deep Security uses the VMware vShield Endpoint framework. In the vSphere license manager asset the “vCloud Networking and Security” license is displayed in evaluation mode and has a expire date.</description></item><item><title>Running Hyper-V and VMware Workstation on Windows 8.x</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 19:40:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</guid><description>For testing I use Hyper-V and VMware Workstation 10 on my laptop. One restriction of VMware Workstation is that it does not support VHDX disk files (yet). VMware Workstation support VHD files, so the VHDX files must be converted to a VHD first. After the conversion VMware Workstation can select the VHD as Hard Disk.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Network Port Diagram</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 09:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</guid><description>VMware has released a Network Port Diagram diagram for VMware Horizon View 5.2.
This diagram covers an entire VMware View environment with protocols and port numbers used. In earlier blog posts I already create two small diagrams with protocols and port numbers used by VMware View:
VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol).</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 &amp;ndash; Partner day impressions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/14/vmworld-europe-2013-partner-day-impressions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 18:47:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/14/vmworld-europe-2013-partner-day-impressions/</guid><description>Here are some impressions of the partner day today.</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5 deployment tips and tricks</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/09/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-deployment-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 12:02:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/09/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-deployment-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Here are some deployment tips and tricks for the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA):
The VMware vCenter Server Appliance is a preconfigured Linux-based virtual machine. The VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) is available as OVF/ OVA It based on Suse Linux Enterprise 11 64-bit Linked Mode, Microsoft SQL or DB2 is not supported As database you can use the embedded vPostgres or external Oracle database The minimal configuration is: 2 vCPUs, 8 GB memory, a 25 GB thin provisioned and 100 GB thick disk.</description></item><item><title>Watch out with Hardware Version 10 in VMware ESXi 5.5!</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/01/watch-out-with-hardware-version-10-in-vmware-esxi-5-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 13:33:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/01/watch-out-with-hardware-version-10-in-vmware-esxi-5-5/</guid><description>Update: 09-09-2014: Today VMware released a new vSphere Client (vSphere Windows client). With vSphere Client 5.5.0 Build 1993072 (available with ESXi 5.5 Update 2) it is possible to edit hardware version 10 VMs settings. When editing a hardware version 10 VM it is only possible to edit hardware version 8 features.</description></item><item><title>Perform ESXi host maintenance on a VMware Horizon View floating desktop pool</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 13:02:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</guid><description>When you need to perform maintenance (planned downtime) on an ESXi host which is part of a floating pool the following steps can be be taken:
These steps are only required when using local storage for the linked clones!
In the VMware Horizon View Administrator, edit the pool and uncheck the datastore for the host on which maintenance is required.</description></item><item><title>Create a signed certificate for VMware View Connection Servers using a Windows Server 2012 CA</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</guid><description>For VMware Horizon View it is recommends that you configure your VMware View Horizon Servers with a signed SSL certificate. Default when you install a VMware View Horizon servers, a certificate is generated that is not signed by a CA. Because it is not signed by a CA It is possible to to intercept traffic.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View and Microsoft Lync 2013 support</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/04/03/vmware-horizon-view-and-microsoft-lync-2013-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:10:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/04/03/vmware-horizon-view-and-microsoft-lync-2013-support/</guid><description>VMware Horizon View 5.2 adds support for Microsoft Lync 2013 with audio en video. With Microsoft Lync 2010, only VoIP was supported, but required a dedicated IP-based phone. Microsoft and VMware collaborated to bring Lync 2013 support to the View 5.2 desktop.
Here is a list of supported features with Lync 2013 in VMware View:</description></item><item><title>Tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 09:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>A security server is a special instance of View Connection Server that runs a subset of View Connection Server functions. You can use a security server to provide an additional layer of security between the internet and your internal network. A security server resides within a DMZ and acts as a proxy host for connections inside your trusted network.</description></item><item><title>Display the protocol used on the VMware View desktop background</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:49:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</guid><description>Systinternals has a tool called “BgInfo”. With this tool it is possible to display content on a Windows desktop background. For example environment variable Information such as “computer name” and the “IP address” can be displayed. This can be very handy when testing or for people that do they support for the Windows environment.</description></item><item><title>Configure the VMware Horizon View Event database with MS SQL Server Express</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/02/07/configure-the-view-5-1-event-database-with-sql-server-express/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 14:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/02/07/configure-the-view-5-1-event-database-with-sql-server-express/</guid><description>The event database record information about View Manager events. Without configure the event database events are logged in a log file. The log file has very limited information. So configuring the Event Database in the View environment is a best practice.
In Proof of Concept (PoC) environments MS SQL Server Express can be used for the Event database.</description></item><item><title>In the vSphere Web Client the &amp;ldquo;Use Windows session authentication&amp;rdquo; is grayed out</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/24/in-the-vsphere-web-client-the-use-windows-session-authentication-is-grayed-out/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 09:44:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/24/in-the-vsphere-web-client-the-use-windows-session-authentication-is-grayed-out/</guid><description>When logging in the vSphere Web Client login page the “Use Windows session Authentication” check box is grayed out. To solve this you need to install the Client Integration Plug-in.
The Client Integration Plug-in provides:
Access to the VM console Deploy OVF or OVA templates Transfer files with the datastore browser Use Windows Session authentication Without the VMware Client Integration Plug-in, the “Use Windows session Authentication” check box is grayed out (1) in the vSphere Web Client login page.</description></item><item><title>VMware Fusion 5 and Microsoft Office 2013 screen refresh problem</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/05/vmware-fusion-5-and-microsoft-office-2013-screen-refresh-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 20:11:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/05/vmware-fusion-5-and-microsoft-office-2013-screen-refresh-problem/</guid><description>When using Microsoft Office 2013 on Windows 7 or Windows 8 in VMware Fusion 5 the screen is not properly refreshed and leaving black regions.
This is because VMware Fusion 5 offers DirectX9 for Windows 7 and Windows 8, but Microsoft Office 2013 requires DirectX10. This is a know issue in VMware Fusion 5.</description></item><item><title>Tested: PHD Virtual Backup 6.0</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</guid><description>PHD Virtual Backup is a backup and recovery solution for VMware and Citrix environments. PHD Virtual Backup version 6 is released. We tested this new version with VMware vSpher
What’s new in PHD Virtual Backup version 6: PHD Virtual Backup version 6.0 contains the following major enhancements:
PHD Instant Recovery: Instant Recovery lets you access your backed up data right away.</description></item><item><title>New updates available on VMware vCenter, VMware View, Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter and Veeam Backup &amp; Replication</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/17/new-updates-available-on-vmware-vcenter-vmware-view-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter-and-veeam-backup-replication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 14:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/17/new-updates-available-on-vmware-vcenter-vmware-view-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter-and-veeam-backup-replication/</guid><description>Over the last days the following updates are released:
VMware vCenter Server 5.0 Update 1b VMware View 5.1.1 Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter Plug-in for VMware vSphere beta Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication 6.1 Patch 1 Below are the enhancements listed per product.
VMware vCenter Server 5.0 Update 1b What&amp;rsquo;s New:
VMware vCenter Server 5.</description></item><item><title>Shadow a VMware View desktop session</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/31/shadow-a-vmware-view-desktop-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/31/shadow-a-vmware-view-desktop-session/</guid><description>In VMware View there is no central way shadow a desktop session such as for example in Citrix XenApp. It would be nice if in the future it is possible to shadow a desktop from for example the VMware View Connection server. This is frequently asked question by customers were VMware View is implemented.</description></item><item><title>Convert VMware to Hyper-V VMs with Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 12:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</guid><description>Last week Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter RC is released. Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter is a stand-alone tool that makes it possible to convert and deploys VMware based VMs to Hyper-V based VMs. It’s coverts the VMware VM and virtual disks (VMDK) to Hyper-V VMs and Virtual Hard Disks (VHDs). As virtualization consultant I got “sometimes“ involved in migrating VMware to Hyper-V VMs, so I tried Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter.</description></item><item><title>Customize the VMware ESXi 5 installation media by adding the latest patches using Image Builder</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/02/13/add-the-latest-patches-to-the-vmware-esxi-5-installation-media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 22:17:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/02/13/add-the-latest-patches-to-the-vmware-esxi-5-installation-media/</guid><description>When you want to customize the VMware ESXi 5 installation media you need to use Image Builder. Image Builder CLI is a set of PowerCLI cmdlets that you can use to manage vSphere image profiles and VIB (VMware Installation Bundle) packages, such as driver VIBs and update VIBs. You can also use Image Builder cmdlets to export an image profile to an ISO or offline depot ZIP file that you can use to install ESXi with a customized set of updates, patches, and drivers</description></item><item><title>What about VMware Virtual Machine hardware versions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/29/what-about-vmware-virtual-machine-hardware-versions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 14:44:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/29/what-about-vmware-virtual-machine-hardware-versions/</guid><description>It depends on the features you need. If you want for example use the “Changed Blocked Tracking (CBT)” feature, you need at least hardware version 7.
In ESX 3.x hardware version 4 is introduced, in vSphere 4.x hardware version 7 is introduced and in vSphere 5 hardware version 8 is introduced.</description></item><item><title>Unable to create VMFS partition</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/19/unable-to-create-vmfs-partition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 14:05:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/19/unable-to-create-vmfs-partition/</guid><description>On my home lab I tried to create a new VMFS volume on a RAID-0 disk set that was coming from another host. When creating the new VMFS volume from the vSphere client, the following error appeared:
Call “HostDatastoreSystem.QueryVmfsDatastoreCreateOptions” for object “datastoresystem-9” on vCenter Server “VC01″ failed.
On the VMware ESXi 5 server I enabled “Local Tech Support Mode”, so I was able to logging in directly on the console and used the fdisk-l command to see the partition information on the disk.</description></item><item><title>Optimize the disk(s) and partition(s) on your VM by using VMware Converter 5</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/06/23/optimize-the-disks-and-partitions-on-your-vm-by-using-vmware-converter-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 11:24:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/06/23/optimize-the-disks-and-partitions-on-your-vm-by-using-vmware-converter-5/</guid><description>By using VMware Converter 5 the following disk optimizations can be easily done on your existing VM:
Convert one or more partition(s) on single disk to partitions on a separate disks. When you want to increase disk space on the C: partition this is a problem because of the D partition is on the same disk.</description></item><item><title>VMware VCAP-DCA exam experience</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/05/27/vmware-vcap-dca-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 20:26:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/05/27/vmware-vcap-dca-exam-experience/</guid><description>I took the VCAP-DCA (VDCA410) exam on 12 May 2011 at Global Knowledge in Nieuwegein (The Netherlands). Today 27 May 2011 I received an e-mail that I passed the VCAP-DCA exam! Great news before starting the weekend!
Here are some VCAP-DCA exam requirements:
The exam time is 4 hours (time is for non English speaking countries) The passing score is 300 out of 500 It takes up to business days 10 days (or more :-) before you know if you passed the exam Scheduling for the VCAP-DCA exam can be done by the Pearson VUE’s website Don’t underestimated the exam, it’s a hard one!</description></item><item><title>Display or filter VMs that are restarted by VMware HA</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/05/18/display-or-filter-vms-that-are-restarted-by-vmware-ha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 20:30:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/05/18/display-or-filter-vms-that-are-restarted-by-vmware-ha/</guid><description>When VMware High Availability(HA) comes in action, the VMs are restarted (depending on the HA settings) on other VMware ESX servers in the cluster. It’s handy to know what VMs are restarted.
In the vCenter client the Tasks and Events page size can be increased. Default the vCenter client displays 100 tasks and events.</description></item><item><title>Unable to delete a VMDK because it&amp;rsquo;s locked</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/30/unable-to-delete-a-vmdk-because-its-locked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/30/unable-to-delete-a-vmdk-because-its-locked/</guid><description>When trying to delete an “old” VMDK file, I’ve got the following message “device or resource is busy”. I was pretty sure that the VMDK was not connected to any VM(s) anymore. I tried to delete the VMDK by command line and by using the datastore browser. I found the VMware KB article “Virtual machine does not power on because of locked files” This KB article describes how to find the VMware ESX host that holds the lock.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew / Whitelist Hyper-V R2 home server NAS</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/18/homebrew-whitelist-hyper-v-home-server-nas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 10:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/18/homebrew-whitelist-hyper-v-home-server-nas/</guid><description>For my home lab i was looking for a home server with NAS functionality. My current Iomega IX2 (2x500GB) NAS is replaced by this server. For this server I had the following requirements
Low power consumption (24x7) Low noise Flexibly and room to expand with extra hard drive(s),hardware RAID and a NIC Home server functionality for sharing photos, music, documents and films NAS functionality with iSCSI and NFS protocol FTP server Hypervisor enabled Backup server Print server Active Directory DNS server Download server Wake-on-LAN functionality to start other virtualization hosts I selected the following components:</description></item><item><title>VMware, Microsoft and Starwind software updates</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/02/18/vmware-microsoft-and-starwind-software-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 12:36:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/02/18/vmware-microsoft-and-starwind-software-updates/</guid><description>Last weeks a lots of software updates and new releases are published. Here’s an overview of some of them:
VMware VMware vSphere 4.1 Update 1 A new update for vSphere 4.1 is released. Here are the ESX(i) and vCenter improvements:
VMware ESX(i) 4.1 Update 1 improvements Enablement of Trusted Execution Technology (TXT) — ESXi 4.</description></item><item><title>Free ticket for VMworld 2010 Copenhagen</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/09/24/free-ticket-for-vmworld-2010-copenhagen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 06:52:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/09/24/free-ticket-for-vmworld-2010-copenhagen/</guid><description>The Dutch ICT website Computable _ recently raffled a VMworld 2010 Copenhagen ticket among his followers on Twitter. Last week i was the lucky winner of the free ticket for VMworld Europe 2010. How cool is that!
Yesterday i had a interview about my expectations on VMworld 2010 in Copenhagen. The interview (Dutch) can be found by clicking on this link .</description></item><item><title>Vote for the top 25 virtualization bloggers list</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/09/14/vote-for-the-top-25-virtualization-bloggers-list/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 12:54:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/09/14/vote-for-the-top-25-virtualization-bloggers-list/</guid><description>Eric Siebert from vSphere-Land has opened the voting for the top 25 virtualization bloggers list. Voting is very easy by clicking on the link provided. It takes only one minute. Choose your 10 favorites blogs and rank them in order of preference. The voting is from 14 September till 24 September 2010.</description></item><item><title>VMware news VMworld 2010 (San Francisco)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/09/03/vmware-news-vmworld-2010-san-francisco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 14:04:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/09/03/vmware-news-vmworld-2010-san-francisco/</guid><description>This week a lot of “new” announcements made at the VMworld 2010 conference in San Francisco. Here are some highlights:
VMware View 4.5 VMware 4.5 is released. Here are some improvements in version 4.5:
Support for VMware vSphere 4.1 Full Windows 7 support Offline support View client for Mac ThinApp entitlement Storage tiering Role Based delegation ThinApp package assignment, Link video.</description></item><item><title>VMs with dropped packets %DRPRX</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/blog/2010/08/vms-with-dropped-packets-drprx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 10:41:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/blog/2010/08/vms-with-dropped-packets-drprx/</guid><description>During a health check of a vSphere environment i notices dropped packets on several VMs. In ESXTOP the %DRPRX value showed dropped receive packets on several VMs. In the screenshot an example:
The customer uses vSphere 4.0 build 244038. All the VMs that experiencing the dropped packets problem were Windows 2008 with an E1000 NIC.</description></item><item><title>Things to consider when upgrading to vSphere 4.1</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/08/11/things-to-consider-when-upgrading-to-vsphere-4-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 09:10:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/08/11/things-to-consider-when-upgrading-to-vsphere-4-1/</guid><description>The new vSphere 4.1 release offers a lot of new cool features and enhancements. Here’s a list What’s New in vSphere 4.1. When upgrading to vSphere 4.1 there are a couple of things to think about before starting:
Make sure your systems and components are supported, check the Hardware Compatibility Guide .</description></item><item><title>VMware HealthAnalyzer 3.0 available</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/07/27/vmware-healthanalyzer-3-0-available/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 09:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/07/27/vmware-healthanalyzer-3-0-available/</guid><description>VMware HealthAnalyzer automates the collection of VMware Infrastructure or VMware vSphere™ inventory, configuration and utilization data, analyzes data and recommends grades, and generates a report card that presents observations, findings and data categorized by VMware Health Check best practices. HealthAnalyzer can be used by VMware consultants and VMware Solution Providers to improve efficiency and accelerate the delivery of a services engagement such as the VMware Health Check.</description></item><item><title>VMware Desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 11:11:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</guid><description>VMware released last week the desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC).
When validating VMware View designs it is important to simulate real world usage as closely as possible. The Desktop Reference Architecture Workload SImulator (RAWC) can be used to simulate a user workload in a typical Microsoft Windows® desktop environment.</description></item><item><title>New Book &amp;ndash; vSphere 4.0 Quick Start Guide released</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/23/new-book-vsphere-4-0-quick-start-guide-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 11:19:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/23/new-book-vsphere-4-0-quick-start-guide-released/</guid><description>The vSphere Quick Start guide is released and available from Amazon. This guide is written by 6 virtualization guru’s named:
Duncan Epping Alan Renouf Dave Mishchenko Bernie Baker Thomas Bryant Stewart Radnidge The book summary from Amazon:
vSphere 4.0 Quick Start Guide continues from an idea started several years ago by a few engineers.</description></item><item><title>VMware View 4 released</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</guid><description>The long awaited VMware View with the PCoIP protocol has landed and is available for download.
VMware View 4.0 includes the following new features:
VMware View with PCoIP – PCoIP provides an optimized desktop experience for the delivery of the entire desktop environment including applications, images, audio, and video content for a wide range of users on the LAN or across the WAN.</description></item><item><title>Huge amount of VMware updates</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</guid><description>Today when i woke up there where a lot of VMware updates available (to much to handle for one day 🙂 ). I did an upgrade of my lab environment, it went smooth with any issues. VMware did a great job with the new improvements! Here’s a list of improvements with some screenshots:</description></item><item><title>VMware View 4 announced</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/09/vmware-view-4-announced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/09/vmware-view-4-announced/</guid><description>Today VMware has View 4 announced. VMware View 4 is supported on VMware vSphere and has a new protocol named PCoIP (View 3 uses RDP).
Here’s a list of new and/or improved features:
FEATURE&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NEW/IMPROVED&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;DESCRIPTION&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Quad monitor support&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Support 32-bit color with 1920 x 1200 display resolution and up to 4 monitors simultaneously.</description></item><item><title>Dutch VMware User Group (VMUG) 2009 event</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/06/dutch-vmware-user-group-vmug-2009-event/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 12:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/11/06/dutch-vmware-user-group-vmug-2009-event/</guid><description>On 11 December 2009 the 5th Dutch VMUG event will be held. It is a technical one day event about virtualization. Last year there were more than 600 visitors. Here’s a list in my opinion of must see presentations:
Managing VMware vSphere 4 m.b.v. de Virtualization EcoShell by Eric Sloof - VMUG / ntpro.</description></item><item><title>Boot from USB in VMware Workstation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/10/16/boot-from-usb-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 08:34:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/10/16/boot-from-usb-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>I ‘am testing an unattended installation of VMware ESXi from an USB drive. After every change, I needed to test if the unattended still worked. I tried to use VMware workstation to test the unattended installation. VMware Workstation doesn’t support boot from USB. There is an unofficial solution to fix this problem by using the PLOP boot manager (Download link ).</description></item><item><title>Missing datastore (LUN), EnableResignature</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/01/23/missing-datastore-lun-enableresignature/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 14:18:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/01/23/missing-datastore-lun-enableresignature/</guid><description>After investing the log files on the VMware ESX host i found the following message:
Jan 22 12:39:34 boz101 vmkernel: 152:21:01:58.702 cpu4:1040)ALERT: LVM: 4476: vml.020003000060a980004335434b464a4b77554e59744c554e202020:1 may be snapshot: disabling access. See resignaturing section in SAN config guide.
It seems that the VMFS volume has been detected with a different LUN ID.</description></item><item><title>New version of the PowerShell Healthcheck script released</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/01/06/new-version-of-the-PowerShell-healthcheck-script-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 20:09:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/01/06/new-version-of-the-PowerShell-healthcheck-script-released/</guid><description>VMware vCenter version Cluster information (Updated) VMware statistics (New) List the active Snapshots CDROMs connected to VMs Floppy drives connected to VMs Datastores Information such as free space RDM information (New) VM information such as VMware tools version, processor and memory limits VMs and there datastore (New) VMware timesync enabled Percentage disk space used inside the VM (New) – VC error logs last 5 days (New) It is possible to schedule this script and output the content to HTML and e-mail it.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESX servers unable to manage via VIC, SSH or iLO session</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/01/06/VMware-esx-servers-unable-to-manage-via-vic-ssh-or-ilo-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 19:25:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2009/01/06/VMware-esx-servers-unable-to-manage-via-vic-ssh-or-ilo-session/</guid><description>Today i had a nasty problem with a VMware environment. Some VMware ESX servers were disconnected from vCenter. Tried to connect the VMware ESX hosts using the VIC, but that was not possible. I was unable to login via SSH connection, connect with HP iLO to the HP Blade enclosure and did a remote connection to the console.</description></item><item><title>New VMware Powerpack for PowerGUI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/20/new-VMware-powerpack-for-powergui/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 18:22:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/20/new-VMware-powerpack-for-powergui/</guid><description>On the PowerGUI website is a new version off VMware PowerPack released.
A PowerPack extends the PowerGUI with a set of folders, nodes, links and actions that allow you to manage VMware Infrastructure. With the PowerPack no PowerShell knowledge is needed.
The new version(December 19, 2008 (2.0.0) has the following new enhancements and supported features:</description></item><item><title>New VMware ESX whitebox</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/12/new-VMware-esx-whitebox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 21:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/12/new-VMware-esx-whitebox/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago my desktop PC died, so my girlfriend could not read there e-mail. I decide to turn my OLD VMware ESX test server into a Microsoft Vista workstation and buy a new whitebox. After searching the internet and comparing components, I found the following configuration:
CoolerMaster Centurion 590 mini tower CoolerMaster Real Power 520W modular Power supply Asus P5BP-E/4L (with 4 onboard NICS) Intel Core 2 Quad 6600 Processor Boxed Kingston 8GB 800MHz DDR2 memory Samsung Spinpoint F1 1TB I had already a LSI Megaraid SATA-4 RAID controller.</description></item><item><title>Healthcheck PowerShell script on number six!</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/12/healthcheck-PowerShell-script-on-number-six/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 18:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/12/healthcheck-PowerShell-script-on-number-six/</guid><description>The Healthcheck PowerShell script I wrote for the VMware PowerShell scripting contest is on 6th position on the &amp;ldquo;Top 10 PowerShell scripts that VMware administrators should use&amp;rdquo; from Eric Siebert. Eric is the administrator of the site VMware-land.com that has the largest VMware link collection on the web.
I attended today the Dutch VMUG event and visited the presentation from Eric Sloof &amp;ldquo;Managing VI3 with PowerShell &amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Check your Hardware Compatibility online</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/11/check-your-hardware-compatibility-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 13:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/11/check-your-hardware-compatibility-online/</guid><description>VMware has a online version of the Hardware Compatibility guides available which replaces the PDF guides. Very handy. Check your Compatibility online now at the following location .</description></item><item><title>VMware ESX uptime 570 days</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/09/VMware-esx-uptime-570-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 13:21:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/09/VMware-esx-uptime-570-days/</guid><description>Today I did a Healthcheck of a VMware ESX environment. The environment was still VMware ESX 3.0.0 build 42531. In ESXTOP the uptime was 570 days! WOW the last time I saw systems with such a long uptime was in the Netware days. Make sure to install the required security patches frequently!</description></item><item><title>Site Recovery Manager (SRM) Update 1 released</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/05/site-recovery-manager-srm-update-1-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 08:10:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/05/site-recovery-manager-srm-update-1-released/</guid><description>SRM 1.0 Update 1 has the following new features:
New Permission Required to Run a Recovery Plan
SRM now distinguishes between permission to test a recovery plan and permission to run a recovery plan. After an SRM server is updated to this release, existing users of that server who had permission to run a recovery plan no longer have that permission.</description></item><item><title>VMware patch alert</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/03/VMware-patch-alert/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 08:28:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/12/03/VMware-patch-alert/</guid><description>VMware released the following six new pathes:
Patch nameDescriptionTypeESX350-200811401-SG</description></item><item><title>Move the VirtualCenter SQL database or migrate the VirtualCenter SQL database to different server.</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/29/move-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-or-migrate-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-to-different-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 20:39:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/29/move-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-or-migrate-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-to-different-server/</guid><description>VMware released two new handy KB articles about how to move or migrating the SQL VirtualCenter database to different server.
To move the database
When relocating your SQL database:
To move SQL Server databases to a new location by using Detach and Attach functions in SQL Server, see Microsoft KB article http://support.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 VM's spontaneously reboot.</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/19/VMware-esx-35-update-3-vms-spontaneously-reboot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/19/VMware-esx-35-update-3-vms-spontaneously-reboot/</guid><description>A week ago i upgraded a customers environment to VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 and VC 2.5 Update 3. After the upgrade some Virtual Machines (VM) spontaneously rebooted. After investing the problem we saw that after a VMotion action the spontaneously reboot occurred.
We disabled in HA the option &amp;ldquo;Virtual Machine Monitoring&amp;rdquo; and set DRS to manual.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESX/ESXi Update 3 released</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/07/VMware-esxesxi-update-3-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 07:14:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/07/VMware-esxesxi-update-3-released/</guid><description>VMware has released Update 3 for ESX/ESXi.
This new release of ESX/ESXi 3.5 comes with the following enhancements:
Increase number of vCPUs per Core Limit (from 8 to 20) New supported servers, NICs and storage IO controllers New supported Guest Operating Systems &amp;hellip; and many more improvements and bug fixes. Please refer to the product release notes for the details on improvements and bug fixes.</description></item><item><title>VI Toolkit Extensions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/04/vi-toolkit-extensions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 12:57:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/04/vi-toolkit-extensions/</guid><description>Today I tested the VI Toolkit extensions. The VI Toolkit extensions are cmdlets that makes your life easier. Here are some functions of what the cmdlets can do:
The VI toolkit extensions require PowerShell V2 CTP 2 and the VI Toolkit.
Example:
list all VMs by name and list the size of the snapshots</description></item><item><title>The VMware VirtualCenter Server service terminated unexpectedly</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/09/25/the-VMware-virtualcenter-server-service-terminated-unexpectedly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 13:24:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/09/25/the-VMware-virtualcenter-server-service-terminated-unexpectedly/</guid><description>After rebooting the VMware VirtualCenter (VC) server, i was unable to logon using the VI-client in VC. In the Windows event log the following Error is listed:
Event Type: Error Event Source: Service Control Manager Event Category: None Event ID: 7031 Date: 25-9-2008 Time: 13:39:58 User: N/A Computer: VC1 Description: The VMware VirtualCenter Server service terminated unexpectedly.</description></item><item><title>VI Toolkit Update 1 released</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/09/05/vi-toolkit-update-1-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 18:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/09/05/vi-toolkit-update-1-released/</guid><description>VMware has released VI Toolkit Update 1. There where performance problems with the get-VM command.
Some users had reported slowness when using the Get-VM cmdlet . The reason turned out to be an odd quirk in querying some types of network adapters, so many people weren&amp;rsquo;t affected at all. On the other hand, if you were affected, it was pretty annoying.</description></item><item><title>VMware PowerShell Healthcheck script</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/08/28/VMware-PowerShell-healthcheck-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 12:57:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/08/28/VMware-PowerShell-healthcheck-script/</guid><description>Healthcheck is a PowerShell script that reports information like snapshots, VMware tools version, datastore space, CDROM and/or floppy drives connected etc. to HTML and e-mail the output to a person or distribution list.
Reason for creating this script:
As VMware Consultant I see a lot of common problems in VMware environments like:</description></item><item><title>VMware HealthAnalyzer error "Dataset for the report card is not valid".</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/08/19/VMware-healthanalyzer-error-dataset-for-the-report-card-is-not-valid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 20:53:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/08/19/VMware-healthanalyzer-error-dataset-for-the-report-card-is-not-valid/</guid><description>VMware has released version 1.0 of VMware HealthAnalyzer. VMware HealthAnalyzer is an virtual appliance that collects and analyses the VMware configuration and analyses categorized by VMware Health check best practices. This tool can be uses by VMware consultants and VMware Authorized Consultant (VAC) partners.
The data can be exported to HTML and Microsoft Excel.</description></item></channel></rss>