<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vsan on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/vsan/</link><description>Recent content in vsan on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vsan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitor vSAN with ControlUp</title><link>/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:48:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</guid><description>One of the new enhancements of ControlUp 7.3 is vSAN monitoring support. ControlUp will detect the vSAN cluster(s), objects and displays real-time vSAN specific metrics and metadata. In this blog post I highlight the features of the new vSAN integration in ControlUp 7.3.
Installation The vSAN cluster is automatically recognized by ControlUp when the following requirements are met:
PowerShell minimum Version 5.0 VMware PowerCLI 10.1.1.x .NET framework version 4.5 vSAN Performance service should be turned on on the cluster The user account configured for the hypervisor connection requires the “storage.</description></item><item><title>Disable Virtual SAN health check alarms</title><link>/2016/09/07/disable-virtual-san-health-check-alarms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 06:38:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/09/07/disable-virtual-san-health-check-alarms/</guid><description>When using PCIE/NVMe SSDs in the capacity layer of Virtual SAN, the SSDs are generating a warning for the “Hardware Compatibility – SCSI Controller on Virtual SAN HCL” health check, even when the devices are on the Virtual SAN HCL.
The &amp;ldquo;Hardware Compatibility - SCSI Controller on Virtual SAN HCL**&amp;rdquo;** health check cannot detect the PCIE/NVMe SSDs because they do not use standard I/O controllers.
To disable the HCL health check alarm use these simple steps:</description></item><item><title>Configure VSAN on HP Servers</title><link>/2016/06/09/vsan-hp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 10:13:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/06/09/vsan-hp/</guid><description>For a new End User Computing (EUC) project I installed a Hybrid Virtual SAN (VSAN) configuration on HP Proliant server hardware. VSAN will be used as storage layer for VDIs. Each HP Proliant DL360 Gen9 server has the following components:
HP Workload Accelerator as caching device HP Smart Array P440 controller with several 10k SAS disks as capacity tier To enable VSAN the the first thing to do is to check the VSAN HCL(link )</description></item><item><title>VMware VSAN Launch Q&amp;A</title><link>/2014/03/06/vmware-vsan-launch-qa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 18:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/03/06/vmware-vsan-launch-qa/</guid><description>VMware has today announced VSAN. Here are some highlights from the Q&amp;amp;A session:
VSAN will be GA at March 10 2014 vSphere 5.5 Update 1 will support VSAN GA Beta VSAN upgrades to the GA release are not supported VSAN is not a VSA. Performance is much better than any VSA Pricing and packaging will covered on the GA date Performance of VSAN scales linear as you add more hardware (extra nodes with storage) Initial release of VSAN requires SSD and HDD.</description></item></channel></rss>