<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>homebrew on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/homebrew/</link><description>Recent content in homebrew on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/homebrew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Control (remotely) the power of your Home Lab</title><link>/2013/02/15/control-remotely-the-power-of-your-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/02/15/control-remotely-the-power-of-your-home-lab/</guid><description>I have a lab at home to test for example VMware vSphere and Microsoft stuff. Running your home lab for 24/7 will result in a high electricity bill. For a couple of months I use the Internet Control Station ICS-1000 (ICS-1000) to power on my home lab when needed from anywhere. The ICS-1000 controls (left picture) controls the receivers (right picture). The ICS-1000 is connected to my router. In the receivers are the power cables plugged from the devices you manage.</description></item><item><title>Intel X79 whitebox for vSphere 5 and Hyper-V 3</title><link>/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</guid><description>In an earlier blog post (found here ) I mentioned that it is time for a new homebrew whitebox based on the Intel X79 chipset. With the X79 chipset it is possible to install 64GB of memory (8 x 8 GB). Because the 8 GB DIMMs are expensive on the moment, I decided to use 8 x 4GB DIMMs (total 32GB).
I decided to create one physical host for testing VMware vSphere 5, vCloud Director, VMware SRM, VMware View 5 etc.</description></item></channel></rss>