<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows-10 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/windows-10/</link><description>Recent content in windows-10 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/windows-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Tip: Download the latest Windows 11 ISO files</title><link>/2021/05/19/quick-tip-download-the-latest-windows-10-iso-file/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 18:55:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/05/19/quick-tip-download-the-latest-windows-10-iso-file/</guid><description>In my lab environment, I use the latest Windows 10 or Windows 11 versions (for example the new Windows 11 23H2) for creating and testing golden images for VDI environments.
To download the latest Windows ISOs file I use the Windows Media Creation Tool. This is a Windows-based tool. When starting the Windows Media Creation Tool it opens a Graphical User Interface and you are able to download Windows Home (N), Education (N), and the Pro (N) ISO.</description></item><item><title>Check the hardware acceleration settings in you're VDI environment</title><link>/2020/04/02/check-the-hardware-acceleration-settings-of-the-default-applications-in-youre-vdi-environment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 07:04:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/04/02/check-the-hardware-acceleration-settings-of-the-default-applications-in-youre-vdi-environment/</guid><description>When having for example Windows 10 VDIs it important to know the hardware acceleration setting of you’re applications. When there isn’t a GPU (such as NVIDIA M10 or a NVIDIA Tesla T4) installed and hardware acceleration is enabled in the application this can introduce strange problems such as black screens and performance issues.</description></item><item><title>Windows 10 with Horizon View Agent generates BSOD</title><link>/2015/07/16/windows-10-with-horizon-view-agent-generates-bsod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 13:18:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/07/16/windows-10-with-horizon-view-agent-generates-bsod/</guid><description>After installing the VMware Horizon View Agent (6.1.1) on a Windows 10 (tested with build 10240), it generates a Blue Screen Of Death (BSOD) when pressing Ctrl+Alt+Del/Ins.
The error is:
DRIVER_IRQ_NOT_LESS_OR_EQUAL (kbdclass.sys).
To fix the problem (The solution was found on the Microsoft Community site, link ):
RDP to the Windows 10 VM Edit HKLM\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Class\{4D36E96B-E325-11CE-BFC1-08002BE10318}\UpperFilters Put the kbdclass before the vmkbd value Reboot the VM After changing the UpperFilters value I was able to login the Horizon View desktop without BSOD.</description></item></channel></rss>