<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sso on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/sso/</link><description>Recent content in sso on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/sso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Identify the Single Sign-On (SSO) deployment method for the vCenter Server</title><link>/2014/11/26/identify-single-sign-sso-deployment-method-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 14:20:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/11/26/identify-single-sign-sso-deployment-method-vcenter-server/</guid><description>With vSphere 5.5 you have the following deployment methods for Single Sign-On (SSO):
vCenter Single Sign-On for your first vCenter Server vCenter Single Sign-On for an additional vCenter Server in an existing site (formerly HA Cluster) vCenter Single Sign-On for an additional vCenter Server with a new site (formerly Multisite) Once SSO is installed it can be usefull to identify what deployment options are used for example in a Site Recovery Manager (SRM) deployment.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Single Sign-On 5.1 to vCenter Single Sign-On 5.5 post task</title><link>/2013/11/11/upgrading-single-sign-on-5-1-to-vcenter-single-sign-on-5-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 17:31:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/11/11/upgrading-single-sign-on-5-1-to-vcenter-single-sign-on-5-5/</guid><description>With vCenter Single Sign-On (SSO) 5.5 there is no requirement for a SQL database anymore. SSO 5.5 uses a own VMware Directory Service (VMdir) database. So after the upgrade to SSO 5.5, the Single Sign-On 5.1 database and users can be removed. This is a manual process. In SQL Management Studio remove the SSO (RSA) database and the “ RSA_DBA” and “ RSA_USER” users created.</description></item><item><title>vCenter Single Sign On (SSO) password reset</title><link>/2013/05/30/vcenter-single-sign-on-sso-password-reset/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 09:24:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/05/30/vcenter-single-sign-on-sso-password-reset/</guid><description>During the installation of the Windows vCenter Single Sing On (SSO) service you must provide a password for the SSO admin user named “admin@System-Domain ”.
The password you enter is called the master password. If you change the master password, the password entered during the installation of the SSO service is needed as master password for resetting the “admin@System-Domain ”.</description></item></channel></rss>