<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>runecast on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/runecast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in runecast on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/runecast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Runecast Analyzer makes hardware checking against the VMware HCL easy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/08/13/runecast-analyzer-makes-hardware-checking-against-the-vmware-hcl-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 07:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/08/13/runecast-analyzer-makes-hardware-checking-against-the-vmware-hcl-easy/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer is a tool that helps VMware administrators to proactive manage there vSphere environment. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. It uses best practices, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STIG, PCI-DSS v3.2.1 and HIPAA) and known issues found in the VMware Knowledge Base to protect the Software Defined Data Center (SDDC). Runecast Analyzer supports the following VMware products:&#xA;VMware vSphere VMware vSAN VMware NSX-V VMware Horizon Runecast Analyzer introduced a new feature called &amp;ldquo;Automated VMware HCL&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ESXi Compatibility Simulation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New enhancements in Runecast Analyzer 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 09:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer provides proactive management for VMware environments. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. In 90% of the outages with VMware environments, the root cause is based on a known issue that is already available in the VMware knowledge base. Runecast Analyzer uses information from the VMware knowledge base, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STG and PCI-DSS), and best practices to proactively identify problems or outages before they occur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proactively manage your vSphere environment with Runecast Analyzer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/02/27/proactively-manage-vsphere-environment-runecast-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 20:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/02/27/proactively-manage-vsphere-environment-runecast-analyzer/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got the opportunity to test Runecast Analyzer. Runecast Analyzer Proactively use VMware KBs, best practices and security hardening guidelines to identify problems in your VMware environment. In this review you find my own experiences of testing Runecast Analyzer.&#xA;Deployment&#xA;The deployment of Runecast Analyzer is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s an on-premises deployment on you&amp;rsquo;re vSphere environment. Within a couple of minutes the Runecast is up and running. First download and deploy the virtual appliance OVA in an existing vSphere 5 or higher environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
