<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>networking on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/networking/</link><description>Recent content in networking on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Test your ESXi network resiliency with ESXCLI</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/05/01/test-your-esxi-network-resiliency-with-esxcli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 08:12:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/05/01/test-your-esxi-network-resiliency-with-esxcli/</guid><description>After configuring the network portion for your ESXi servers you need to test if the redundancy is working as accepted. From the ESXi layer you can bringing down/up one or more uplinks to test the network resilience. No longer you need to pull out the UTP cables. Since ESXi5 this can be done by using the esxcli network nic down/up command.
First log in to ESXi using for example using Tech Support Mode</description></item><item><title>Configure the Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP) in vSphere 5</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/16/configure-the-link-layer-discovery-protocol-lldp-in-vsphere-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 07:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/16/configure-the-link-layer-discovery-protocol-lldp-in-vsphere-5/</guid><description>Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP)is a vendor-neutral open standard discovery protocol that is supported by multiple vendors such as Cisco, HP and Juniper for example. LLDP displays for example on what network switch and port the NIC in the ESXi hosts is connected. Prior VMware vSphere 5 only Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP) was supported.
In vSphere 5 Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP) is supported. CDP and LLDP can be handy for example when you want to know that the correct network switch port is used when installing or troubleshooting ESXi hosts.</description></item></channel></rss>