<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pcoip on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/pcoip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pcoip on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/pcoip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot VMware View Security Server PCoIP port problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/26/troubleshoot-vmware-view-security-server-pcoip-port-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 11:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/26/troubleshoot-vmware-view-security-server-pcoip-port-problems/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had to troubleshoot a VMware View Client connection problem. In a new VMware View environment the customer has installed a VMware Horizon View Security Server for the external connections. When a external View Client tried to connect through the Security Server using the PCoIP protocol to the View desktop the following appeared:&#xA;The connection to the remote computer ended&#xA;When the users connects to the View Desktop using the LAN (without the Security Server) everything worked fine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware View 4 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</guid>
      <description>The long awaited VMware View with the PCoIP protocol has landed and is available for download.&#xA;VMware View 4.0 includes the following new features:&#xA;VMware View with PCoIP – PCoIP provides an optimized desktop experience for the delivery of the entire desktop environment including applications, images, audio, and video content for a wide range of users on the LAN or across the WAN. PCoIP can compensate for an increase in latency or a reduction in bandwidth, to ensure that end users can remain productive regardless of network conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware VIEW 4 useful information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/13/vmware-view-4-useful-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 10:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/13/vmware-view-4-useful-information/</guid>
      <description>After attending the VMware View 4 Talkshoe podcast the following information about the announced VMware View 4 was discussed:&#xA;VM’s per core: VM’s per core, In VMware View 3 the number was 6-9 VM’s per core, now in View 4 with for example the Intel Nehalem processors you can get to 12-16 VM’s per core. This number heavily depends for example on the application load inside the VM’s.&#xA;The PCoIP protocol does NOT support: Security Server; Smart Cards integration; Thinprint support.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
