<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/hp/</link><description>Recent content in hp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/hp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HP AMS driver problem in ESXi 5.x</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/10/23/hp-ams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 14:58:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/10/23/hp-ams/</guid><description>The last weeks several customers contacted me that one or more ESXi hosts are not manageable anymore. The ESXi host has the following symptoms:
Unable to manage using the vSphere Client, Web Client or SSH. Unable to perform a vMotion On the ESXi console there is a message: can&amp;rsquo;t fork Enable services from the console does not work The VMs are still running on the ESXi host.</description></item><item><title>Add HP or Dell drivers to VMware Update Manager (VUM)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/17/add-hp-drivers-vib-to-vmware-update-manager-vum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 07:37:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/17/add-hp-drivers-vib-to-vmware-update-manager-vum/</guid><description>HP has created a vSphere Installation Bundle (VIB) depot for all sort of important HP driver bundles for VMware vSphere 5 and higher. The VIP depot contains:
HP ESXi 5.0 Management Providers bundle - includes the latest HP Common Information Model (CIM) Providers, HP Integrated Lights-Out (iLO) driver, HP Compaq ROM Utility (CRU) driver, and the new HP Agentless Management Service (AMS).</description></item><item><title>Display HP P4000 SAN/iQ version, installed patches and up-time</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/02/01/hp-p4000-display-saniq-version-installed-patches-and-up-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/02/01/hp-p4000-display-saniq-version-installed-patches-and-up-time/</guid><description>During a health check I needed to know the SAN/iQ version, installed patches and the up-time of the HP P4000 storage nodes because of a nasty bug in SAN/iQ 9.0 or 9.0.01 that hang or reboot nodes after 208.5 days.
To see the SAN/iQ version, installed patches and the up-time (thanks to Calvin Zito @HPStorageGuy for guiding me to the up-time counter in CMC)</description></item></channel></rss>