<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vcp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/vcp/</link><description>Recent content in Vcp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hurry-up for the VCP5-DCV Delta Exam</title><link>/2014/11/13/hurry-vcp5-dcv-delta-exam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 22:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/11/13/hurry-vcp5-dcv-delta-exam/</guid><description>VMware has released a new delta exam to re-certify current VCP5-DCV holders. This delta exam focusses on material between vSphere 5.0/5.1 and vSphere 5.5 exams. This exam must be done before the end of the month! Here are some details of the exam:
Based on new material between the vSphere 5.</description></item><item><title>Passed the VCP4 exam</title><link>/2009/10/15/passed-the-vcp4-exam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 07:18:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/10/15/passed-the-vcp4-exam/</guid><description>Yesterday i did the VCP4 exam and passed with a score of 475. The exam has 85 questions and for a non English speaker you get 90 minutes to complete the exam. The passing score is 300 out of 500. The exam has 90 multiple choice/selects questions. The exam is harder than the VCP3 exam, but with proper preparation and experience it’s not that hard.</description></item><item><title>Resources to prepare for VMware Certified Professional (VCP4) on vSphere 4</title><link>/2009/08/25/resources-to-prepare-for-vmware-certified-professional-on-vsphere-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/25/resources-to-prepare-for-vmware-certified-professional-on-vsphere-4/</guid><description>There are four possible paths to achieve VCP4 certifiaction:
If you are NEW to VMware Attend the VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage course OR attend the VMware vSphere 4: Fast Track (available in Q4) Take and pass the VCP4 exam If you are currently a VCP3 Take and pass the VCP4 exam.</description></item></channel></rss>