<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>snapshot on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/snapshot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in snapshot on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/snapshot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tested: VMware snapshot management with Snapwatcher</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/06/02/tested-vmware-snapshot-management-with-snapwatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 07:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/06/02/tested-vmware-snapshot-management-with-snapwatcher/</guid>
      <description>To monitor and manage VMware Virtual Machine Snapshots Opvizor has released a tool called Snapwatcher. As consultant I see often that admins don’t have an overview of all the snapshots that exists in their environment. The main concerns with Virtual Machine snapshots are:&#xA;Snapshots are created and forgot to remove Snapshots can very quickly grow in size Snapshots filling datastore space Delta files may cause decreased Virtual Machine and host performance In this review Opvizor Snapwatcher is tested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VM snapshot needs consolidation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/10/vm-snapshot-needs-consolidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 07:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/10/vm-snapshot-needs-consolidation/</guid>
      <description>When a snapshot didn’t commit properly, it can happen that the snapshot manager in the vCenter server shows no snapshot(s), but that there are still active delta files on the datastore. These ‘hidden’ snapshot can cause the datastore to run out of space.&#xA;To report these ‘hidden’ snapshots (prior vSphere 5), I created a script that searches all the datastores for ‘*.delta’ files and reported them by mail.&#xA;In vSphere 5 you have a new feature that reports and make it possible to consolidate these ‘hidden’ snapshot(s).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESXi 5 snapshot changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/04/20/vmware-esxi-5-snapshot-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 08:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/04/20/vmware-esxi-5-snapshot-changes/</guid>
      <description>In ESX(i) 3.x and 4.x snapshots files are default created in the virtual machine’s working directory (home directory). The working directory is the same directory as the were the virtual machine configuration (*.vmx) file is stored.&#xA;In this example a VM called “test” that has two disks (VMDK’s) placed on two datastores. The first disk is created on the VMFS01 datastore and the second disk is created on the VMFS02 datastore.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
