<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terraform on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/terraform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terraform on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 22:43:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Download the latest Hashicorp Terraform, Packer, and Vault bits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/09/22/download-the-latest-hashicorp-terraform-packer-and-vault-bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 07:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/09/22/download-the-latest-hashicorp-terraform-packer-and-vault-bits/</guid>
      <description>I created a PowerShell Script that downloads the latest version of Terraform, Packer, and Vault, extracts the archives to binaries, and adds the folder of the path environment variable. Running this script ensures you always work with the latest versions of Terraform, Packer, and Vault.&#xA;&amp;lt;# .DESCRIPTION Function to download and extract the latest Packer, Terraform and Vault version from Hashicorp .NOTES Author: Ivo Beerens .NOTES Site: www.ivobeerens.nl .NOTES Version: 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create Windows VMs in Azure with Terraform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/03/27/create-windows-vms-in-azure-with-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 17:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/03/27/create-windows-vms-in-azure-with-terraform/</guid>
      <description>With Terraform you can easily create new VMs in an existing Azure environment in a couple of minutes. For example, when I want to test an application, I create a new VM and install the application. When I finish testing I remove the VM with a single command. The VM creation only takes a couple of minutes.&#xA;In this example, an Azure VM is created using existing Azure resources (Resource Group, VNet, and Subnet) with the following settings:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
