<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vSphere on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vsphere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vSphere on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip: VMware VCSA installer page is blank when selecting a datastore</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/08/24/quick-tip-vmware-vcsa-installer-page-is-blank-when-selecting-a-datastore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/08/24/quick-tip-vmware-vcsa-installer-page-is-blank-when-selecting-a-datastore/</guid>
      <description>While upgrading a vCenter Server 6.7 to version 7 Update 3 using the vCenter Server 7 UI installer, I was not able to select a datastore for installing the new vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA).&#xA;The datastore selection was blank as shown in the following image.&#xA;This issue still exists in the vCenter Server 7 UI installer.&#xA;Here are the steps to solve this:&#xA;Go to the %appdata% folder (it opens the C:\Users&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming folder) Delete the installer folder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in VMware vSphere 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/03/10/whats-new-in-vmware-vsphere-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 13:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/03/10/whats-new-in-vmware-vsphere-7/</guid>
      <description>vSphere 7 is built for supporting modern applications and the hybrid cloud. In the coming years, enterprises will build more and more applications using cloud-native tools and methods. There is a lot more complexity in deploying and managing modern applications. vSphere 7 with Kubernetes (formerly known as Project Pacific) is based on VMware Cloud Foundation 4 (VCF) and will help with this complexity. The developer doesn’t need to deal with infrastructure anymore and the VI Admin can provision and manage the infrastructure workloads with the same tools they already known.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Tools pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers delivered by Windows Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/01/09/vmware-tools-pvscsi-and-vmxnet3-drivers-delivered-by-windows-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 13:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/01/09/vmware-tools-pvscsi-and-vmxnet3-drivers-delivered-by-windows-update/</guid>
      <description>Today I was updating a Windows Server 2016 template VM with Windows Updates. During the update, I notice that the pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers are updated by the Windows Updates process.&#xA;In 10.3.10 of VMware Tools, the pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers available through Windows Update for Windows Server 2016 and Windows Server 2019 Operating Systems. This means that the pvscsi and vmxnet3 drivers are updated as part of the Windows Updating process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue circle in the vSphere client after upgrading to vCenter Server 6.7 Update 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/04/24/blue-circle-in-the-vsphere-client-after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-6-7-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/04/24/blue-circle-in-the-vsphere-client-after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-6-7-update-2/</guid>
      <description>After upgrading the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to version 6.7 Update 2, I tried to log in using the vSphere Client. After entering the credentials an endless blue running circle appears.&#xA;In the VAMI interface (https://vcsa-fqdn:5480) of the VCSA, the health statistics of all the components are green (okay) so I decided to reboot the VCSA.&#xA;After the VCSA reboot I encountered the same blue running circle when trying to log in using the vSphere Client.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Tools 10.3.0 recalled, check you&#39;re vSphere environment!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/07/vmware-tools-10-3-0-recalled-check-youre-vsphere-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 09:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/07/vmware-tools-10-3-0-recalled-check-youre-vsphere-environment/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday VMware released a Knowledge Base article that VMware Tools version 10.3.0 is recalled because issues with the VMXNET3 network driver for Windows on ESXi 6.5. The issues can cause a Purple Diagnostic Screen (PSOD) or guest network connectivity loss. Because of these issues, VMware Tools 10.3.0 is recalled and no longer available.&#xA;Update: September 12, 2018: VMware Tools 10.3.2. is released that fixes the VMXNET3 issue. More information can be found here, link .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading a vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to version 6.7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/04/23/upgrade-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-to-version-6-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 06:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/04/23/upgrade-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-to-version-6-7/</guid>
      <description>Last week VMware launched vSphere 6.7. In this blog post I show how easy it is to upgrade a vCenter Server 6.x appliance to a new vCenter Server 6.7 appliance using the graphical interface (GUI) upgrade. The GUI upgrade uses a two stage process:&#xA;Stage 1: Deploy a new vCenter Server 6.7 appliance Stage 2: Transfer the services and configuration data from the old to the new appliance Upgrading the vCenter Server Appliance includes deploying a new appliance (version 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unable to login because of a ESXi root account lockout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/01/02/esxi-root-account-locked/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 11:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/01/02/esxi-root-account-locked/</guid>
      <description>When starting one of my VMware ESXi 6.5 lab hosts I was unable to login using the vSphere Host Client. I tried to make an SSH session to the host but got an “Access Denied” message.&#xA;Using the Direct Console Interface (DCUI) I was able to login using the root account. In the log folder (under /var/log) I found that the root account is locked because of many failed attempt by investigate the following log files:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy an OVA/OVF fails with certificate error</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2017/10/23/deploy-ovaovf-fails-certificate-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 20:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2017/10/23/deploy-ovaovf-fails-certificate-error/</guid>
      <description>When trying to deploy an OVA/OVF with the vSphere Web Client the following error is displayed:&#xA;The operation failed for an undetermined reason. Typically this problem occurs due to certificates that the browser does not trust. If you are using self-signed or custom certificates, open the URL below in a new browser tab and accept the certificate, then retry the operation.&#xA;This error occurs with vSphere 6.5 because the certificates are not trusted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to check before upgrading to vSphere 6.5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/11/21/check-upgrading-vsphere-6-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 16:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/11/21/check-upgrading-vsphere-6-5/</guid>
      <description>Last week vSphere 6.5 was released (GA). This release has a lot of new cool features (see this link for more information). In the past I saw vSphere environments that are upgraded without proper preparation resulting in a rollback because compatibility issues with hard-or software. So I created a simple list with steps to check before upgrading to vSphere 6.5:&#xA;Check the hardware against the VMware Compatibility Guide, link There is a PowerCLI script to check the hardware against the VMware Compatibility Guide, link Devices deprecated and unsupported in ESXi 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identify the Single Sign-On (SSO) deployment method for the vCenter Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/11/26/identify-single-sign-sso-deployment-method-vcenter-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 14:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/11/26/identify-single-sign-sso-deployment-method-vcenter-server/</guid>
      <description>With vSphere 5.5 you have the following deployment methods for Single Sign-On (SSO):&#xA;vCenter Single Sign-On for your first vCenter Server vCenter Single Sign-On for an additional vCenter Server in an existing site (formerly HA Cluster) vCenter Single Sign-On for an additional vCenter Server with a new site (formerly Multisite) Once SSO is installed it can be usefull to identify what deployment options are used for example in a Site Recovery Manager (SRM) deployment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After upgrading vSphere 4 to 5 the Fusion-IO card is in minimal mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/03/upgrading-vsphere-5-x-fusion-io-card-disappeared/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/03/upgrading-vsphere-5-x-fusion-io-card-disappeared/</guid>
      <description>Last week I did a VMware vSphere and VMware View 4 to 5 upgrade. The ESXi servers for the VMware View environment uses Fusion-IO (HP IO Accelerators) PCI flash cards for there non-persistent VDI pools. After the upgrade to vSphere 5.1 I imported the latest Fusion-IO drivers and created a baseline in vSphere Update Manager (VUM) and deployed the new drivers to the cluster.&#xA;After the installation of the Fusion-IO drivers on the ESXi hosts, the Fusion-IO card was not listed in the vSphere (Web) client.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unable to connect from the vSphere Client or PowerCLI on Windows XP or Windows 2003 to a vCenter Server 5.5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/15/unable-to-connect-from-the-vsphere-client-or-powercli-on-windows-xp-or-windows-2003-to-a-vcenter-server-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 07:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/15/unable-to-connect-from-the-vsphere-client-or-powercli-on-windows-xp-or-windows-2003-to-a-vcenter-server-5-5/</guid>
      <description>In my lab environment I still have a Windows XP with the vSphere Client 5.5 installed. When I try to connect with the vSphere Client or vSphere PowerCLI it faisl to connect to the vCenter Server 5.5 or vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5. The following errors appears (The OS has a Dutch language installed):&#xA;PowerCLI error:&#xA;In the release notes of vSphere 5.5 this is a known issue:&#xA;vSphere 5.5 uses the Open SSL library, which, for security, is configured by default to accept only connections that use strong cipher suites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Single Sign-On 5.1 to vCenter Single Sign-On 5.5 post task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/11/upgrading-single-sign-on-5-1-to-vcenter-single-sign-on-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 17:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/11/upgrading-single-sign-on-5-1-to-vcenter-single-sign-on-5-5/</guid>
      <description>With vCenter Single Sign-On (SSO) 5.5 there is no requirement for a SQL database anymore. SSO 5.5 uses a own VMware Directory Service (VMdir) database. So after the upgrade to SSO 5.5, the Single Sign-On 5.1 database and users can be removed. This is a manual process. In SQL Management Studio remove the SSO (RSA) database and the “ RSA_DBA” and “ RSA_USER” users created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test your ESXi network resiliency with ESXCLI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/05/01/test-your-esxi-network-resiliency-with-esxcli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 08:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/05/01/test-your-esxi-network-resiliency-with-esxcli/</guid>
      <description>After configuring the network portion for your ESXi servers you need to test if the redundancy is working as accepted. From the ESXi layer you can bringing down/up one or more uplinks to test the network resilience. No longer you need to pull out the UTP cables. Since ESXi5 this can be done by using the esxcli network nic down/up command.&#xA;First log in to ESXi using for example using Tech Support Mode</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager has now Hyper-V 2012 support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/19/vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager-has-now-hyper-v-2012-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/19/vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager-has-now-hyper-v-2012-support/</guid>
      <description>VMware has released the beta the public beta of VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager 1.1. This beta supports Microsoft Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V or Hyper-V Server 2012. Another new capability is to migrate VMs from your Hyper-V to your VMware vSphere environment .&#xA;The VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager 1.1 is a minor release which introduces the following new capabilities:&#xA;Migration of virtual machines from Hyper-V to ESX or ESXi hosts. Support for the latest Microsoft Hyper-V hypervisor (as well as earlier Hyper-V versions).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remove a vSphere Distributed Switch (VDS) from host</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/15/remove-a-host-from-the-vsphere-distributed-switch-vds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/15/remove-a-host-from-the-vsphere-distributed-switch-vds/</guid>
      <description>The option to remove a ESXi host from a vSphere Distributed Switch can be difficult to find. Here are the steps listed to remove an ESXi host from a vSphere Distributed Switch (VDS):&#xA;Open the vSphere client Click Home and the Networking icon in the inventory tab Select the desired VDS (2) Select the hosts tab Select the desired ESXi host, right click and select Remove from vSphere Distributed Switch (4) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update VMware tools without reboot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/12/24/update-vmware-tools-without-reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/12/24/update-vmware-tools-without-reboot/</guid>
      <description>Update February 22, 2013: William Lam created a clarification on the Zero-Down Time) VMware Tools Upgrade. Here is a quote from the post:&#xA;Is there downtime when upgrading to future versions of VMware Tools?&#xA;It depends. If one or more components have been updated since the last VMware Tools upgrade or one of the VMware Tools components requests a system reboot, then a reboot will be required. The following VMware KB http://kb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to a new vCenter server with the vSphere Distributed Switch (VDS) enabled in vSphere 5.1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/10/29/migrate-to-a-new-vcenter-server-with-the-vsphere-distributed-switch-vds-enabled-in-vsphere-5-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/10/29/migrate-to-a-new-vcenter-server-with-the-vsphere-distributed-switch-vds-enabled-in-vsphere-5-1/</guid>
      <description>Migrating to a new fresh vCenter server using the vSphere Distributed Switch (VDS) prior vSphere 5.1 is not a easy task. The VDS is part of the vCenter configuration. If you try to import hosts that have a VDS configuration to a new vCenter server the following warning will appear:&#xA;The distributed Virtual Switch corresponding to the proxy switches d5 6e 22 50 dd f2 94 7b-a6 1f b2 c2 e6 aa 0f bf on the host does not exist in vCenter or does not contain the host.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convert VMware to Hyper-V VMs with Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 12:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</guid>
      <description>Last week Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter RC is released. Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter is a stand-alone tool that makes it possible to convert and deploys VMware based VMs to Hyper-V based VMs. It’s coverts the VMware VM and virtual disks (VMDK) to Hyper-V VMs and Virtual Hard Disks (VHDs). As virtualization consultant I got “sometimes“ involved in migrating VMware to Hyper-V VMs, so I tried Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter.&#xA;What’s supported Supported VMware platforms to convert from :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unable to join domain when deploy a template using guest customization specification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/22/unable-to-join-domain-when-deploy-a-template-using-guest-customization-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 10:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/22/unable-to-join-domain-when-deploy-a-template-using-guest-customization-specification/</guid>
      <description>At a customer I was unable to join a domain when deploying a template from vCenter using a guest customization specification. This only happened with Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7 templates.&#xA;To solve this problem, you need the do the following in the guest customization specification:&#xA;Enter the FQDN name in Windows Server Domain field (1) Enter the user@domain_FQDN in the username field (2) I used the NetBIOS domain name in the “Windows Server Domain” field and “domain\username” in the username field what doesn’t work with Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7 anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel X79 whitebox for vSphere 5 and Hyper-V 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier blog post (found here ) I mentioned that it is time for a new homebrew whitebox based on the Intel X79 chipset. With the X79 chipset it is possible to install 64GB of memory (8 x 8 GB). Because the 8 GB DIMMs are expensive on the moment, I decided to use 8 x 4GB DIMMs (total 32GB).&#xA;I decided to create one physical host for testing VMware vSphere 5, vCloud Director, VMware SRM, VMware View 5 etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware vCenter 4 and MS SQL Express 2008 R2 bug</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/01/06/vmware-vcenter-4-and-ms-sql-express-2008-r2-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 10:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/01/06/vmware-vcenter-4-and-ms-sql-express-2008-r2-bug/</guid>
      <description>When looking for performance data in vCenter 4.1 from the past week, month or year, I got the message “Performance data is currently not available for this entry”. Only real time data is visible in vSphere client.&#xA;In the vCenter Service Status the warning “Performance statistics rollup from Past Day to Past Week is not occurring in the database” appeared.&#xA;The vCenter server is installed on MS Windows 2008 R2 and uses vCenter server version 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time for new whitebox for your VMware vSphere or MS Hyper-V home lab environment?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/11/18/time-for-new-whitebox-for-your-vmware-vsphere-or-ms-hyper-v-home-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 10:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/11/18/time-for-new-whitebox-for-your-vmware-vsphere-or-ms-hyper-v-home-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>When using a whitebox lab environment at home and like to test for example vSphere 5, vCloud Director, VMware View and MS Hyper-V (nested in VMware vSphere you need a lot of processor power and memory. In almost all whitebox lab environment the processor power is not the problem but the amount of memory is.&#xA;Till now the Sandy Bridge desktop boards support up to 32GB memory with only four DIMM slots on the motherboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Display or filter VMs that are restarted by VMware HA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/05/18/display-or-filter-vms-that-are-restarted-by-vmware-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 20:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/05/18/display-or-filter-vms-that-are-restarted-by-vmware-ha/</guid>
      <description>When VMware High Availability(HA) comes in action, the VMs are restarted (depending on the HA settings) on other VMware ESX servers in the cluster. It’s handy to know what VMs are restarted.&#xA;In the vCenter client the Tasks and Events page size can be increased. Default the vCenter client displays 100 tasks and events. In a cluster with a lot of host and a HA action the 100 tasks and events can be to low.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unable to delete a VMDK because it&amp;rsquo;s locked</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/30/unable-to-delete-a-vmdk-because-its-locked/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 10:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/30/unable-to-delete-a-vmdk-because-its-locked/</guid>
      <description>When trying to delete an “old” VMDK file, I’ve got the following message “device or resource is busy”. I was pretty sure that the VMDK was not connected to any VM(s) anymore. I tried to delete the VMDK by command line and by using the datastore browser. I found the VMware KB article “Virtual machine does not power on because of locked files” This KB article describes how to find the VMware ESX host that holds the lock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware, Microsoft and Starwind software updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/02/18/vmware-microsoft-and-starwind-software-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 12:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/02/18/vmware-microsoft-and-starwind-software-updates/</guid>
      <description>Last weeks a lots of software updates and new releases are published. Here’s an overview of some of them:&#xA;VMware VMware vSphere 4.1 Update 1 A new update for vSphere 4.1 is released. Here are the ESX(i) and vCenter improvements:&#xA;VMware ESX(i) 4.1 Update 1 improvements Enablement of Trusted Execution Technology (TXT) — ESXi 4.1 Update 1 can be configured to boot with Intel Trusted Execution Technology (TXT). This boot option can protect ESXi in some cases where system binaries are corrupted or have been tampered with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post checks after upgrading to VMware vSphere 4.1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/17/post-checks-after-upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-4-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 12:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/17/post-checks-after-upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-4-1/</guid>
      <description>Memory Limits When adding existing VMware ESX servers (for example 3.5) to the VMware vCenter 4.1 server, all the VMs got a memory limit.&#xA;To reset the memory limits to unlimited for all VMs, use the following PowerCLI script:&#xA;Connect-VIServer &amp;lt;servername&amp;gt; Get-VM | Get-VMResourceConfiguration | Where-Object {$\_.MemLimitMB -ne ‘-1‘} | Set-VMResourceConfiguration -MemLimitMB $null VMware ESX NICs as fixed Already mentioned earlier in the “Change NIC speed and duplex setting to AUTO in ESX4 using PowerCLI” blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install VMware ESXi 4.1 from bootable USB stick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/10/25/install-vmware-esxi-4-1-from-bootable-usb-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/10/25/install-vmware-esxi-4-1-from-bootable-usb-stick/</guid>
      <description>Not all servers nowadays have a DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and installing a single VMware ESXi server. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable and install VMware ESXi 4.1 from it by using Windows.&#xA;Preparation:&#xA;Need 1GB USB memory stick or more. Download the VMware ESXi 4.1 ISO named VMware-VMvisor-Installer-4.1.0-260247.x86_64.iso (In this example I used the VMware vSphere Hypervisor version). Update: The latest version of VMware ESXi is 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guides on esxtop and vCenter metrics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/10/07/guides-on-esxtop-and-vcenter-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 15:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/10/07/guides-on-esxtop-and-vcenter-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Here’s are some links to guides on esxtop and vCenter metrics in vSphere 4.x:&#xA;vCenter Performance counters for vSphere 4 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware news VMworld 2010 (San Francisco)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/09/03/vmware-news-vmworld-2010-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 14:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/09/03/vmware-news-vmworld-2010-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>This week a lot of “new” announcements made at the VMworld 2010 conference in San Francisco. Here are some highlights:&#xA;VMware View 4.5 VMware 4.5 is released. Here are some improvements in version 4.5:&#xA;Support for VMware vSphere 4.1 Full Windows 7 support Offline support View client for Mac ThinApp entitlement Storage tiering Role Based delegation ThinApp package assignment, Link video. The profile management (RTO software) solution is not included in this release and the security server does still not support the PCoIP protocol!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMs with dropped packets %DRPRX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2010/08/vms-with-dropped-packets-drprx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 10:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2010/08/vms-with-dropped-packets-drprx/</guid>
      <description>During a health check of a vSphere environment i notices dropped packets on several VMs. In ESXTOP the %DRPRX value showed dropped receive packets on several VMs. In the screenshot an example:&#xA;The customer uses vSphere 4.0 build 244038. All the VMs that experiencing the dropped packets problem were Windows 2008 with an E1000 NIC.&#xA;E1000 — An emulated version of the Intel 82545EM Gigabit Ethernet NIC. A driver for this NIC is not included with all guest operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrainSignal VMware vSphere Pro Series Vol .1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/03/23/trainsignal-vmware-vsphere-pro-series-vol-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 21:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/03/23/trainsignal-vmware-vsphere-pro-series-vol-1/</guid>
      <description>VMware View &amp;amp; ThinApp Presented by David Davis covers the following topics:&#xA;View Overview and introduction Installing VMware View 4 Deploying Virtual Desktops with View Automated Virtual Desktop Deployment with View Pools Adding a Terminal Services Pool in View Understanding View Composer Linked Clones Introduction to ThinApp 4 Installing ThinApp Virtualizing Applications with ThinApp Managing VMware vSphere with PowerCLI presented by Hal Rottenberg covers the following topics:&#xA;Introduction to PowerCLI, PowerShell Basic PowerCLI Concepts PowerCLI in the Real World PowerCLI Cmdlet Deep dives Cisco Nexus 1000V - VMware vSphere Third-Party Virtual Distributed Switch presented by Rick Scherer covers the following topics:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for HP EVA, vSphere 4 and Round Robin multi-pathing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/01/19/best-practices-for-hp-eva-vsphere-4-and-round-robin-multi-pathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 10:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/01/19/best-practices-for-hp-eva-vsphere-4-and-round-robin-multi-pathing/</guid>
      <description>To get your HP EVA storage system and VMware ESX hosts storage balances you get a better performance. Here are some Best practices.&#xA;The VMware vSphere and the HP EVA 4x00, 6x00 and 8x00 series are ALUA compliant. ALUA compliant means in simple words that it is not needed to manually identify preferred I/O paths between VMware ESX hosts and the storage controllers.&#xA;When you create a new Vdisk on the HP EVA the LUN is set default set to No Preference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Book &amp;ndash; vSphere 4.0 Quick Start Guide released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/23/new-book-vsphere-4-0-quick-start-guide-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 11:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/23/new-book-vsphere-4-0-quick-start-guide-released/</guid>
      <description>The vSphere Quick Start guide is released and available from Amazon. This guide is written by 6 virtualization guru’s named:&#xA;Duncan Epping Alan Renouf Dave Mishchenko Bernie Baker Thomas Bryant Stewart Radnidge The book summary from Amazon:&#xA;vSphere 4.0 Quick Start Guide continues from an idea started several years ago by a few engineers. The idea was simple, provide an easy to use reference guide for all level administrators, consultants and architects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huge amount of VMware updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</guid>
      <description>Today when i woke up there where a lot of VMware updates available (to much to handle for one day 🙂 ). I did an upgrade of my lab environment, it went smooth with any issues. VMware did a great job with the new improvements! Here’s a list of improvements with some screenshots:&#xA;VMware ESX 4 Update 1 improvements: VMware View 4.0 support – This release adds support for VMware View 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources to prepare for VMware Certified Professional (VCP4) on vSphere 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/08/25/resources-to-prepare-for-vmware-certified-professional-on-vsphere-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/08/25/resources-to-prepare-for-vmware-certified-professional-on-vsphere-4/</guid>
      <description>There are four possible paths to achieve VCP4 certifiaction:&#xA;If you are NEW to VMware Attend the VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage course OR attend the VMware vSphere 4: Fast Track (available in Q4) Take and pass the VCP4 exam If you are currently a VCP3 Take and pass the VCP4 exam. This option will only be available until December 31, 2009. The What&amp;rsquo;s New class is strongly recommended. Beginning in 2010, VCP3s must attend the VMware vSphere 4: What’s New class in order to upgrade.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
