<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>desktop on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/desktop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in desktop on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 22:28:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/desktop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMware Desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 11:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</guid>
      <description>VMware released last week the desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC).&#xA;When validating VMware View designs it is important to simulate real world usage as closely as possible. The Desktop Reference Architecture Workload SImulator (RAWC) can be used to simulate a user workload in a typical Microsoft Windows® desktop environment.&#xA;Desktop RAWC runs on a Windows XP guest operating system and is executed on each desktop virtual machine (VM) on one or more ESX™ hosts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware View 4 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</guid>
      <description>The long awaited VMware View with the PCoIP protocol has landed and is available for download.&#xA;VMware View 4.0 includes the following new features:&#xA;VMware View with PCoIP – PCoIP provides an optimized desktop experience for the delivery of the entire desktop environment including applications, images, audio, and video content for a wide range of users on the LAN or across the WAN. PCoIP can compensate for an increase in latency or a reduction in bandwidth, to ensure that end users can remain productive regardless of network conditions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
