<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Packer on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/packer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Packer on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 09:44:40 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/packer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pass a GitHub Actions secret variable to a Packer PowerShell provider</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/06/pass-github-variable-to-packer-powershell-provisioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:16:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/06/pass-github-variable-to-packer-powershell-provisioner/</guid>
      <description>Pass a GitHub Actions secret variable to a Packer PowerShell Provider With GitHub Actions you can automate the image deployment with Hashicorp Packer. It can be useful to pass a GitHub Actions (secret) variable to a PowerShell provisioner script in Hashicorp Packer. For example if you want to use an Azure storage Blob Shared Access Signature (SAS) URI as secret in a PowerShell script that downloads software from the Blob storage to the Packer image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>Some people ask if it is possible to create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer. The answer is YES. The Packer plugin that makes this possible is called “Hyperv”. Version 1.1.1 supports TPM. Enabling TPM in the Hyper-V VM makes it possible to install Windows 11 without any registry hacks.&#xA;So I decided to test Packer with Hyper-V and Windows 11 and create a blog post about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install Windows 11 on VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 07:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>For testing purposes, I frequently use VMware Workstation to install Operating Systems such as Windows 11. The biggest challenge with Windows 11 is that you need a TPM 2.0 device. When installing Windows 11, if your computer does not meet the hardware requirements, you will see a message stating, “This PC can’t run Windows 11“.&#xA;Windows 11 requires the following minimal hardware specifications:&#xA;CPU: 1 GHz or faster with 2 or more cores on the processor RAM: 4 GB RAM Storage: 64 GB or larger Firmware: UEFI, Secure boot TPM: Trusted Platform Module (TPM) 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a Windows 10 image with Packer using VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/05/31/build-a-windows-10-image-with-packer-using-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/05/31/build-a-windows-10-image-with-packer-using-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>Most of the time I use Packer against a VMware vSphere and Microsoft Azure environment. But sometimes it’s useful to use VMware Workstation for local testing purposes. For building Windows 10 images with Packer and using VMware Workstation there is not much information available. In this blog post, I show how to build a Windows 10 image with Packer and VMware Workstation.&#xA;With Packer, the VMware-iso builder is used for creating images with VMware Workstation or VMware Fusion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packer has now virtual TPM (vTPM) device support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/01/27/packer-has-now-virtual-tpm-vtpm-device-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 19:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/01/27/packer-has-now-virtual-tpm-vtpm-device-support/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier blogpost called “Use Packer to install Windows 11 and enable vTPM and VBS ” I highlighted a workaround for adding a virtual TPM (vTPM) device to a VM in a VMware vSphere environment. A vTPM device is needed for running Windows 11 (without using registry hacks to bypass the TPM device check).&#xA;The latest Packer Plugin for VMware vSphere (V1.0.3) has now support for adding a vTPM device.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
