<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-horizon on IvoBeerens.NL</title><link>/tags/vmware-horizon/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-horizon on IvoBeerens.NL</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vmware-horizon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>List all the active VMware Horizon client versions that are used</title><link>/2022/07/13/list-all-the-active-vmware-horizon-client-versions-that-are-used/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 06:20:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/07/13/list-all-the-active-vmware-horizon-client-versions-that-are-used/</guid><description>Before upgrading a VMware Horizon environment I want to known what VMware Horizon Client versions are in use. Just to be sure that the VMware Horizon clients are supported when upgrading to a new VMware Horizon version.
Another use-case is to identify the VMware Horizon Client versions that are in use for security releated issues.</description></item><item><title>Get the highest concurrent license usage from a VMware Horizon environment</title><link>/2022/03/09/get-the-highest-concurrent-license-usage-from-a-vmware-horizon-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 12:57:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/03/09/get-the-highest-concurrent-license-usage-from-a-vmware-horizon-environment/</guid><description>In some managed VMware Horizon environments, I wanted to know the highest concurrent users per month. This information can be found in the Horizon Administrator Console under Settings -&amp;gt; Product Licensing and Usage -&amp;gt; Usage.
Using the VMware Horizon Administrator console is a manual task. I wanted to automate this. To automated this use VMware PowerCLI which supports access to the View API.</description></item><item><title>Enable Adobe Flash support for the VMware Horizon Administrator console</title><link>/2021/03/07/enable-adobe-flash-player-for-vmware-horizon-environments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 21:53:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/03/07/enable-adobe-flash-player-for-vmware-horizon-environments/</guid><description>Adobe Flash is no longer supported after December 31, 2020, and currently disabled by default.
During my consulting work, I still see organizations that use Adobe Flash-based applications such as the VMware Horizon Administrator. VMware Horizon 7.10 has an HTML5 based Horizon Console that nearly feature-complete and replaces the Adobe Flash-based Horizon Console.</description></item></channel></rss>