<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-Horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/vmware-horizon/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-Horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vmware-horizon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>List all the active VMware Horizon client versions that are used</title><link>/2022/07/13/list-all-the-active-vmware-horizon-client-versions-that-are-used/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 06:20:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/07/13/list-all-the-active-vmware-horizon-client-versions-that-are-used/</guid><description>Before upgrading a VMware Horizon environment I want to known what VMware Horizon Client versions are in use. Just to be sure that the VMware Horizon clients are supported when upgrading to a new VMware Horizon version.
Another use-case is to identify the VMware Horizon Client versions that are in use for security releated issues.</description></item><item><title>Get the highest concurrent license usage from a VMware Horizon environment</title><link>/2022/03/09/get-the-highest-concurrent-license-usage-from-a-vmware-horizon-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 12:57:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/03/09/get-the-highest-concurrent-license-usage-from-a-vmware-horizon-environment/</guid><description>In some managed VMware Horizon environments, I wanted to know the highest concurrent users per month. This information can be found in the Horizon Administrator Console under Settings -&amp;gt; Product Licensing and Usage -&amp;gt; Usage.
Using the VMware Horizon Administrator console is a manual task. I wanted to automate this. To automated this use VMware PowerCLI which supports access to the View API.</description></item><item><title>Enable Adobe Flash support for the VMware Horizon Administrator console</title><link>/2021/03/07/enable-adobe-flash-player-for-vmware-horizon-environments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 21:53:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/03/07/enable-adobe-flash-player-for-vmware-horizon-environments/</guid><description>Adobe Flash is no longer supported after December 31, 2020, and currently disabled by default.
During my consulting work, I still see organizations that use Adobe Flash-based applications such as the VMware Horizon Administrator. VMware Horizon 7.10 has an HTML5 based Horizon Console that nearly feature-complete and replaces the Adobe Flash-based Horizon Console.</description></item><item><title>ControlUp 8.1 Native VMware Horizon integration</title><link>/2020/01/16/controlup-8-1-native-vmware-horizon-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 08:22:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/16/controlup-8-1-native-vmware-horizon-integration/</guid><description>In part 2 we highlight the native support for VMware Horizon 7 and higher environments in ControlUp 8.1. The integration is based on the SOAP API. Adding a VMware Horizon environment is easy, click on the Add EUC environment and enter the name a Horizon Connection Server and click ‘OK’. ControlUp discovers Horizon components such as Connection Servers, Cloud Pod Architecture (CPA), desktop pools and sessions automatically.</description></item><item><title>Export VMware Horizon pool settings</title><link>/2019/12/12/export-vmware-horizon-pool-settings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 11:21:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/12/12/export-vmware-horizon-pool-settings/</guid><description>I created a simple PowerShell script that exports all the pool settings on a Horizon Connection Server and saves them in a separate JSON file. To run this script follow the requirements below:
Download the Export-pools.ps1 script from my GitHub page. Edit the script script and enter the correct file location in the &amp;lsquo;$fileloc&amp;rsquo; variable.</description></item><item><title>"Logon As Current User" and the "AD domain list" options default disabled after a VMware Horizon upgrade</title><link>/2019/11/18/enable-logon-as-current-user-and-the-ad-domain-list-after-a-vmware-horizon-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 19:18:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/11/18/enable-logon-as-current-user-and-the-ad-domain-list-after-a-vmware-horizon-upgrade/</guid><description>When upgrading a VMware Horizon Connection server to version 7.8 or higher the following message appears during the upgrade.
This means the following settings are disabled after the upgrade:
Login As Current User will no longer work when selecting the &amp;ldquo;Log in as current user&amp;rdquo; in the Horizon Client List of user domains will be withheld from Horizon clients With this option, the Active Directory domain name is not visible and replace *DefaultDomain*</description></item><item><title>Horizon Access Point / Unified Access Gateway (UAG) implementation tips</title><link>/2017/05/16/horizon-access-point-unified-access-gateway-uag-implementation-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 06:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/16/horizon-access-point-unified-access-gateway-uag-implementation-tips/</guid><description>In 2013 I created a blog post with some tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server (link ). Now the Unified Access Gateway (UAG) is replacing the VMware Security Server. So it’s time for a new blog post with some implementation tips about VMware Access Point / Unified Access Gateway (UAG).</description></item><item><title>Slow logoff from a Horizon View VDI desktop</title><link>/2016/07/26/slow-logoff-horizon-view-vdi-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 19:16:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/07/26/slow-logoff-horizon-view-vdi-desktop/</guid><description>When building a new Horizon Environment, the logoff and refresh maintenance window takes a couple of minutes.
When a user is logging off from a Horizon VDI session the desktop refreshed in a floating pool. (A refresh action can be configured per pool). During the logoff and refresh window the desktop is in &amp;ldquo;maintenance mode&amp;rdquo; and the user is unable log in.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Client Drive Redirection</title><link>/2015/06/05/vmware-horizon-view-client-drive-redirection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 09:42:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/06/05/vmware-horizon-view-client-drive-redirection/</guid><description>On of the new features of VMware Horizon 6 version 6.1.1 is Client Drive Redirection (CDR). Microsoft RDS and Citrix already have CDR for many years in there product. Now this handy feature is available in Horizon View. CDR is supported on VDI desktops (single-user) and RDS desktops and applications on Windows and as Tech Preview on Mac OS X clients.</description></item><item><title>The end of Tera1 zero client support in VMware Horizon View 6</title><link>/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 14:01:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</guid><description>The Tera1 zero clients has reached their limits on new features that can be added and the ability to support new features of Horizon View such as RDSH. Teradici supports the following combinations:
ProcessorFirmwareHorizon View Version supportVMware CertifiedTera24.8.06.1YesTera24.7.16.0YesTera14.7.16.0.1No (*2)(*2) Tera1 zero clients are certified on VMware Horizon View 5.3 and earlier.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon Q2 2015 announcements</title><link>/2015/04/29/vmware-horizon-q2-2015-announcements/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 19:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/04/29/vmware-horizon-q2-2015-announcements/</guid><description>VMware announced last week what’s new with Horizon 6 (Q2 2015) as well as some brand new offerings that will help you to deliver and manage apps and end users across physical, virtual and cloud-hosted environments. Here are the announcements:
User Experience improvements Linux Desktops support (GA in Q2) User Environment Manager (UEM) (GA in Q2) VMware Workspace Environment Management (WEM) Free SysTrack Desktop Assessment tool User Experience Improvements</description></item><item><title>Create a VMware Horizon View self signed certificate with makecert</title><link>/2014/06/24/create-a-vmware-horizon-view-self-signed-certificate-with-makecert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 07:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/06/24/create-a-vmware-horizon-view-self-signed-certificate-with-makecert/</guid><description>With the command line Windows utility makecert.exe it is possible to create quickly a self-signed (private) certificate that can be used with VMware Horizon View. Makecert is part of the Windows Software Deployment Kit (SDK)for Windows 7 and 8. Below are the steps outlined to create a self-signed certificate using makecert.</description></item></channel></rss>