<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vcp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/vcp/</link><description>Recent content in vcp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hurry-up for the VCP5-DCV Delta Exam</title><link>/2014/11/13/hurry-vcp5-dcv-delta-exam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 22:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/11/13/hurry-vcp5-dcv-delta-exam/</guid><description>VMware has released a new delta exam to re-certify current VCP5-DCV holders. This delta exam focusses on material between vSphere 5.0/5.1 and vSphere 5.5 exams. This exam must be done before the end of the month! Here are some details of the exam:
Based on new material between the vSphere 5.0/5.1 and vSphere 5.5 exams The VCP5-DCV Exam consists of 65 questions and a short pre-exam survey consisting of 8 questions In the VMware Education portal check when the VCP5-DCV certification expires: The passing score is 300 (scale from 100-500) The exam is available in English and Japanese Exam time limit is 75 minutes and 15 minutes for the survey questions.</description></item><item><title>Resources to prepare for VMware Certified Professional (VCP4) on vSphere 4</title><link>/2009/08/25/resources-to-prepare-for-vmware-certified-professional-on-vsphere-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/08/25/resources-to-prepare-for-vmware-certified-professional-on-vsphere-4/</guid><description>There are four possible paths to achieve VCP4 certifiaction:
If you are NEW to VMware Attend the VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage course OR attend the VMware vSphere 4: Fast Track (available in Q4) Take and pass the VCP4 exam If you are currently a VCP3 Take and pass the VCP4 exam. This option will only be available until December 31, 2009. The What&amp;rsquo;s New class is strongly recommended. Beginning in 2010, VCP3s must attend the VMware vSphere 4: What’s New class in order to upgrade.</description></item></channel></rss>