<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vdi on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/vdi/</link><description>Recent content in vdi on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vdi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Windows 10 version for my VDI desktop?</title><link>/2018/10/24/what-windows-10-version-for-my-vdi-desktop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 18:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/10/24/what-windows-10-version-for-my-vdi-desktop/</guid><description>In a VDI project one of the questions in the design phase is always: “What version I use for my Windows 10 VDI desktop?”. Before Windows 10, the Operating System release cycle was approximate 3 to 5 years. With Windows 10 a new release management concept is introduced called “Windows as a Service (WaaS)”.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8 white paper update</title><link>/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</guid><description>VMware released an updated version of the “VMware Horizon with View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8” whitepaper. This white paper discuss the necessary information for optimizing a Windows 7 or Windows 8 virtual desktop image for VMware Horizon View using the Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) or use a script-based approach.</description></item><item><title>Optimize Windows 8 for Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) environments</title><link>/2013/04/12/optimize-windows-8-for-virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-environments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 07:07:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/04/12/optimize-windows-8-for-virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-environments/</guid><description>Optimize and tuning a Windows 8 desktop in a VDI environment is important to reduce for example the CPU, IOPS and the memory footprint. During the Microsoft Management Summit (MMS) 2013 a breakout session about optimizing a Windows 8 desktop for Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) is held. The session has three main subjects:</description></item><item><title>VMware Desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC)</title><link>/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 11:11:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</guid><description>VMware released last week the desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC).
When validating VMware View designs it is important to simulate real world usage as closely as possible. The Desktop Reference Architecture Workload SImulator (RAWC) can be used to simulate a user workload in a typical Microsoft Windows® desktop environment.</description></item><item><title>VMware View 4 released</title><link>/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</guid><description>The long awaited VMware View with the PCoIP protocol has landed and is available for download.
VMware View 4.0 includes the following new features:
VMware View with PCoIP – PCoIP provides an optimized desktop experience for the delivery of the entire desktop environment including applications, images, audio, and video content for a wide range of users on the LAN or across the WAN.</description></item></channel></rss>