<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Troubleshooting on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/troubleshooting/</link><description>Recent content in Troubleshooting on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 21:44:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The New Microsoft Teams Client throw an error in AVD - The parameter is incorrect</title><link>/blog/2024/02/new-teams-parameter-is-incorrect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 15:44:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/02/new-teams-parameter-is-incorrect/</guid><description>After deploying new Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) session hosts with the new Teams Client installed, users getting the following error after the login:
C:\Program Files\WindowsApp\MSTeams_24004.1307.2669.7070_x64_8wekyb..\msteams_autostarter.exe
The parameter is incorrect
In the picture the error The parameter is incorrect is displayed as de parameter is onjuist because the AVD host has a Dutch language pack installed.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESXi Broadcom data corruption problem with the tg3 driver. Check your environment!</title><link>/2014/02/19/vmware-esxi-broadcom-data-corruption-problem-with-tg3-driver-check-your-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 09:41:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/02/19/vmware-esxi-broadcom-data-corruption-problem-with-tg3-driver-check-your-environment/</guid><description>VMware has released a new KB article (2072515) on possible data corruption with Broadcom adapters that use the tg3 driver. This problem can occur when:
The system is configured with greater than 4 GB RAM TCP Segmentation Offload (TSO) is enabled on the adapter The system is running ESXi/ESX 3.5, 4.</description></item><item><title>Enable the Intel I217-V network card in VMware ESXi</title><link>/2013/09/20/enable-the-intel-i217-v-network-card-in-vmware-esxi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 09:23:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/20/enable-the-intel-i217-v-network-card-in-vmware-esxi/</guid><description>The motherboard of my Haswell whitebox contains an Intel I217-V network card. See my “Haswell low power whitebox for ESXi and Hyper-V ” post for more information. The Intel I217-V network card is not recognized by VMware ESXi 5.x by default. On the VMware community I found a post with the Intel I217-V ESXi driver attached.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot VMware View Security Server PCoIP port problems</title><link>/2013/07/26/troubleshoot-vmware-view-security-server-pcoip-port-problems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 11:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/07/26/troubleshoot-vmware-view-security-server-pcoip-port-problems/</guid><description>Recently I had to troubleshoot a VMware View Client connection problem. In a new VMware View environment the customer has installed a VMware Horizon View Security Server for the external connections. When a external View Client tried to connect through the Security Server using the PCoIP protocol to the View desktop the following appeared:</description></item><item><title>VMs with dropped packets %DRPRX</title><link>/blog/2010/08/vms-with-dropped-packets-drprx/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 10:41:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2010/08/vms-with-dropped-packets-drprx/</guid><description>During a health check of a vSphere environment i notices dropped packets on several VMs. In ESXTOP the %DRPRX value showed dropped receive packets on several VMs. In the screenshot an example:
The customer uses vSphere 4.0 build 244038. All the VMs that experiencing the dropped packets problem were Windows 2008 with an E1000 NIC.</description></item><item><title>How-to extend the VMDK and the Windows disk</title><link>/2008/08/08/extend-vmdk-disk-and-the-windows-disk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 13:36:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/08/08/extend-vmdk-disk-and-the-windows-disk/</guid><description>I see a lot of environments where the Virtual Machine (VM) disk space must be extended.
Prior ESX 3.5 the way to extend a VDMK was to use the vmkfstools command with the -X parameter from the VMware ESX server console. With the coming of ESX 3.5 it is possible to extend the VMDK file when the VM was shutdown.</description></item></channel></rss>