<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/horizon/</link><description>Recent content in horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/horizon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>List the parent VM and active snapshot per VMware Horizon pool</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/09/21/list-the-parent-and-active-snapshot-per-vmware-horizon-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 15:02:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/09/21/list-the-parent-and-active-snapshot-per-vmware-horizon-pool/</guid><description>On my GitHub page (link ), I uploaded a PowerShell script that identifies all the active parent VM and snapshot per VMware Horizon pool. The parent VM is also known as Golden image.
With this script, you can quickly identify what parent VMs and snapshots are in use.</description></item><item><title>Configure Microsoft Teams offloading in VMware Horizon</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/08/25/configure-microsoft-teams-offloading-in-vmware-horizon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 06:41:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2020/08/25/configure-microsoft-teams-offloading-in-vmware-horizon/</guid><description>With VMware Horizon 8 or the new naming format, Horizon 2006 (YYMM) Microsoft Teams offloading / media optimization is supported. Media Optimization for Microsoft Teams redirects audio calls, video calls, and viewing desktop shares for a seamless experience between the client system and the remote session without negatively affecting the virtual infrastructure and overloading the network.
What is supported The Media Optimization for Microsoft Teams offers the following features:
Accepting and making audio and video calls Multiparty audio and video conferencing Transfer, forward, mute, hold, and resume a call PSTN calls via dial pad Desktop screen sharing Multi monitor screen sharing and screen picker for screen sharing Volume control from the remote desktop Active speaker identification Limitations Media Optimization for Microsoft Teams has the following limitations:</description></item><item><title>VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) 3.4 RADIUS license change</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/02/13/vmware-unified-access-gateway-uag-3-4-radius-license-change/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 07:25:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/02/13/vmware-unified-access-gateway-uag-3-4-radius-license-change/</guid><description>The VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) acts as reverse proxy and tunnels sessions (PCoIP and Blast) to desktops and remote apps. Besides Horizon support, new features are added for AirWatch and Identity Manager. With version 3.4, the VMware Unified Access Gateway is offered in three editions based on the Horizon or Workspace ONE licenses:
Standard Advanced Enterprise Per edition the following features are supported:
One of the new features is high availability support for the Unified Access Gateway.</description></item><item><title>Drive mapping not working with User Environment Manager (UEM)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/12/21/drive-mapping-not-working-user-environment-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 14:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/12/21/drive-mapping-not-working-user-environment-manager/</guid><description>During a Horizon View implementation with User Environment Manager (UEM) 9.1 the drive mappings don’t show up for some with a Windows 10 VDI. The flexEngine log shows the drive mapping was successfully.
2016-12-16 15:18:45.084 [INFO ] Successfully mapped drive ‘G:’ to ‘\filesrv-01\apps$’ (‘Applicaties.xml’)
When opening an elevated command prompt and type the command net use the drive mappings where displayed and accessible. The users that didn&amp;rsquo;t get the drive mappings where local administrator in the Windows 10 VDI desktop.</description></item><item><title>What to know about Horizon Instant Clones</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/04/21/instant-clone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 07:12:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/04/21/instant-clone/</guid><description>Horizon 7 introduced the Instant Clone feature leverages the vmFork technology introduced in vSphere 6.0 U1. With Instant Clone technology it is possible to clone and deploy a VDI desktop VMs in seconds. This is called the Just-In-Time Desktop.
Below is an overview how an Instant Clone VM is created:
Master Image. The Master Image or Golden Image is a Windows 7 or 10 optimized image that contains installed software such as the Horizon Agent for example.</description></item><item><title>Horizon View Administrator displays a blank error window</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/03/29/horizon-7-blank-admin-screen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 06:29:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/03/29/horizon-7-blank-admin-screen/</guid><description>After upgrading to VMware Horizon View 7, the administrator webpage displays a blank error window when trying to connect using the IP address of the Connection Server.
Horizon View 7 adds new security features that checks for the original URL for the web request. If not, it rejects the request and display the blank error window.
Steps to resolve this:
Use https://FQDN/admin or
On every Connection Server create a locked.properties text file in c:\Program Files\VMware\VMware View\Server\sslgateway\conf Add the following line: checkOrigin=false Save the file Restart the &amp;ldquo;VMware Horizon View Connection Server&amp;rdquo; service After the modification you&amp;rsquo;re able to connect to the View Administrator URL using the IP address of the Connection Server.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot replication problems between VMware Horizon View Connection servers</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/09/17/vmware-view-check-the-replication-status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:15:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/09/17/vmware-view-check-the-replication-status/</guid><description>In environments with multiple Horizon View Connection Servers (High Available) the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) directory is replicated. Configuration, Pool and desktop information is stored in the ADAM database. Problems with replication can result in:
Configuration changes made are not replicated Authentication problems The VMware View Administrator dashboard does not check the replication status. So regular checking the replication status is a good thing. Checking the replication status can be done by using the following command:</description></item><item><title>What&amp;rsquo;s new in VMware Horizon 6</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 13:33:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware Horizon 6 has been today announced. VMware Horizon 6 has five major enhancements:
Cloud Pod Architecture. Remote Desktop Session Host (RDS) Hosted Apps Virtual SAN Application Catalog vCops for View 6 Here is an overview picture of the Horizon 6 architecture:
Cloud Pod Architecture In version 5 Horizon View supports 10.000 desktops in a Pod. If you need to to have more or than 10.000 desktops or needed to span a datacenter another Pod was needed.</description></item><item><title>Display VMware Horizon View Pool information using PowerCLI</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 21:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</guid><description>For a VMware View Horizon Healthcheck I needed to display all VMware View Pools created and export some settings for documentation. The easiest way to do this is using View PowerCLI on a VMware View Connection server.
Here are some examples to use:
Display all the pools and settings: get-pool
Display the pools with selected fields in table form:
Get-pool | select DisplayName,Pool_ID,Enabled,MinimumCount,MaximumCount,HeadroomCount,Persistence,Pooltype,Protocol | FT -AutoSize
Display the some fields in table form and export the pool information to a a text file:</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Network Port Diagram</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 09:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</guid><description>VMware has released a Network Port Diagram diagram for VMware Horizon View 5.2.
This diagram covers an entire VMware View environment with protocols and port numbers used. In earlier blog posts I already create two small diagrams with protocols and port numbers used by VMware View:
VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol). Link The diagram created by VMware can be handy when implementing and troubleshooting VMware Horizon View.</description></item><item><title>Create a signed certificate for VMware View Connection Servers using a Windows Server 2012 CA</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</guid><description>For VMware Horizon View it is recommends that you configure your VMware View Horizon Servers with a signed SSL certificate. Default when you install a VMware View Horizon servers, a certificate is generated that is not signed by a CA. Because it is not signed by a CA It is possible to to intercept traffic. So it is highly recommend to replace the default certificate with a signed certificate after the installation.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/20/vmware-horizon-view-and-html-access-blast-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:06:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/20/vmware-horizon-view-and-html-access-blast-protocol/</guid><description>With the release of the VMware Horizon View Feature Pack 1 for VMware Horizon View 5.2 it possible to connect with HTML5 to your View desktop. This without installing additional software. The new HTML5 protocol is called Blast. Connecting by using the Blast HTML protocol can be handy when you are on a device that does not have the VMware View client installed.
The VMware Horizon View Feature Pack 1 contains the following two main components:</description></item><item><title>Tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 09:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>A security server is a special instance of View Connection Server that runs a subset of View Connection Server functions. You can use a security server to provide an additional layer of security between the internet and your internal network. A security server resides within a DMZ and acts as a proxy host for connections inside your trusted network.
Setting up a VMware Horizon View Security server can be a challenging task because you have to deal with firewalls and some ports that’s need to be opened between the servers.</description></item><item><title>Display the protocol used on the VMware View desktop background</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:49:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</guid><description>Systinternals has a tool called “BgInfo”. With this tool it is possible to display content on a Windows desktop background. For example environment variable Information such as “computer name” and the “IP address” can be displayed. This can be very handy when testing or for people that do they support for the Windows environment.
VMware View 5.1 has the following environment variables available in a desktop session :
ViewClient_Broker_DNS_Name ViewClient_Broker_DomainName ViewClient_Broker_Remote_IP_Address ViewClient_Broker_Tunneled ViewClient_Broker_Tunnel_URL ViewClient_Broker_URL ViewClient_Broker_UserName ViewClient_IP_Address ViewClient_LoggedOn_Domainname ViewClient_LoggedOn_Username ViewClient_Machine_Name ViewClient_MAC_Address ViewClient_Protocol ViewClient_Type ViewClient_Windows_Timezone The View environment variables can be added to BgInfo using the custom field option.</description></item></channel></rss>