<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>home-lab on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/home-lab/</link><description>Recent content in home-lab on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/home-lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to build an ESXi on ARM Pi cluster?</title><link>/2020/10/21/how-to-build-an-esxi-on-arm-pi-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 19:21:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/21/how-to-build-an-esxi-on-arm-pi-cluster/</guid><description>Shortly after VMworld 2020, VMware released (after years of announcing and demoing) the ESXi On ARM fling (*1). On Social media and the community ESXi on ARM is a very hot topic. The ESXi ARM fling makes it possible to run the VMware ESXi hypervisor on ARM platforms such as:</description></item><item><title>NVMe SSDs are not recognized anymore after upgrading to VMware ESXi 7</title><link>/2020/04/09/nvme-ssds-are-not-recognized-anymore-after-upgrading-to-vmware-esxi-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:47:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/04/09/nvme-ssds-are-not-recognized-anymore-after-upgrading-to-vmware-esxi-7/</guid><description>Last week VMware released vSphere 7. The first thing I did was upgrading my homelab. My homelab has two hosts (Shuttle SH370R6 Plus and a Shuttle SH370R8 Plus). After upgrading my hosts from VMware ESXi 6.7 Update 3 to VMware ESXi 7, the NVMe SSDs are not recognized anymore. I Have the following NVMe SSD disks in the hosts:</description></item><item><title>VMware homelab build of materials and configuration</title><link>/2020/02/07/vmware-homelab-build-of-materials-and-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 09:39:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/02/07/vmware-homelab-build-of-materials-and-configuration/</guid><description>William Lam has started a great initiative. William asked (link ) everyone who owns a homelab to share there build of materials (BOM) and configuration so the vCommunity can benefit and learn from. I have a simple homelab configuration, the materials I used and configuration are listed below:
Internet
Cable modem in bridge mode with 250 Mbit/s down and 25 Mbit/s upload.</description></item><item><title>Using the Shuttle SH370R6 plus as home lab server</title><link>/2019/01/30/home-lab-extension-with-a-shuttle-sh370r6-plus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 11:32:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/01/30/home-lab-extension-with-a-shuttle-sh370r6-plus/</guid><description>For my home lab I needed a new host that replaces my Intel NUC (link ) that act as management host. The hardware resources (CPU and memory) on the NUC were limiting my lab activities.
I had the following requirements for the new home lab host:
Ability to run the latest VMware ESXi 6.</description></item><item><title>Using the Apple Mac Mini 2018 as VMware ESXi homelab host</title><link>/2018/11/12/using-the-apple-mac-mini-2018-as-vmware-esxi-homelab-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 14:12:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/11/12/using-the-apple-mac-mini-2018-as-vmware-esxi-homelab-host/</guid><description>Begin November Apple released there new Apple Mini 2018 models. The last Mac Mini was from 2014. My first question: Is it possible to use the new Mac Mini 2018 as VMware ESXi host? So I’ve borrowed a Mac Mini 2018 model with the following specifications:
Mac Mini 2018, CPU: Intel Core i3 3.</description></item><item><title>Slow network throughput between Ubiquiti EdgeRouter VLANs</title><link>/2018/06/04/slow-network-throughput-between-ubiquiti-edgerouter-vlans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 19:32:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/06/04/slow-network-throughput-between-ubiquiti-edgerouter-vlans/</guid><description>After putting my NAS in a separate storage VLAN I noticed that my network throughput was slow to and from the NAS. The throughput of a simple file copy from a windows laptop (wired at 1 GbE) to a SMB share on the NAS was only 17,7 MB. The Windows laptop was on a different VLAN then the NAS.</description></item><item><title>DHCP problems after Ubiquiti EdgeRouter firmware upgrade</title><link>/2018/04/16/dhcp-problems-after-ubiquiti-edgerouter-firmware-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 06:57:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/04/16/dhcp-problems-after-ubiquiti-edgerouter-firmware-upgrade/</guid><description>In my homelab I use a Ubiquiti EdgeRouter Lite 3-port and UniFi AC Access Points for some time now. After upgrading the Ubiquiti EdgeRouter to the latest firmware (EdgeOS 1.10.1) my WIFI devices where unable to get an IP address. I have different VLANs defined on the EdgeRouter for the WIFI networks.</description></item><item><title>The mobile SDDC and EUC lab environment</title><link>/2016/06/23/sddc-mobile-lab-environment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 09:46:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/06/23/sddc-mobile-lab-environment/</guid><description>With my company I work for (Ictivity ), we decided to develop a mobile Software Defined Data Center (SDDC) and End User Computing (EUC) lab environment. This mobile lab environment will be used to demo the VMware SDDC and End User Computing (EUC) stack with integration of third party solutions. One of the reasons to use a physical lab environment instead of cloud services was flexibility and having no dependencies.</description></item><item><title>New whitebox for extending my home lab</title><link>/2015/01/05/new-whitebox-extending-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 11:48:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/01/05/new-whitebox-extending-home-lab/</guid><description>For a couple of months I’m searching for an extra whitebox host for extending my home lab environment. My current lab whitebox is a Haswell based whitebox (see: link). Here is an overview of the new lab environment:
For the new whitebox I had the following requirements:
Hardware such as NICs must be recognized by VMware ESXi Use 32 GB memory or more Low power consumption Expandable Small form factor Quiet Possibility to run nested hypervisors such as VMware ESXi and Hyper-V Remote Management Possibility to create a VMware Cluster and use vMotion, HA, DRS and DPM with the existing Haswell host I reviewed the following popular home lab systems:</description></item><item><title>Haswell low power whitebox for ESXi and Hyper-V</title><link>/2013/06/25/haswell-low-power-whitebox-for-esxi-and-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/06/25/haswell-low-power-whitebox-for-esxi-and-hyper-v/</guid><description>I was searching for a new whitebox for my home lab. I had the following requirements for the new whitebox:
Low power consumption for 24x7 running &amp;gt;16 GB memory Expansion slots for PCI(-E) cards Good performance Low noise A couple of weeks ago Intel released the new 4th generation Haswell CPUs that consumes less power.</description></item><item><title>Control (remotely) the power of your Home Lab</title><link>/2013/02/15/control-remotely-the-power-of-your-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/02/15/control-remotely-the-power-of-your-home-lab/</guid><description>I have a lab at home to test for example VMware vSphere and Microsoft stuff. Running your home lab for 24/7 will result in a high electricity bill. For a couple of months I use the Internet Control Station ICS-1000 (ICS-1000) to power on my home lab when needed from anywhere.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESXi 5 whitebox NIC support</title><link>/2011/12/13/vmware-esxi-5-whitebox-nic-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 15:44:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/12/13/vmware-esxi-5-whitebox-nic-support/</guid><description>I tested the NICs below in my VMware ESXi 5.x whitebox server at home. Here the status:
NICRecognized by VMware ESXi 5Listed in ESXi 5 asIntel PRO/1000GT Desktop Adapter PCIYesIntel 82541PI Gigabit Ethernet ControllerRealtek RTL 8111EYesRealtek 8168 Gigabit EthernetIntel Gigabit CT Desktop Adapter PCI-eYesIntel Corporation 82574LIntel 82579 Gigabit LAN controllerNo You need the make a customized ESXi 5 ISO or VIB file.</description></item></channel></rss>