<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-horizon-view-2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/vmware-horizon-view-2/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-horizon-view-2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/vmware-horizon-view-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Easily fix VMware Horizon View desktop provisioning errors</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/02/11/fix-vmware-horizon-view-desktop-provisioning-errors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 13:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/02/11/fix-vmware-horizon-view-desktop-provisioning-errors/</guid><description>Sometimes you are unable to remove linked clones or stale desktop entries from the VMware Horizon View Administrator. In this example we have a missing VM in the VMware Horizon View Administrator.
When trying to remove the VM from the VMware Horizon View Administrator the following error is generated:
Failed to remove VM&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; from the View Composer Inventory</description></item><item><title>Monitor VMware Horizon View environments with ControlUp</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/10/09/controlup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 07:47:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/10/09/controlup/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago ControlUp released version 4.0 with support for VMware Horizon View. In this blog post I share my experience with ControlUp 4.0 monitoring VMware vSphere and VMware Horizon View.
What is ControlUp
ControlUp is a real-time performance monitor for Microsoft Remote Desktop Services (RDS), Citrix, and physical- and virtual server environments.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot replication problems between VMware Horizon View Connection servers</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/09/17/vmware-view-check-the-replication-status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:15:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/09/17/vmware-view-check-the-replication-status/</guid><description>In environments with multiple Horizon View Connection Servers (High Available) the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) directory is replicated. Configuration, Pool and desktop information is stored in the ADAM database. Problems with replication can result in:
Configuration changes made are not replicated Authentication problems The VMware View Administrator dashboard does not check the replication status.</description></item><item><title>Error occurred during vCenter operation when editing a VMware Horizon View pool</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/09/09/error-occurred-vcenter-operation-editing-vmware-horizon-view-pool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 10:55:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/09/09/error-occurred-vcenter-operation-editing-vmware-horizon-view-pool/</guid><description>When editing a VMware Horizon desktop pool in some situations the server error ‘Error occurred during vCenter operation’. appears.
The error hasn&amp;rsquo;t any useful information that says what is wrong. When this error occurs the vCenter Server is unable to find one or more objects listed in the desktop pool. When changing datacenter, cluster or host settings in vCenter the desktop pool must be updated to.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8 white paper update</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</guid><description>VMware released an updated version of the “VMware Horizon with View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8” whitepaper. This white paper discuss the necessary information for optimizing a Windows 7 or Windows 8 virtual desktop image for VMware Horizon View using the Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) or use a script-based approach.</description></item></channel></rss>