<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-tools on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vmware-tools/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-tools on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vmware-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Identify VMs that have VMware Tools with the OpenSSL v3 vulnerability</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/11/01/identify-vms-that-have-vmware-tools-with-the-openssl-v3-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 19:05:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/11/01/identify-vms-that-have-vmware-tools-with-the-openssl-v3-vulnerability/</guid><description>In OpenSSL version 3.0.0 to 3.0.6, a critical vulnerability is found (link ). A lot of vendors use these versions of OpenSSL in their products. VMware has the following statement:
To date, no VMware products have been found to be critically impacted by CVE-2022-3602 or CVE-2022-3786. Regardless, VMware products that consume OpenSSL 3.0.x will consume 3.0.7 fixes as a precautionary measure in upcoming releases.
VMware Tools version 12.0.0 and 12.1.0 both contain the OpenSSL 3.</description></item><item><title>VMware Tools installation and upgrade tips and tricks</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/09/09/vmware-tools-installation-and-upgrade-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 08:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/09/09/vmware-tools-installation-and-upgrade-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>The VMware Tools package provides drivers (such as VMXNET3, PVSCSI, SVGA etc.) and services that enhance the performance of virtual machines and make several vSphere features easy to use. Here are some tips and tricks when working with VMware Tools:
An overview of the VMware Tools versions mapping can be found here, link The latest VMware Tools versions can be downloaded from the following links: link and link Within VMware ESXi, the VMware Tools are located under: /vmimages/tools-isoimages The latest VMware Tools version 10.</description></item></channel></rss>