<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>upgrade on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in upgrade on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to vSphere 5.1? Check your third party software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/11/28/upgrading-to-vsphere-5-1-check-your-third-party-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 13:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/11/28/upgrading-to-vsphere-5-1-check-your-third-party-software/</guid>
      <description>Before upgrading to vSphere 5.1 it is important to check your existing hardware, firmware levels, drivers, vSphere versions, other VMware products that integrates and third party software if it is compatible with vSphere 5.1. Here is a list of third party software and it’s support for vSphere 5.1 .&#xA;Software Version vSphere 5.1 Support Comment Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication 6.5 yes CommVault 9 SP8 yes 3 extra SP8 post patches needed PHDVB 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Windows Server 2012 Release Candidate (RC) to RTM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/09/07/upgrade-windows-server-2012-release-candidate-rc-to-rtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 09:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/09/07/upgrade-windows-server-2012-release-candidate-rc-to-rtm/</guid>
      <description>Now Windows Server 2012 is release I tried to upgrade my lab environment from Microsoft Windows Server 2012 RC 8400 to Windows 2012 RTM. It is not officially supported to upgrade from Windows Server 2012 RC to Windows Server 2012 RTM by Microsoft.&#xA;I did the following steps to upgrade:&#xA;Downloaded the Windows Server 2012 ISO Mount or extract the ISO Executed setup.exe After several screens it is possible to choose for “Upgrade: Install Windows and keep files, settings and applications” option Now the he following error appeared: The upgrade cannot continue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post checks after upgrading to VMware vSphere 4.1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/17/post-checks-after-upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-4-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 12:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/17/post-checks-after-upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-4-1/</guid>
      <description>Memory Limits When adding existing VMware ESX servers (for example 3.5) to the VMware vCenter 4.1 server, all the VMs got a memory limit.&#xA;To reset the memory limits to unlimited for all VMs, use the following PowerCLI script:&#xA;Connect-VIServer &amp;lt;servername&amp;gt; Get-VM | Get-VMResourceConfiguration | Where-Object {$\_.MemLimitMB -ne ‘-1‘} | Set-VMResourceConfiguration -MemLimitMB $null VMware ESX NICs as fixed Already mentioned earlier in the “Change NIC speed and duplex setting to AUTO in ESX4 using PowerCLI” blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things to consider when upgrading to vSphere 4.1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/08/11/things-to-consider-when-upgrading-to-vsphere-4-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 09:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/08/11/things-to-consider-when-upgrading-to-vsphere-4-1/</guid>
      <description>The new vSphere 4.1 release offers a lot of new cool features and enhancements. Here’s a list What’s New in vSphere 4.1. When upgrading to vSphere 4.1 there are a couple of things to think about before starting:&#xA;Make sure your systems and components are supported, check the Hardware Compatibility Guide . Verify that other products are compatible with vSphere 4.1. For example VMware View 4 is not supported on vSphere 4.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
