<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Usb on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/usb/</link><description>Recent content in Usb on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 22:28:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/usb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a bootable VMware ESXi 5 USB stick in Windows and perform a scripted installation</title><link>/2011/09/17/create-a-bootable-vmware-esxi-5-usb-stick-in-windows-and-perform-a-scripted-installation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 16:42:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/09/17/create-a-bootable-vmware-esxi-5-usb-stick-in-windows-and-perform-a-scripted-installation/</guid><description>Here is a simple procedure to make a bootable VMware ESXi 5 or ESXi 6 USB stick in Windows and perform a scripted unattended VMware ESXi installation. The 5 steps are:
Step 1 Be sure removing all partitions and format a FAT32 partition on the USB stick by using the following command:</description></item><item><title>Install VMware ESXi 4.1 from bootable USB stick</title><link>/2010/10/25/install-vmware-esxi-4-1-from-bootable-usb-stick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/25/install-vmware-esxi-4-1-from-bootable-usb-stick/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have a DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and installing a single VMware ESXi server. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable and install VMware ESXi 4.1 from it by using Windows.
Preparation:
Need 1GB USB memory stick or more.</description></item><item><title>Create a bootable USB to install Windows 8 Server or Hyper-V Server 8</title><link>/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and install for example Windows Server 8. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable for the following OS versions:
Windows Server 8 Hyper-V Server 8 Server 2008 R2 Hyper-V Server R2 Preparation: Need a 4 GB USB memory stick or more Download the desired ISO and save it Stick the USB stick on a free USB port on your computer equipped with a Windows OS.</description></item></channel></rss>