<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hyper-v-r2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/hyper-v-r2/</link><description>Recent content in hyper-v-r2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 22:28:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/hyper-v-r2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Watch out installing SP1 on your Hyper-V R2 cluster</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/25/watch-out-installing-sp1-on-your-hyper-v-r2-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 20:20:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/25/watch-out-installing-sp1-on-your-hyper-v-r2-cluster/</guid><description>Yesterday I spoke a customer who has problems after applying Windows 2008 R2 SP1 on his 5 node Hyper-V cluster. When validating the storage on the cluster, the following error “disk with identifier “2ef8c0……” has a persistent reservation” is displayed on multiple cluster disks.
The problem can occur in the following scenario:</description></item><item><title>Homebrew / Whitelist Hyper-V R2 home server NAS</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/18/homebrew-whitelist-hyper-v-home-server-nas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 10:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/18/homebrew-whitelist-hyper-v-home-server-nas/</guid><description>For my home lab i was looking for a home server with NAS functionality. My current Iomega IX2 (2x500GB) NAS is replaced by this server. For this server I had the following requirements
Low power consumption (24x7) Low noise Flexibly and room to expand with extra hard drive(s),hardware RAID and a NIC Home server functionality for sharing photos, music, documents and films NAS functionality with iSCSI and NFS protocol FTP server Hypervisor enabled Backup server Print server Active Directory DNS server Download server Wake-on-LAN functionality to start other virtualization hosts I selected the following components:</description></item><item><title>Create a bootable USB to install Windows 8 Server or Hyper-V Server 8</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and install for example Windows Server 8. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable for the following OS versions:
Windows Server 8 Hyper-V Server 8 Server 2008 R2 Hyper-V Server R2 Preparation: Need a 4 GB USB memory stick or more Download the desired ISO and save it Stick the USB stick on a free USB port on your computer equipped with a Windows OS.</description></item></channel></rss>