<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Download the latest Hashicorp Terraform, Packer, and Vault bits</title><link>/2023/09/22/download-the-latest-hashicorp-terraform-packer-and-vault-bits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 07:22:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/09/22/download-the-latest-hashicorp-terraform-packer-and-vault-bits/</guid><description>I created a PowerShell Script that downloads the latest version of Terraform, Packer, and Vault, extracts the archives to binaries, and adds the folder of the path environment variable. Running this script ensures you always work with the latest versions of Terraform, Packer, and Vault.
&amp;lt;# .DESCRIPTION Function to download and extract the latest Packer, Terraform and Vault version from Hashicorp .NOTES Author: Ivo Beerens .NOTES Site: www.ivobeerens.nl .NOTES Version: 1.</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI help install, update and troubleshooting tips</title><link>/2019/07/16/powercli-installation-updating-and-troubleshooting-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 11:54:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/07/16/powercli-installation-updating-and-troubleshooting-tips/</guid><description>PowerCLI is a must-have tool for every VMware Administrator when you want to automate something in your VMware environment. In this blog, I highlight the installation, updating, and some troubleshooting tips for deploying and running PowerCLI on Windows OSes.
PowerCLI installation Uninstall PowerCLI 6.x and earlier from the Add/remove programs or Programs and Features if exist. Make sure you have an internet connection. Check if Windows Management Framework 5.1 is installed for Windows 7,8 and Windows Server 2012 R2 and earlier OSes.</description></item><item><title>New VMware Powerpack for PowerGUI</title><link>/2008/12/20/new-VMware-powerpack-for-powergui/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 18:22:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/12/20/new-VMware-powerpack-for-powergui/</guid><description>On the PowerGUI website is a new version off VMware PowerPack released.
A PowerPack extends the PowerGUI with a set of folders, nodes, links and actions that allow you to manage VMware Infrastructure. With the PowerPack no PowerShell knowledge is needed.
The new version(December 19, 2008 (2.0.0) has the following new enhancements and supported features:
reorganized the PowerPack structure to facilitate easier management of multiple hosts and to allow users to retrieve objects from one or more of the hosts they are managing whether they are already connected or not added support for browsing the VMware Inventory hierarchy (includes Hosts and Clusters, Virtual Machines and Templates, Networks and Datastores), including being able to browse directly into the file system on the datastores added many new links and actions exposed many more VMware Infrastructure objects through topological views and through integration in the hierarchy improved the performance of many nodes, links and actions added single sign-on support (note that connecting to multiple hosts using the same username but different passwords is currently not supported, but we are working on that and will provide support for this soon) tested management against Virtual Center 2.</description></item><item><title>Healthcheck PowerShell script on number six!</title><link>/2008/12/12/healthcheck-PowerShell-script-on-number-six/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 18:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/12/12/healthcheck-PowerShell-script-on-number-six/</guid><description>The Healthcheck PowerShell script I wrote for the VMware PowerShell scripting contest is on 6th position on the &amp;ldquo;Top 10 PowerShell scripts that VMware administrators should use&amp;rdquo; from Eric Siebert. Eric is the administrator of the site VMware-land.com that has the largest VMware link collection on the web.
I attended today the Dutch VMUG event and visited the presentation from Eric Sloof &amp;ldquo;Managing VI3 with PowerShell &amp;rdquo;. I saw in his presentation that I was on the 6th place.</description></item><item><title>VI Toolkit Update 1 released</title><link>/2008/09/05/vi-toolkit-update-1-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 18:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/05/vi-toolkit-update-1-released/</guid><description>VMware has released VI Toolkit Update 1. There where performance problems with the get-VM command.
Some users had reported slowness when using the Get-VM cmdlet . The reason turned out to be an odd quirk in querying some types of network adapters, so many people weren&amp;rsquo;t affected at all. On the other hand, if you were affected, it was pretty annoying. To address this we&amp;rsquo;ve released Update 1 of our toolkit .</description></item><item><title>VMware PowerShell Healthcheck script</title><link>/2008/08/28/VMware-PowerShell-healthcheck-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 12:57:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/08/28/VMware-PowerShell-healthcheck-script/</guid><description>Healthcheck is a PowerShell script that reports information like snapshots, VMware tools version, datastore space, CDROM and/or floppy drives connected etc. to HTML and e-mail the output to a person or distribution list.
Reason for creating this script:
As VMware Consultant I see a lot of common problems in VMware environments like:
Snapshots are enabled and forgot Datastores are almost full (for example if snapshots are enabled) VMware tools versions are different CDROM and floppy drives are still mounted to the VM Virtual Machines have CPU and Memory limits or reservations (VMs are swapping) In the VM, the VMware Tools timesync option is not enabled In the Virtual Infrastructure Client (VIC) it is difficult to see this sort of information.</description></item></channel></rss>