<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tpm on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/tpm/</link><description>Recent content in Tpm on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tpm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Packer to install Windows 11 and enable vTPM and VBS</title><link>/2021/10/22/use-packer-to-install-windows-11-and-enable-vtpm-and-vbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 07:30:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/22/use-packer-to-install-windows-11-and-enable-vtpm-and-vbs/</guid><description>I use Packer for building images for VMware VDI environments. With the latest version (when writing this blog Packer version 1.7.7 is the latest version) it is not possible to configure a TPM in the Hashicorp Configuration Languag (HCL) config file. TPM 2.0 is required to install Windows 11. A vTPM emulates a physical TPM 2.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows 11 on VMware vSphere with a virtual TPM</title><link>/2021/10/07/install-windows-11-on-vmware-vsphere-with-a-virtual-tpm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 20:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/07/install-windows-11-on-vmware-vsphere-with-a-virtual-tpm/</guid><description>Yesterday I wrote a blog called “Install Windows 11 as VM on VMware vSphere / Workstation without TPM 2.0 chipset“. In this blog article, I explained how to install Windows 11 without having a TPM 2.0 chipset by using a registry hack. Paul Braren from tinkertry.com created a cool video (link) about installing Windows 11 on VMware vSphere using my blog article.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows 11 as VM on VMware vSphere / Workstation without TPM 2.0</title><link>/2021/10/06/install-windows-11-as-vm-in-vmware-vsphere-workstation-without-tpm-2-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 10:18:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/06/install-windows-11-as-vm-in-vmware-vsphere-workstation-without-tpm-2-0/</guid><description>Yesterday Windows 11 is officially released. Windows 11 require a Trusted Platform Module (TPM) version 2.0 (link). . My VMware ESXi servers at home don’t have a TPM 2.0. During the installation, Windows will check for the presence of a TPM 2.0, if not available the installation will fail. There is a registry hack available to bypass the TPM 2.</description></item></channel></rss>