<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>view on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/view/</link><description>Recent content in view on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 13:23:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What&amp;rsquo;s new in VMware Horizon 6</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 13:33:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware Horizon 6 has been today announced. VMware Horizon 6 has five major enhancements:
Cloud Pod Architecture. Remote Desktop Session Host (RDS) Hosted Apps Virtual SAN Application Catalog vCops for View 6 Here is an overview picture of the Horizon 6 architecture:
Cloud Pod Architecture In version 5 Horizon View supports 10.000 desktops in a Pod. If you need to to have more or than 10.000 desktops or needed to span a datacenter another Pod was needed.</description></item><item><title>Install a wildcard certificate on a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 20:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>On a View Security Server I needed to change the default self signed certificate to a signed wildcard certificate. The customer had a wildcard certificate that didn’t include the private key. A certificate that include the private key is a requirement for a VMware View Security server.
If you have the certificate (*.cer or .crt) and private key (.key), convert it to a PCKS#12 (PFX) format before you import the certificate.</description></item><item><title>Display VMware Horizon View Pool information using PowerCLI</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 21:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</guid><description>For a VMware View Horizon Healthcheck I needed to display all VMware View Pools created and export some settings for documentation. The easiest way to do this is using View PowerCLI on a VMware View Connection server.
Here are some examples to use:
Display all the pools and settings: get-pool
Display the pools with selected fields in table form:
Get-pool | select DisplayName,Pool_ID,Enabled,MinimumCount,MaximumCount,HeadroomCount,Persistence,Pooltype,Protocol | FT -AutoSize
Display the some fields in table form and export the pool information to a a text file:</description></item><item><title>Perform ESXi host maintenance on a VMware Horizon View floating desktop pool</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 13:02:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</guid><description>When you need to perform maintenance (planned downtime) on an ESXi host which is part of a floating pool the following steps can be be taken:
These steps are only required when using local storage for the linked clones!
In the VMware Horizon View Administrator, edit the pool and uncheck the datastore for the host on which maintenance is required. By unchecking the datastore no new desktops are provisioned to this host In the pool settings modify the “Delete or refresh desktop on logoff” to “Delete Immediately” Optionally: In the pool settings modify the “Automatically or logoff after disconnect” to 240 minutes or less so that disconnected sessions are removed.</description></item><item><title>Display the maximum concurrent connected users in VMware Horizon View with PowerCLI</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 09:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</guid><description>VMware Horizon View generates everyday at 5 minutes for midnight an event how many concurrent users connected to View that day. This information can be useful for example when when investing trends.
When the Event database in the VMware Horizon View Administrator is configured, this information can be found using the VMware Horizon View Administrator, Monitoring, select Events and filter for “over the past”
With PowerCLI the daily maximum concurrent connected users can be displayed by using the following command from the VMware View Connection server using View PowerCLI:</description></item><item><title>Create a signed certificate for VMware View Connection Servers using a Windows Server 2012 CA</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</guid><description>For VMware Horizon View it is recommends that you configure your VMware View Horizon Servers with a signed SSL certificate. Default when you install a VMware View Horizon servers, a certificate is generated that is not signed by a CA. Because it is not signed by a CA It is possible to to intercept traffic. So it is highly recommend to replace the default certificate with a signed certificate after the installation.</description></item><item><title>Optimize Windows 8 for Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) environments</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/04/12/optimize-windows-8-for-virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-environments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 07:07:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/04/12/optimize-windows-8-for-virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-environments/</guid><description>Optimize and tuning a Windows 8 desktop in a VDI environment is important to reduce for example the CPU, IOPS and the memory footprint. During the Microsoft Management Summit (MMS) 2013 a breakout session about optimizing a Windows 8 desktop for Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) is held. The session has three main subjects:
Microsoft Guidance for Windows 8 Configuration VDI desktop. What version of Windows 8 do I need, how many CPUs, memory, disk partitioning etc.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View and Microsoft Lync 2013 support</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/04/03/vmware-horizon-view-and-microsoft-lync-2013-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:10:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/04/03/vmware-horizon-view-and-microsoft-lync-2013-support/</guid><description>VMware Horizon View 5.2 adds support for Microsoft Lync 2013 with audio en video. With Microsoft Lync 2010, only VoIP was supported, but required a dedicated IP-based phone. Microsoft and VMware collaborated to bring Lync 2013 support to the View 5.2 desktop.
Here is a list of supported features with Lync 2013 in VMware View:
Features
Support/Unsupported
Presence
Supported
Instant Message
Supported
Desktop Sharing
Supported
Application Sharing
Supported
PowerPoint Sharing</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/20/vmware-horizon-view-and-html-access-blast-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:06:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/20/vmware-horizon-view-and-html-access-blast-protocol/</guid><description>With the release of the VMware Horizon View Feature Pack 1 for VMware Horizon View 5.2 it possible to connect with HTML5 to your View desktop. This without installing additional software. The new HTML5 protocol is called Blast. Connecting by using the Blast HTML protocol can be handy when you are on a device that does not have the VMware View client installed.
The VMware Horizon View Feature Pack 1 contains the following two main components:</description></item><item><title>Tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 09:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>A security server is a special instance of View Connection Server that runs a subset of View Connection Server functions. You can use a security server to provide an additional layer of security between the internet and your internal network. A security server resides within a DMZ and acts as a proxy host for connections inside your trusted network.
Setting up a VMware Horizon View Security server can be a challenging task because you have to deal with firewalls and some ports that’s need to be opened between the servers.</description></item><item><title>Display the protocol used on the VMware View desktop background</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:49:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</guid><description>Systinternals has a tool called “BgInfo”. With this tool it is possible to display content on a Windows desktop background. For example environment variable Information such as “computer name” and the “IP address” can be displayed. This can be very handy when testing or for people that do they support for the Windows environment.
VMware View 5.1 has the following environment variables available in a desktop session :
ViewClient_Broker_DNS_Name ViewClient_Broker_DomainName ViewClient_Broker_Remote_IP_Address ViewClient_Broker_Tunneled ViewClient_Broker_Tunnel_URL ViewClient_Broker_URL ViewClient_Broker_UserName ViewClient_IP_Address ViewClient_LoggedOn_Domainname ViewClient_LoggedOn_Username ViewClient_Machine_Name ViewClient_MAC_Address ViewClient_Protocol ViewClient_Type ViewClient_Windows_Timezone The View environment variables can be added to BgInfo using the custom field option.</description></item><item><title>Configure the VMware Horizon View Event database with MS SQL Server Express</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/07/configure-the-view-5-1-event-database-with-sql-server-express/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 14:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/07/configure-the-view-5-1-event-database-with-sql-server-express/</guid><description>The event database record information about View Manager events. Without configure the event database events are logged in a log file. The log file has very limited information. So configuring the Event Database in the View environment is a best practice.
In Proof of Concept (PoC) environments MS SQL Server Express can be used for the Event database. This procedure describes how-to create a event database by using an MS SQL Server Express database:</description></item><item><title>New updates available on VMware vCenter, VMware View, Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter and Veeam Backup &amp; Replication</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/17/new-updates-available-on-vmware-vcenter-vmware-view-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter-and-veeam-backup-replication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 14:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/17/new-updates-available-on-vmware-vcenter-vmware-view-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter-and-veeam-backup-replication/</guid><description>Over the last days the following updates are released:
VMware vCenter Server 5.0 Update 1b VMware View 5.1.1 Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter Plug-in for VMware vSphere beta Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication 6.1 Patch 1 Below are the enhancements listed per product.
VMware vCenter Server 5.0 Update 1b What&amp;rsquo;s New:
VMware vCenter Server 5.0 Update 1b is a patch release and offers the following improvements:
vCenter Server 5.0 Update 1b introduces support for the following vCenter Databases Oracle 11g Enterprise Edition, Standard Edition, Standard ONE Edition Release 2 [11.</description></item><item><title>Shadow a VMware View desktop session</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/07/31/shadow-a-vmware-view-desktop-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/07/31/shadow-a-vmware-view-desktop-session/</guid><description>In VMware View there is no central way shadow a desktop session such as for example in Citrix XenApp. It would be nice if in the future it is possible to shadow a desktop from for example the VMware View Connection server. This is frequently asked question by customers were VMware View is implemented.
Brian Knudtson explain in his blog post how to access a PCoIP session from the vSphere Console.</description></item></channel></rss>