<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/vmware-workstation/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vmware-workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to install Windows 11 on VMware Workstation</title><link>/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 07:26:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>For testing purposes, I frequently use VMware Workstation to install Operating Systems such as Windows 11. The biggest challenge with Windows 11 is that you need a TPM 2.0 device. When installing Windows 11, if your computer does not meet the hardware requirements, you will see a message stating, “This PC can’t run Windows 11“.
Windows 11 requires the following minimal hardware specifications:
CPU: 1 GHz or faster with 2 or more cores on the processor RAM: 4 GB RAM Storage: 64 GB or larger Firmware: UEFI, Secure boot TPM: Trusted Platform Module (TPM) 2.</description></item><item><title>VMware Workstation Device/Credential Guard are not compatible</title><link>/2018/12/13/vmware-workstation-device-credential-guard-are-not-compatible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 07:36:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/12/13/vmware-workstation-device-credential-guard-are-not-compatible/</guid><description>When using VMware Workstation 15 Pro with on Windows 10 with the Hyper-V role enabled I’ve got the following error when trying to install or start Windows 10 in VMware Workstation:
VMware Workstation and Device/Credential Guard are not compatible. VMware Workstation can be run after disabling Device/Credential Guard. Please visit http://www.VMware.com/go/turnoff _CG_DG for more details.
In 2013 I did a post about using VMware Workstation and Hyper-V together on Windows 8, link .</description></item></channel></rss>