<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows-server-2012 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/windows-server-2012/</link><description>Recent content in windows-server-2012 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 16:18:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/windows-server-2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Identify LUN IDs in Windows Server 2012 R2</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/26/identify-lun-ids-in-windows-server-2012-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 19:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/26/identify-lun-ids-in-windows-server-2012-r2/</guid><description>During a Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V implementation I needed to identify all the iSCSI disks (LUNs) presented by an EMC VNX SAN to the Hyper-v Failover cluster. Each presented iSCSI disk has a unique LUN ID. To View the LUN ID of a disk, you can use the diskpart command.</description></item><item><title>Enable the Intel I217-V NIC in Windows Server 2012</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/24/enable-the-intel-i217-v-nic-in-windows-server-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 20:44:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/24/enable-the-intel-i217-v-nic-in-windows-server-2012/</guid><description>My new Gigabyte Z87-D3HP motherboard with support for 4th Generation Intel® Core™ processors (codename Haswell) has a onboard Intel I217-V NIC. The NIC is not recognized and supported in Windows Server 2012. As with the “Enable the Intel 82579V NIC in Windows Server 2012 ” blogpost it is possible to enable the NIC in Windows Server 2012.</description></item><item><title>Create a signed certificate for VMware View Connection Servers using a Windows Server 2012 CA</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</guid><description>For VMware Horizon View it is recommends that you configure your VMware View Horizon Servers with a signed SSL certificate. Default when you install a VMware View Horizon servers, a certificate is generated that is not signed by a CA. Because it is not signed by a CA It is possible to to intercept traffic.</description></item><item><title>Switch between Windows Server 2012 core and Windows Server 2012 GUI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/22/why-switch-between-windows-server-2012-core-and-windows-server-2012-gui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 08:55:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/22/why-switch-between-windows-server-2012-core-and-windows-server-2012-gui/</guid><description>In Windows Server 2012 you can choose between a Server Core and Server with a GUI (full) during the installation. The Full Server GUI has all the tools and options to configure and troubleshoot. Server core is a minimal Windows installation with less tools and options.
Server Core has the following advantages over Server Full:</description></item><item><title>License Windows Server 2012 editions in virtual environments</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/02/license-windows-server-2012-editions-in-virtual-environments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/02/license-windows-server-2012-editions-in-virtual-environments/</guid><description>As virtualization consultant I got frequently questions about Windows Server 2012 licensing in virtual environments such as VMware and Hyper-V. Here is a short blog about Windows Server 2012 licensing in virtual environments.
What about the Windows Server 2012 license:
The Windows Server 2012 licenses are based on the physical processor A single license covers two physical processors.</description></item><item><title>Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012 support on VMware ESXi, Workstation and Fusion</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/12/11/windows-8-and-windows-server-2012-support-on-vmware-esxi-workstation-and-fusion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 12:39:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/12/11/windows-8-and-windows-server-2012-support-on-vmware-esxi-workstation-and-fusion/</guid><description>The following VMware releases are supported with Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012:
OS Supported versions Windows 8 32/64 Bits Workstation 9 Fusion 5.0 ESXi 5.0 U1 ESXi 5.1 Windows Server 2012 64 Bits Workstation 9 Fusion 5.0 ESXi 5.0 U1 ESXi 5.1 Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012 are supported on ESX 5.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade Windows Server 2012 Release Candidate (RC) to RTM</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/07/upgrade-windows-server-2012-release-candidate-rc-to-rtm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 09:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/07/upgrade-windows-server-2012-release-candidate-rc-to-rtm/</guid><description>Now Windows Server 2012 is release I tried to upgrade my lab environment from Microsoft Windows Server 2012 RC 8400 to Windows 2012 RTM. It is not officially supported to upgrade from Windows Server 2012 RC to Windows Server 2012 RTM by Microsoft.
I did the following steps to upgrade:</description></item><item><title>Enable the Intel 82579V NIC in Windows Server 2012</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/08/enable-the-intel-82579v-nic-in-windows-server-2012/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 13:59:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/08/enable-the-intel-82579v-nic-in-windows-server-2012/</guid><description>After installing Windows Server 2012 on my homebrew server, the onboard Intel 82579V Gigabit NIC on the Asus P9X79 motherboard was not working. On the Asus site I found Windows 8 Intel drivers for the motherboard. After installing the drivers the NIC was still not working. To get the Intel 82579V NIC working in Windows Server 2012 follow these steps:</description></item><item><title>Nest Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V in VMware ESXi 5</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/28/nest-windows-server-2012-hyper-v-in-vmware-esxi-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 09:57:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/28/nest-windows-server-2012-hyper-v-in-vmware-esxi-5/</guid><description>In this blog post I explain how you can install Windows 2012 Server Release Candidate (RC) in VMware ESXi and enable the Hyper-V role. It is possible to build a Hyper-V cluster LAB and live migrate VMs between the virtual Hyper-V nodes on one VMware ESXi 5 host.
Before you begin make sure:</description></item><item><title>Install Windows Server 2012 in VMware Workstation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/04/install-windows-server-2012-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 19:14:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/04/install-windows-server-2012-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>This procedure describes how to install Windows Server 2012 in VMware Workstation. The following versions are used:
VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 e.x.p Build-646643 Windows Server 2012 Release Candidate Datacenter Build 8400 In VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 create a new VM with the following settings:
New Virtual Machine Custom (advanced) Workstation Tech Preview Select “I will install the operating system later” Select “Microsoft Windows” and select as version “Windows 8 x64” Set the Name and Location Minimal 1 processor, 1 core 2048 MB memory Select “Use network address translation (NAT)” Select “LSI Logic SAS” Create a new virtual disk SCSI 60 GB disk size Leave default disk file Finish After the VM is created, edit virtual Machine settings and browse for the Windows Server 2012 ISO in the the CD/DVD option Remove the VM from VMware Workstation by clicking on the X icon Edit the VMX file (i use Notepad++) and add the following line to the end to of the VMX file: vmGenCounter.</description></item></channel></rss>