<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New whitebox for extending my home lab</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/01/05/new-whitebox-extending-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 11:48:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/01/05/new-whitebox-extending-home-lab/</guid><description>For a couple of months I’m searching for an extra whitebox host for extending my home lab environment. My current lab whitebox is a Haswell based whitebox (see: link). Here is an overview of the new lab environment:
For the new whitebox I had the following requirements:
Hardware such as NICs must be recognized by VMware ESXi Use 32 GB memory or more Low power consumption Expandable Small form factor Quiet Possibility to run nested hypervisors such as VMware ESXi and Hyper-V Remote Management Possibility to create a VMware Cluster and use vMotion, HA, DRS and DPM with the existing Haswell host I reviewed the following popular home lab systems:</description></item><item><title>Intel X79 whitebox for vSphere 5 and Hyper-V 3</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</guid><description>In an earlier blog post (found here ) I mentioned that it is time for a new homebrew whitebox based on the Intel X79 chipset. With the X79 chipset it is possible to install 64GB of memory (8 x 8 GB). Because the 8 GB DIMMs are expensive on the moment, I decided to use 8 x 4GB DIMMs (total 32GB).</description></item><item><title>What about VMware Virtual Machine hardware versions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/29/what-about-vmware-virtual-machine-hardware-versions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 14:44:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/29/what-about-vmware-virtual-machine-hardware-versions/</guid><description>It depends on the features you need. If you want for example use the “Changed Blocked Tracking (CBT)” feature, you need at least hardware version 7.
In ESX 3.x hardware version 4 is introduced, in vSphere 4.x hardware version 7 is introduced and in vSphere 5 hardware version 8 is introduced.</description></item></channel></rss>