<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMware ESXi on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vmware-esxi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMware ESXi on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 16:02:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vmware-esxi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patch a VMware ESXI host with the ESXCLI command and choose the right image profile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/12/08/patch-a-VMware-esxi-hosts-with-esxcli-command-and-choose-the-right-image-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 08:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/12/08/patch-a-VMware-esxi-hosts-with-esxcli-command-and-choose-the-right-image-profile/</guid>
      <description>When installing a patch on a VMware ESXi host using the ESXCLI command you need to specify the image profile that is available in the ESXi patch.&#xA;Here are the steps for patching a VMware ESXi host with the correct image profile:&#xA;Go to the Customer Connect Patch Downloads page. Download the patch needed, In this example, I use ESXi patch VMware-ESXi-7.0U3o-22348816-depot.zip Upload the patch to a datastore Make a SSH connection to the ESXi host Place the host in maintenance mode esxcli system maintenanceMode set –enable-true Now you need to know which image profiles are available in the VMware ESXi patch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identify the NIC driver and supported driver version for an ESXi server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/15/identify-nic-driver-and-supported-driver-version-for-esxi-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/15/identify-nic-driver-and-supported-driver-version-for-esxi-server/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I troubleshooted some NIC driver problems in VMware ESXi. During the troubleshooting, I needed to Identify the NIC driver, the software version used, and the latest driver version supported by VMware. Here are the steps outlined.&#xA;Identify the NIC driver and software version: Make an SSH connection to the ESXi host Identify all the NICs by using the following command: esxcli network nic list In this example you can see that Intel (igb) and Broadcom (tg3) NICs are used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESXi Broadcom data corruption problem with the tg3 driver. Check your environment!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/02/19/vmware-esxi-broadcom-data-corruption-problem-with-tg3-driver-check-your-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 09:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/02/19/vmware-esxi-broadcom-data-corruption-problem-with-tg3-driver-check-your-environment/</guid>
      <description>VMware has released a new KB article (2072515) on possible data corruption with Broadcom adapters that use the tg3 driver. This problem can occur when:&#xA;The system is configured with greater than 4 GB RAM TCP Segmentation Offload (TSO) is enabled on the adapter The system is running ESXi/ESX 3.5, 4.x, 5.0, 5.1 and 5.5 The tg3 driver version is less than v3.135b The advice is to update to the latest tg3 driver that fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable the Intel I217-V network card in VMware ESXi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/09/20/enable-the-intel-i217-v-network-card-in-vmware-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 09:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/09/20/enable-the-intel-i217-v-network-card-in-vmware-esxi/</guid>
      <description>The motherboard of my Haswell whitebox contains an Intel I217-V network card. See my “Haswell low power whitebox for ESXi and Hyper-V ” post for more information. The Intel I217-V network card is not recognized by VMware ESXi 5.x by default. On the VMware community I found a post with the Intel I217-V ESXi driver attached. To enable the Intel I217-V network card you have two options:&#xA;Inject the driver in the ESXi ISO using for example the “ESXi-Customizer” tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backup the ESXi configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/08/09/backup-the-esxi-configuration-and-update-the-status-in-vcenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/08/09/backup-the-esxi-configuration-and-update-the-status-in-vcenter/</guid>
      <description>I create a simple PowerCLI script that backups all the VMware ESXi host configurations that are connected to a vCenter Server. This script can be scheduled to make for example every week a backup of the ESXi server configs. You can easily customize the script for your own needs.&#xA;#Variables $Folder = &amp;#34;D:\Backup\BCK-ESXi&amp;#34; $FolderOld = &amp;#34;D:\Backup\BCK-ESXi\_old&amp;#34; $vc= &amp;#34;vcenterserver-fqdn&amp;#34; # Connect to local vCenter Server Connect-ViServer # Move existing backup files to the old directory Move-Item ($Folder + &amp;#34;\*.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
