<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>microsoft on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in microsoft on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 21:58:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perform an Azure Virtual Machine (VM) inventory with PowerShell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/05/16/perform-an-azure-vm-inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 17:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/05/16/perform-an-azure-vm-inventory/</guid>
      <description>To generate quickly an overview of all the Virtual Machines (VMs) in an Azure subscription I made a PowerShell script that uses the Azure Az PowerShell module. This script will do an inventory of all VMs in a subscription.&#xA;The following VM information is displayed per subscription:&#xA;Name PowerState Region Resource Group VM Size CPU Cores Memory (MB) License Type Operating System Offer SKU Publisher VM Generation VM Agent version OS Name OS Version NIC Name VNet Private IP address Public IP address OS disk name OS disk size (GB) OS storage type OS disk caching Data disks count Data disks names Admin username If boot diagnostics is enabled Boot diagnostics storage account Tags The time the VM was created The output will be displayed in the PowerShell console, to a PowerShell GridView output, and saved to a delimited CSV file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware, Microsoft and Starwind software updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/02/18/vmware-microsoft-and-starwind-software-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 12:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/02/18/vmware-microsoft-and-starwind-software-updates/</guid>
      <description>Last weeks a lots of software updates and new releases are published. Here’s an overview of some of them:&#xA;VMware VMware vSphere 4.1 Update 1 A new update for vSphere 4.1 is released. Here are the ESX(i) and vCenter improvements:&#xA;VMware ESX(i) 4.1 Update 1 improvements Enablement of Trusted Execution Technology (TXT) — ESXi 4.1 Update 1 can be configured to boot with Intel Trusted Execution Technology (TXT). This boot option can protect ESXi in some cases where system binaries are corrupted or have been tampered with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test Microsoft Hyper-V R2 server on your laptop with Virtual Hard Disk (VHD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/03/test-microsoft-hyper-v-r2-server-on-your-laptop-with-virtual-hard-disk-vhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 09:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/03/test-microsoft-hyper-v-r2-server-on-your-laptop-with-virtual-hard-disk-vhd/</guid>
      <description>When you want to test some Microsoft Hyper-V R2 stuff it’s handy to do that on your laptop. I test a lot stuff on my laptop equipped with Microsoft Windows 7, 8GB RAM and VMware Workstation. Installing Microsoft Hyper-V R2 for example in VMware Workstation is possible, but it is not possible to start any Virtual Machines (VMs). Microsoft Hyper-V requires a processor with Intel-VT or AMD-V with the No-Execute (NX) feature.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
