<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vdp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/vdp/</link><description>Recent content in vdp on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/vdp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows 2008 R2 VMs fail to backup with VMware Data Protection (VDP)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/01/18/windows-2008-r2-vms-fail-to-backup-with-vmware-data-protection-vdp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 11:04:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/01/18/windows-2008-r2-vms-fail-to-backup-with-vmware-data-protection-vdp/</guid><description>When using VMware Data Protection (VDP) 5.1 and want to backup Windows 2008 R2 VM’s you should disable application-consistent quiescing. On the moment the VADP API doesn’t support Windows 2008 R2 application-consistent quiescing. So be sure that servers that uses a database such as SQL and Exchange are backuped with other third party backup software else the database will be not consistent when restoring!
If you don’t disable application-consistent quiescing the backup of the Windows 2008 R2 will probably fail.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading the vSphere Data Protection (VDP) appliance</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/12/07/upgrading-the-vsphere-data-protection-vdp-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 10:10:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/12/07/upgrading-the-vsphere-data-protection-vdp-appliance/</guid><description>Here are the steps outlined for upgrading the vSphere Data Protection (VDP) appliance.
1. Check the version of the VDP. SSH to the VDP appliance and use the following command:
rpm –qa | grep vdr
The current version of the VDP appliance is: vdr-1.1.53-53
2. The vSphere (web) client displays version 5.1.0.0 (5.1.0.0). This version will not change after the upgrade.
3. Shutdown the VDP appliance.
4. The virtual disks used by the vSphere Data Protection appliance are set to be “Independent - Persistent.</description></item><item><title>Implementing vSphere Data Protection (VDP) tips</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/09/21/implementing-vsphere-data-protection-vdp-tips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/09/21/implementing-vsphere-data-protection-vdp-tips/</guid><description>vSphere Data Protection (VDP) is replacing VMware Data Recovery (vDR). VDP is a more robust product based on the EMC Avamar product.
Here are some VDP implementing tips:
Each vCenter server can support up to 10 VDP appiances Each VDP appliance supports up to 100 VMs VDP stores deduplicated data on the 0.5,1 or 2 TB datastores. It is not possible to use CIFS or NFS shares directly from the VDP appliance.</description></item></channel></rss>