<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Runecast Analyzer makes hardware checking against the VMware HCL easy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/08/13/runecast-analyzer-makes-hardware-checking-against-the-vmware-hcl-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 07:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/08/13/runecast-analyzer-makes-hardware-checking-against-the-vmware-hcl-easy/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer is a tool that helps VMware administrators to proactive manage there vSphere environment. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. It uses best practices, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STIG, PCI-DSS v3.2.1 and HIPAA) and known issues found in the VMware Knowledge Base to protect the Software Defined Data Center (SDDC). Runecast Analyzer supports the following VMware products:&#xA;VMware vSphere VMware vSAN VMware NSX-V VMware Horizon Runecast Analyzer introduced a new feature called &amp;ldquo;Automated VMware HCL&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ESXi Compatibility Simulation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor vSAN with ControlUp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</guid>
      <description>One of the new enhancements of ControlUp 7.3 is vSAN monitoring support. ControlUp will detect the vSAN cluster(s), objects and displays real-time vSAN specific metrics and metadata. In this blog post I highlight the features of the new vSAN integration in ControlUp 7.3.&#xA;Installation The vSAN cluster is automatically recognized by ControlUp when the following requirements are met:&#xA;PowerShell minimum Version 5.0 VMware PowerCLI 10.1.1.x .NET framework version 4.5 vSAN Performance service should be turned on on the cluster The user account configured for the hypervisor connection requires the “storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication - Multi-Tenancy, licensing and conclusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/11/02/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-editions-and-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 10:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/11/02/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-editions-and-licensing/</guid>
      <description>In the last part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the Multi-Tenancy option, licensing and the final conclusion.&#xA;Multi-Tenancy and branding NAKIVO supports multi-tenancy to deliver Backup-as-a-Service (BAAS) and Disaster-Recovery as a Service (DRaas). The tenants are isolated from each other and cannot access other tenants. Each tenant can access their own environment through a self-service portal and perform all data protection of recovery tasks.&#xA;For each tenant custom branding can be used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New enhancements in Runecast Analyzer 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 09:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer provides proactive management for VMware environments. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. In 90% of the outages with VMware environments, the root cause is based on a known issue that is already available in the VMware knowledge base. Runecast Analyzer uses information from the VMware knowledge base, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STG and PCI-DSS), and best practices to proactively identify problems or outages before they occur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Replication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/23/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 18:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/23/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-replication/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the replication feature. With the replication feature you can replicate VMs. The source VMs are copied, a VM replica is created of each and replicated to the target VMware environment (also known as the recovery site).&#xA;VM Replication protects for example against the following type of disasters:&#xA;Natural disasters (earthquakes, floods, tornados etc.) Data center problems such as power losses, fire and water damage Hardware problems such as host, network and storage failures Human errors VM failures caused by updates or patches, virus or manually removal The replication feature can be used for business continuity as part of you&amp;rsquo;re disaster recovery plan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Backup and Recovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/16/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-backup-and-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 06:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/16/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-backup-and-recovery/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review the backup and recovery options will be highlighted.&#xA;Backup To begin with backup and recovery we first need a backup job. Configuring a backup job contains the following five steps:&#xA;1. VMs: Select the VMs to backup from the inventory of the vCenter Server or ESXi host. 2. Destination: Select the destination to store the VMs. Select the onboard repository with deduplication and compression enabled for storage space savings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/03/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 07:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/03/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-installation/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the installation and basic configuration.&#xA;For the installation of NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication you have several options. NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication can be installed as&#xA;Windows or Linux installation package Virtual Appliance for VMware (OVF) In the Amazon AWS cloud Directly installed on NAS devices such as QNAP, Synology and NETGEAR In my test environment I installed NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication as Virtual Appliance (VA) on my VMware vSphere 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/01/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 15:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/01/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-released/</guid>
      <description>NAKIVO announced today that NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication v7.5 is out of beta and available. This new version includes the following new features:&#xA;Support for VMware vSphere 6.7: It&amp;rsquo;s now officially compatible with the latest version of VMware vSphere. Cross-Platform Recovery: With the Cross-Platform Recovery feature, users can export VM data from VMware and Hyper-V backups into VMDK, VHD, or VHDX format. The exported files can then be used for recovery across different hypervisors, cross-platform VM data migration, long-term archival, or sandbox testing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proactively manage your vSphere environment with Runecast Analyzer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/02/27/proactively-manage-vsphere-environment-runecast-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 20:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/02/27/proactively-manage-vsphere-environment-runecast-analyzer/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got the opportunity to test Runecast Analyzer. Runecast Analyzer Proactively use VMware KBs, best practices and security hardening guidelines to identify problems in your VMware environment. In this review you find my own experiences of testing Runecast Analyzer.&#xA;Deployment&#xA;The deployment of Runecast Analyzer is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s an on-premises deployment on you&amp;rsquo;re vSphere environment. Within a couple of minutes the Runecast is up and running. First download and deploy the virtual appliance OVA in an existing vSphere 5 or higher environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested: VDI End User Experience monitoring tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/08/26/tested-vdi-end-user-experience-monitor-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 07:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/08/26/tested-vdi-end-user-experience-monitor-tools/</guid>
      <description>The success and effectiveness of a VDI environment depends on the End User Experience (UX). When the End User Experience isn’t good, users will complain and the VDI project will fail. So the ability to analyze, report and troubleshoot when a problem occurs is critical in a VDI environment. To get this insight I tested ControlUp v6 and VMware vRealize Operations for Horizon v6.3. Both tools are tested against the following subjects:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested: VMware snapshot management with Snapwatcher</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/06/02/tested-vmware-snapshot-management-with-snapwatcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 07:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/06/02/tested-vmware-snapshot-management-with-snapwatcher/</guid>
      <description>To monitor and manage VMware Virtual Machine Snapshots Opvizor has released a tool called Snapwatcher. As consultant I see often that admins don’t have an overview of all the snapshots that exists in their environment. The main concerns with Virtual Machine snapshots are:&#xA;Snapshots are created and forgot to remove Snapshots can very quickly grow in size Snapshots filling datastore space Delta files may cause decreased Virtual Machine and host performance In this review Opvizor Snapwatcher is tested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested SMS PASSCODE multi-factor authentication with VMware Horizon View</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2015/04/tested-sms-passcode-multi-factor-authentication-with-vmware-horizon-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 06:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2015/04/tested-sms-passcode-multi-factor-authentication-with-vmware-horizon-view/</guid>
      <description>Citrix Web Interface Protection RADIUS Protection Cloud Application Protection IIS Web Site Protection ISA/TMG Web Site Protection Windows Logon Protection Secure Device Provisioning (for ActiveSync devices) In this review we test how-to integrate SMS PASSCODE with the latest version of VMware Horizon View using RADIUS authentication.&#xA;What is SMS PASSCODE Unlike traditional hardware-token based solutions, SMS PASSCODE works without distribution of any hardware-tokens. As a result, the logistic overhead involved is minimal and roll-out is much faster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor VMware Horizon View environments with ControlUp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/10/09/controlup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 07:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/10/09/controlup/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago ControlUp released version 4.0 with support for VMware Horizon View. In this blog post I share my experience with ControlUp 4.0 monitoring VMware vSphere and VMware Horizon View.&#xA;What is ControlUp&#xA;ControlUp is a real-time performance monitor for Microsoft Remote Desktop Services (RDS), Citrix, and physical- and virtual server environments. ControlUp can be used to:&#xA;Troubleshoot performance issues in real time Analyze performance trends and usage patterns Compare and manage multiple computers Investigate incidents and receive email alerts The new 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested: PHD Virtual Backup 6.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</guid>
      <description>PHD Virtual Backup is a backup and recovery solution for VMware and Citrix environments. PHD Virtual Backup version 6 is released. We tested this new version with VMware vSpher&#xA;What’s new in PHD Virtual Backup version 6: PHD Virtual Backup version 6.0 contains the following major enhancements:&#xA;PHD Instant Recovery: Instant Recovery lets you access your backed up data right away. The VM(s) will be powered on directly from the backup storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested: Altaro Hyper-V Backup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</guid>
      <description>In my LAB environment I tested Altaro Hyper-V Backup version 3. Altaro Hyper-V Backup is software that makes it possible to backup and restore Windows 2008 (R2) Hyper-V VMs.&#xA;Editions There are three editions available: The free edition, the standard edition and the unlimited edition. For this test I used the unlimited edition because it supports “Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs)”. More info can be found here.&#xA;Installation Altaro Hyper-V Backup needs to be installed on the Hyper-V host.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
