<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>boot on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/boot/</link><description>Recent content in boot on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/boot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Identify the boot device for a VMware ESXi host</title><link>/2021/11/26/identify-the-boot-device-for-a-vmware-esxi-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 08:31:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/11/26/identify-the-boot-device-for-a-vmware-esxi-host/</guid><description>With vSphere 7 VMware is moving away from supporting SD cards and USB as boot media. ESXi Boot configuration with only SD card or USB drive, without any persistent device, is deprecated with vSphere 7 Update 3. In future vSphere releases, it will be an unsupported configuration!
Move from SD cards and USB devices to local persistent disk(s) such as SATA, SAS (including SATADOM), SSD disks as a boot device for example.</description></item><item><title>Install VMware ESXi 4.1 from bootable USB stick</title><link>/2010/10/25/install-vmware-esxi-4-1-from-bootable-usb-stick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/25/install-vmware-esxi-4-1-from-bootable-usb-stick/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have a DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and installing a single VMware ESXi server. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable and install VMware ESXi 4.1 from it by using Windows.
Preparation:
Need 1GB USB memory stick or more. Download the VMware ESXi 4.1 ISO named VMware-VMvisor-Installer-4.1.0-260247.x86_64.iso (In this example I used the VMware vSphere Hypervisor version). Update: The latest version of VMware ESXi is 4.</description></item><item><title>Create a bootable USB to install Windows 8 Server or Hyper-V Server 8</title><link>/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and install for example Windows Server 8. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable for the following OS versions:
Windows Server 8 Hyper-V Server 8 Server 2008 R2 Hyper-V Server R2 Preparation: Need a 4 GB USB memory stick or more Download the desired ISO and save it Stick the USB stick on a free USB port on your computer equipped with a Windows OS.</description></item></channel></rss>