<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows-8 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/windows-8/</link><description>Recent content in Windows-8 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/windows-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimize Windows 8 for Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) environments</title><link>/2013/04/12/optimize-windows-8-for-virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-environments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 07:07:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/04/12/optimize-windows-8-for-virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-environments/</guid><description>Optimize and tuning a Windows 8 desktop in a VDI environment is important to reduce for example the CPU, IOPS and the memory footprint. During the Microsoft Management Summit (MMS) 2013 a breakout session about optimizing a Windows 8 desktop for Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) is held. The session has three main subjects:</description></item><item><title>Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012 support on VMware ESXi, Workstation and Fusion</title><link>/2012/12/11/windows-8-and-windows-server-2012-support-on-vmware-esxi-workstation-and-fusion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 12:39:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/12/11/windows-8-and-windows-server-2012-support-on-vmware-esxi-workstation-and-fusion/</guid><description>The following VMware releases are supported with Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012:
OS Supported versions Windows 8 32/64 Bits Workstation 9 Fusion 5.0 ESXi 5.0 U1 ESXi 5.1 Windows Server 2012 64 Bits Workstation 9 Fusion 5.0 ESXi 5.0 U1 ESXi 5.1 Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012 are supported on ESX 5.</description></item><item><title>Enable Windows Server 8 Hyper-V in VMware Workstation</title><link>/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 21:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 is available as download. The Technology Preview makes it possible for example to install and operate Windows 8 and Windows Server 8 in a VM and the possibility to nest VMs.
I tested the installation of Windows Server 8 in VMware Workstation TP, enabled the Hyper-V role and run a Windows 7 64-bit VM in Hyper-V.</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2012 PowerShell Cmdlets for Hyper-V help</title><link>/2012/03/07/windows-server-8-powershell-cmdlets-for-hyper-v-help/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 14:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/03/07/windows-server-8-powershell-cmdlets-for-hyper-v-help/</guid><description>In Windows 2008 &amp;amp; Windows2008 R2 there were no official PowerShell Cmdlets available for Hyper-V. This is changed in Windows 2012 and Windows 8. Windows Server 2012 and 8 has 162 or more PowerShell Cmdlets available for Hyper-V. Windows 8 uses PowerShell version 3.
Cmdlets are very powerful, that lets you automate all aspects of Hyper-V.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows 8 Consumer Preview as VM in VMware vSphere 5</title><link>/2012/02/29/install-windows-8-consumer-preview-as-vm-in-vmware-vsphere-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 18:55:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/02/29/install-windows-8-consumer-preview-as-vm-in-vmware-vsphere-5/</guid><description>Today the Windows 8 Consumer Preview is launched. To install the Windows 8 Consumer Preview as VM in VMware vSphere 5, use the following steps:
Install VMware ESXi 5.0 patch release ESXi500-201112001 . If you didn’t install the patch the following screen appears when booting the Windows 8 ISO: Your computer ran into a problem and needs to restart</description></item><item><title>Create a bootable USB to install Windows 8 Server or Hyper-V Server 8</title><link>/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and install for example Windows Server 8. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable for the following OS versions:
Windows Server 8 Hyper-V Server 8 Server 2008 R2 Hyper-V Server R2 Preparation: Need a 4 GB USB memory stick or more Download the desired ISO and save it Stick the USB stick on a free USB port on your computer equipped with a Windows OS.</description></item></channel></rss>