<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vcenter-Server on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/vcenter-server/</link><description>Recent content in Vcenter-Server on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vcenter-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove expired root certificates from a vCenter Server the easy way</title><link>/2023/04/17/quick-tip-remove-expired-root-certificates-from-a-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 17:44:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/04/17/quick-tip-remove-expired-root-certificates-from-a-vcenter-server/</guid><description>I see a lot of vCenter Servers that have expired root certificates. In the vCenter Server Appliance Administration section under Certificate Management, you can see the expired certificates.
Cleaning up expired root certificates from the vCenter Server can be done by using the &amp;ldquo;vecs-cli&amp;rdquo; command on the vCenter Server Appliance (In the vSphere Client this is not possible).</description></item><item><title>Patch a vCenter Server High Availability (VCHA) environment</title><link>/2021/01/25/patch-a-vcenter-server-high-availability-vcha-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 20:08:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/01/25/patch-a-vcenter-server-high-availability-vcha-environment/</guid><description>Last week I tried to patch a vCenter Server High Availability (VCHA) 7 cluster environment. I read the documentation and the procedure described looks still the same as in version 6.x. First patch the witness node, then the passive node, failover the active node, and patch the passive node using the software-packages tool.</description></item><item><title>Adding a static route to a vCenter Server with multiple Network Interface Cards (NICs)</title><link>/2020/12/15/adding-static-routes-to-a-vcenter-server-with-multiple-network-cards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 13:22:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/12/15/adding-static-routes-to-a-vcenter-server-with-multiple-network-cards/</guid><description>For a Disaster Recovery (DR) site, I designed a separate isolated VMware Horizon environment. The vCenter Server has an external (eth0) and internal (eth1) IP address. The external connection is for management and restoring production VMs to the DR environment. The internal connection is for Horizon infrastructure components that need access to the vCenter Server such as a VMware Horizon Server and VMware App Volumes.</description></item><item><title>Blue circle in the vSphere client after upgrading to vCenter Server 6.7 Update 2</title><link>/2019/04/24/blue-circle-in-the-vsphere-client-after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-6-7-update-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:02:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/04/24/blue-circle-in-the-vsphere-client-after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-6-7-update-2/</guid><description>After upgrading the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) to version 6.7 Update 2, I tried to log in using the vSphere Client. After entering the credentials an endless blue running circle appears.
In the VAMI interface (https://vcsa-fqdn:5480) of the VCSA, the health statistics of all the components are green (okay) so I decided to reboot the VCSA.</description></item></channel></rss>