<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vshield on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vshield/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vshield on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vshield/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Networking and Security license in Evaluation Mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/18/vcloud-networking-and-security-license-in-evaluation-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 08:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/18/vcloud-networking-and-security-license-in-evaluation-mode/</guid>
      <description>A customer has a VMware vSphere 5.1 environment with VMware Horizon View 5.2 environment and Trend Micro Deep Security installed. Trend Micro Deep Security uses the VMware vShield Endpoint framework. In the vSphere license manager asset the “vCloud Networking and Security” license is displayed in evaluation mode and has a expire date.&#xA;This is strange because vSphere 5.1 &amp;gt; includes a vShield Endpoint license. So no extra vShield licenses are required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable the vShield driver in VMware tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/11/enable-the-vshield-driver-in-vmware-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 12:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/11/enable-the-vshield-driver-in-vmware-tools/</guid>
      <description>One of the steps of a vShield Endpoint based deployment is to enable the vShield driver in VMware tools. The vShield driver is not enabled by default. This can be done manually or automatically for example in the golden image of a VDI desktop.&#xA;Here are the manually steps when the VMware tools already are installed:&#xA;In the vSphere client open a Console session Select VM – Guest – Install/Upgrade VMware Tools Choose Interactive Tools Upgrade In the VM open the setup program Choose Next Choose Modify Expand the VMCI Driver section, select vShield Drivers and select “This feature will be installed on the local hard drive” Next – modify If you are installing VMware Tools in a number of Windows virtual machines, you can automate its installation by using the following syntax:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
