<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware View on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/vmware-view/</link><description>Recent content in VMware View on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vmware-view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enable Touch ID Authentication in VMware Horizon</title><link>/2015/10/05/enable-touch-id-authentication-in-vmware-horizon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 06:47:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/10/05/enable-touch-id-authentication-in-vmware-horizon/</guid><description>In Horizon 6.2 it is possible to authenticate with Apples Touch ID. Touch ID is not enabled by default and has the following minimal requirements:
iPhone 5S, 6, and 6 Plus iPad Air 2 and iPad mini 3 IOS 8 Horizon 6 version 6.2 The View Connection Server must present a valid root-signed certificate to the Horizon Client Horizon 3.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Client Drive Redirection</title><link>/2015/06/05/vmware-horizon-view-client-drive-redirection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 09:42:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/06/05/vmware-horizon-view-client-drive-redirection/</guid><description>On of the new features of VMware Horizon 6 version 6.1.1 is Client Drive Redirection (CDR). Microsoft RDS and Citrix already have CDR for many years in there product. Now this handy feature is available in Horizon View. CDR is supported on VDI desktops (single-user) and RDS desktops and applications on Windows and as Tech Preview on Mac OS X clients.</description></item><item><title>The end of Tera1 zero client support in VMware Horizon View 6</title><link>/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 14:01:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</guid><description>The Tera1 zero clients has reached their limits on new features that can be added and the ability to support new features of Horizon View such as RDSH. Teradici supports the following combinations:
ProcessorFirmwareHorizon View Version supportVMware CertifiedTera24.8.06.1YesTera24.7.16.0YesTera14.7.16.0.1No (*2)(*2) Tera1 zero clients are certified on VMware Horizon View 5.3 and earlier.</description></item><item><title>Tested SMS PASSCODE multi-factor authentication with VMware Horizon View</title><link>/blog/2015/04/tested-sms-passcode-multi-factor-authentication-with-vmware-horizon-view/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 06:42:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2015/04/tested-sms-passcode-multi-factor-authentication-with-vmware-horizon-view/</guid><description>Citrix Web Interface Protection RADIUS Protection Cloud Application Protection IIS Web Site Protection ISA/TMG Web Site Protection Windows Logon Protection Secure Device Provisioning (for ActiveSync devices) In this review we test how-to integrate SMS PASSCODE with the latest version of VMware Horizon View using RADIUS authentication.
What is SMS PASSCODE Unlike traditional hardware-token based solutions, SMS PASSCODE works without distribution of any hardware-tokens.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot replication problems between VMware Horizon View Connection servers</title><link>/2014/09/17/vmware-view-check-the-replication-status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:15:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/09/17/vmware-view-check-the-replication-status/</guid><description>In environments with multiple Horizon View Connection Servers (High Available) the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) directory is replicated. Configuration, Pool and desktop information is stored in the ADAM database. Problems with replication can result in:
Configuration changes made are not replicated Authentication problems The VMware View Administrator dashboard does not check the replication status.</description></item><item><title>Error occurred during vCenter operation when editing a VMware Horizon View pool</title><link>/2014/09/09/error-occurred-vcenter-operation-editing-vmware-horizon-view-pool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 10:55:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/09/09/error-occurred-vcenter-operation-editing-vmware-horizon-view-pool/</guid><description>When editing a VMware Horizon desktop pool in some situations the server error ‘Error occurred during vCenter operation’. appears.
The error hasn&amp;rsquo;t any useful information that says what is wrong. When this error occurs the vCenter Server is unable to find one or more objects listed in the desktop pool. When changing datacenter, cluster or host settings in vCenter the desktop pool must be updated to.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8 white paper update</title><link>/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</guid><description>VMware released an updated version of the “VMware Horizon with View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8” whitepaper. This white paper discuss the necessary information for optimizing a Windows 7 or Windows 8 virtual desktop image for VMware Horizon View using the Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) or use a script-based approach.</description></item><item><title>Create a VMware Horizon View self signed certificate with makecert</title><link>/2014/06/24/create-a-vmware-horizon-view-self-signed-certificate-with-makecert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 07:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/06/24/create-a-vmware-horizon-view-self-signed-certificate-with-makecert/</guid><description>With the command line Windows utility makecert.exe it is possible to create quickly a self-signed (private) certificate that can be used with VMware Horizon View. Makecert is part of the Windows Software Deployment Kit (SDK)for Windows 7 and 8. Below are the steps outlined to create a self-signed certificate using makecert.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Network Port Diagram</title><link>/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 09:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</guid><description>VMware has released a Network Port Diagram diagram for VMware Horizon View 5.2.
This diagram covers an entire VMware View environment with protocols and port numbers used. In earlier blog posts I already create two small diagrams with protocols and port numbers used by VMware View:
VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol).</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot VMware View Security Server PCoIP port problems</title><link>/2013/07/26/troubleshoot-vmware-view-security-server-pcoip-port-problems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 11:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/07/26/troubleshoot-vmware-view-security-server-pcoip-port-problems/</guid><description>Recently I had to troubleshoot a VMware View Client connection problem. In a new VMware View environment the customer has installed a VMware Horizon View Security Server for the external connections. When a external View Client tried to connect through the Security Server using the PCoIP protocol to the View desktop the following appeared:</description></item><item><title>VMware View Manager 4.0.1 released</title><link>/2010/02/19/vmware-view-manager-4-0-1-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 07:40:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/02/19/vmware-view-manager-4-0-1-released/</guid><description>VMware View Manager 4.0.1 is released. This release includes the following new features:
Localization of VMware View The View Client and online help for View Client are now available in Japanese, French, German, and simplified Chinese. The View Manager Administration Guide, View Manager Release Notes, Getting Started with VMware View document, View Upgrade Guide, and View Architecture Planning Guide are also available in these languages.</description></item><item><title>VMware Desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC)</title><link>/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 11:11:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/28/vmware-desktop-reference-architecture-workload-simulator-rawc/</guid><description>VMware released last week the desktop Reference Architecture Workload Simulator (RAWC).
When validating VMware View designs it is important to simulate real world usage as closely as possible. The Desktop Reference Architecture Workload SImulator (RAWC) can be used to simulate a user workload in a typical Microsoft Windows® desktop environment.</description></item><item><title>VMware View 4 released</title><link>/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/21/vmware-view-4-released/</guid><description>The long awaited VMware View with the PCoIP protocol has landed and is available for download.
VMware View 4.0 includes the following new features:
VMware View with PCoIP – PCoIP provides an optimized desktop experience for the delivery of the entire desktop environment including applications, images, audio, and video content for a wide range of users on the LAN or across the WAN.</description></item><item><title>Huge amount of VMware updates</title><link>/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</guid><description>Today when i woke up there where a lot of VMware updates available (to much to handle for one day 🙂 ). I did an upgrade of my lab environment, it went smooth with any issues. VMware did a great job with the new improvements! Here’s a list of improvements with some screenshots:</description></item><item><title>VMware VIEW 4 useful information</title><link>/2009/11/13/vmware-view-4-useful-information/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 10:28:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/13/vmware-view-4-useful-information/</guid><description>After attending the VMware View 4 Talkshoe podcast the following information about the announced VMware View 4 was discussed:
VM’s per core: VM’s per core, In VMware View 3 the number was 6-9 VM’s per core, now in View 4 with for example the Intel Nehalem processors you can get to 12-16 VM’s per core.</description></item><item><title>VMware View 4 announced</title><link>/2009/11/09/vmware-view-4-announced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/09/vmware-view-4-announced/</guid><description>Today VMware has View 4 announced. VMware View 4 is supported on VMware vSphere and has a new protocol named PCoIP (View 3 uses RDP).
Here’s a list of new and/or improved features:
FEATURE&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NEW/IMPROVED&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;DESCRIPTION&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Quad monitor support&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Support 32-bit color with 1920 x 1200 display resolution and up to 4 monitors simultaneously.</description></item><item><title>VMware View released</title><link>/2008/12/02/VMware-view-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 07:46:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/12/02/VMware-view-released/</guid><description>VMware has VMware View released. The solution consist of:
VMware Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VMware Infrastructure 3 + VMware View Manager 3) Storage Optimization with VMware View Composer Application Virtualization with VMware ThinApp Client Virtualization with Offline Desktop – Experimental Use VMware infrastructure 3:
VMware View 3 is built on VMware Infrastructure 3 and as a result, IT organizations can extend the benefits of industry-leading virtualization to the desktop.</description></item></channel></rss>