<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>certificate on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/certificate/</link><description>Recent content in certificate on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/certificate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove expired root certificates from a vCenter Server the easy way</title><link>/2023/04/17/quick-tip-remove-expired-root-certificates-from-a-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 17:44:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/04/17/quick-tip-remove-expired-root-certificates-from-a-vcenter-server/</guid><description>I see a lot of vCenter Servers that have expired root certificates. In the vCenter Server Appliance Administration section under Certificate Management, you can see the expired certificates.
Cleaning up expired root certificates from the vCenter Server can be done by using the &amp;ldquo;vecs-cli&amp;rdquo; command on the vCenter Server Appliance (In the vSphere Client this is not possible).</description></item><item><title>Firefox does not trusts vCenter signed CA certificates</title><link>/2018/02/13/firefox-not-trusts-vcenter-ca-signed-certificates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 20:57:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/02/13/firefox-not-trusts-vcenter-ca-signed-certificates/</guid><description>For a vCenter Server environment I replaced the default SSL certificates with CA signed SSL certificates. The Platform Service Controller (PSC) is configured as VMCA subordinate CA. When opening the vSphere Web/HTML5 Client, Firefox displays the following warning: Your connection is not secure.
This is because Firefox does not trust root certificates in the Windows certificate store.</description></item><item><title>Create a signed certificate for VMware View Connection Servers using a Windows Server 2012 CA</title><link>/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</guid><description>For VMware Horizon View it is recommends that you configure your VMware View Horizon Servers with a signed SSL certificate. Default when you install a VMware View Horizon servers, a certificate is generated that is not signed by a CA. Because it is not signed by a CA It is possible to to intercept traffic.</description></item></channel></rss>