<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows-2008-r2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/windows-2008-r2/</link><description>Recent content in windows-2008-r2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 22:28:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/windows-2008-r2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sysprep goes wrong on Microsoft Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7</title><link>/2011/02/11/microsoft-sysprep-goes-wrong-on-microsoft-windows-2008-r2-and-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 08:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/02/11/microsoft-sysprep-goes-wrong-on-microsoft-windows-2008-r2-and-windows-7/</guid><description>This week I encountered a problem with Sysprepping a Microsoft Windows 2008 R2 VM after cloning. I cloned an existing VM and used a Customization Specification in vSphere vCenter for the Sysprep. When the Sysprepped Microsoft Windows 2008 R2 VM reboots, the following message appears:
Windows could not finish configuring the system. To attempt to resume configuration, restart the computer.
Every time when restarting the VM, the message appears. After some troubleshooting such as disable services and active software before the Sysprep I found Microsoft Knowledgebase article “A Windows 7 or a Windows Server 2008 R2 image deployment process stops when you try to deploy the image on another computer” KB981542 .</description></item><item><title>Huge amount of VMware updates</title><link>/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/11/20/huge-amount-of-vmware-updates/</guid><description>Today when i woke up there where a lot of VMware updates available (to much to handle for one day 🙂 ). I did an upgrade of my lab environment, it went smooth with any issues. VMware did a great job with the new improvements! Here’s a list of improvements with some screenshots:
VMware ESX 4 Update 1 improvements: VMware View 4.0 support – This release adds support for VMware View 4.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft TechDays Belgium</title><link>/2009/03/12/microsoft-techdays-belgium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 20:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/03/12/microsoft-techdays-belgium/</guid><description>The last three days i attended Microsoft TechDays in Antwerpen (Belgium). The first day (pre-conference) was dedicated to Windows 2008 R2. The other 2 days I attended sessions such as Windows 7, Powershell V2, SYSVOL replication and Remote Desktop Services (former Terminal Services). Here is an short overview:
Windows 2008 R2 will be released in 64-bit version only. - All new Windows server product can be managed through PowerShell PowerShell 2 is default installed on Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7.</description></item></channel></rss>