<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/workstation/</link><description>Recent content in workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Run VMware Workstation and Microsoft Hyper-V together in Windows 10</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/09/17/run-vmware-workstation-and-microsoft-hyper-v-together-on-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 14:51:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/09/17/run-vmware-workstation-and-microsoft-hyper-v-together-on-windows-10/</guid><description>In 2013 I wrote a blog post that it was not possible to run VMware Workstation when the Hyper-V role was enabled (link ). Since VMware Workstation 15.5 it is possible to run VMware Workstation and the Hyper-V role together.
Requirements:
Windows 10 2004 or newer VMware Workstation 15.5.5 or newer Supported CPU: Intel Sandy Bridge or an AMD Bulldozer or newer I tested this with my Windows 10 laptop with the Hyper-V role enabled, the Windows Subsystem for Linux running, and VMware Workstation 16 Pro.</description></item><item><title>Running Hyper-V and VMware Workstation on Windows 8.x</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 19:40:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</guid><description>For testing I use Hyper-V and VMware Workstation 10 on my laptop. One restriction of VMware Workstation is that it does not support VHDX disk files (yet). VMware Workstation support VHD files, so the VHDX files must be converted to a VHD first. After the conversion VMware Workstation can select the VHD as Hard Disk.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows Server 2012 in VMware Workstation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/04/install-windows-server-2012-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 19:14:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/04/install-windows-server-2012-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>This procedure describes how to install Windows Server 2012 in VMware Workstation. The following versions are used:
VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 e.x.p Build-646643 Windows Server 2012 Release Candidate Datacenter Build 8400 In VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 create a new VM with the following settings:
New Virtual Machine Custom (advanced) Workstation Tech Preview Select “I will install the operating system later” Select “Microsoft Windows” and select as version “Windows 8 x64” Set the Name and Location Minimal 1 processor, 1 core 2048 MB memory Select “Use network address translation (NAT)” Select “LSI Logic SAS” Create a new virtual disk SCSI 60 GB disk size Leave default disk file Finish After the VM is created, edit virtual Machine settings and browse for the Windows Server 2012 ISO in the the CD/DVD option Remove the VM from VMware Workstation by clicking on the X icon Edit the VMX file (i use Notepad++) and add the following line to the end to of the VMX file: vmGenCounter.</description></item><item><title>Enable Windows Server 8 Hyper-V in VMware Workstation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 21:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 is available as download. The Technology Preview makes it possible for example to install and operate Windows 8 and Windows Server 8 in a VM and the possibility to nest VMs.
I tested the installation of Windows Server 8 in VMware Workstation TP, enabled the Hyper-V role and run a Windows 7 64-bit VM in Hyper-V.</description></item></channel></rss>