<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-tools on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/vmware-tools/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-tools on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/vmware-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Identify VMs that have VMware Tools with the OpenSSL v3 vulnerability</title><link>/2022/11/01/identify-vms-that-have-vmware-tools-with-the-openssl-v3-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 19:05:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/11/01/identify-vms-that-have-vmware-tools-with-the-openssl-v3-vulnerability/</guid><description>In OpenSSL version 3.0.0 to 3.0.6, a critical vulnerability is found (link ). A lot of vendors use these versions of OpenSSL in their products. VMware has the following statement:
To date, no VMware products have been found to be critically impacted by CVE-2022-3602 or CVE-2022-3786. Regardless, VMware products that consume OpenSSL 3.0.x will consume 3.0.7 fixes as a precautionary measure in upcoming releases.
VMware Tools version 12.0.0 and 12.1.0 both contain the OpenSSL 3.</description></item><item><title>An unattended installation of VMware Tools 12 generates a 2711 error</title><link>/2022/04/14/vmware-tools-error-2711/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 11:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/04/14/vmware-tools-error-2711/</guid><description>For a new Windows 10 image build, I used the latest supported VMware Tools In this case that was VMware Tools 12.0.0. VMware Tools is deployed using an unattended installation such as:
e:\setup64.exe /S /v &amp;#34;/qb REBOOT=R ADDLOCAL=All REMOVE=AppDefense,Hgfs,CBHelper,VmwTimeProvider,VSS,NetworkIntrospection,FileIntrospection&amp;#34; /l c:\windows\temp\vmware_tools_install.log During the installation of VMware Tools, the following error occurred: &amp;ldquo;The installer has encountered an unexpected error installing this package. This may indicate a problem with this package. The error code is 2711.</description></item><item><title>VMware Tools installation and upgrade tips and tricks</title><link>/2019/09/09/vmware-tools-installation-and-upgrade-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 08:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/09/09/vmware-tools-installation-and-upgrade-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>The VMware Tools package provides drivers (such as VMXNET3, PVSCSI, SVGA etc.) and services that enhance the performance of virtual machines and make several vSphere features easy to use. Here are some tips and tricks when working with VMware Tools:
An overview of the VMware Tools versions mapping can be found here, link The latest VMware Tools versions can be downloaded from the following links: link and link Within VMware ESXi, the VMware Tools are located under: /vmimages/tools-isoimages The latest VMware Tools version 10.</description></item><item><title>VMware Tools 10.3.0 recalled, check you're vSphere environment!</title><link>/2018/09/07/vmware-tools-10-3-0-recalled-check-youre-vsphere-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 09:06:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/09/07/vmware-tools-10-3-0-recalled-check-youre-vsphere-environment/</guid><description>Yesterday VMware released a Knowledge Base article that VMware Tools version 10.3.0 is recalled because issues with the VMXNET3 network driver for Windows on ESXi 6.5. The issues can cause a Purple Diagnostic Screen (PSOD) or guest network connectivity loss. Because of these issues, VMware Tools 10.3.0 is recalled and no longer available.
Update: September 12, 2018: VMware Tools 10.3.2. is released that fixes the VMXNET3 issue. More information can be found here, link .</description></item></channel></rss>