<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vcsa on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/vcsa/</link><description>Recent content in vcsa on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vcsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The new way to patch the vCenter Server Appliance 6</title><link>/2015/07/30/the-new-way-to-patch-the-vcenter-server-appliance-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 09:26:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/07/30/the-new-way-to-patch-the-vcenter-server-appliance-6/</guid><description>The patching process in vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA) version 6 is changed from previous versions. It is not possible anymore to use the Virtual Appliance Management Interface (VAMI) and update the appliance using the User Interface. The new way to patch the vCenter Server Appliance involves the following steps:
Download the patch from the VMware Patch Download Center, link . Choose vc and select version 6.x Download the latest patch ISO Attach the *.</description></item><item><title>What's new in the vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA) 6.0</title><link>/2015/02/02/whats-new-vsphere-6-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:11:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/02/02/whats-new-vsphere-6-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</guid><description>What’s new in the vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA) 6.0:
ISO with an easy guided Installer Different deployment options possible during the guided installer such as: Install vCenter Server Install Platform Services Controller Install vCenter Server with an Embedded Platform Controller (default) Scripted install. Values can be specified in a template file Embedded vPostgres database. As external database Oracle is supported. IPv6 Support Enhanced Linked mode support VMware Data Protection (VDP) support for backup and recovery Based on a hardened Suse Linux Enterprise 11 SP3 (64-bit) The minimum (Up to 20 hosts and 400 VMs) appliance requirements for the VCSA are: 2 vCPU 8 GB memory ~ 100 GB diskspace Is has the same feature parity as vCenter Windows: What are we missing:</description></item><item><title>Unable to connect from the vSphere Client or PowerCLI on Windows XP or Windows 2003 to a vCenter Server 5.5</title><link>/2013/11/15/unable-to-connect-from-the-vsphere-client-or-powercli-on-windows-xp-or-windows-2003-to-a-vcenter-server-5-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 07:54:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/11/15/unable-to-connect-from-the-vsphere-client-or-powercli-on-windows-xp-or-windows-2003-to-a-vcenter-server-5-5/</guid><description>In my lab environment I still have a Windows XP with the vSphere Client 5.5 installed. When I try to connect with the vSphere Client or vSphere PowerCLI it faisl to connect to the vCenter Server 5.5 or vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5. The following errors appears (The OS has a Dutch language installed):
PowerCLI error:
In the release notes of vSphere 5.5 this is a known issue:
vSphere 5.5 uses the Open SSL library, which, for security, is configured by default to accept only connections that use strong cipher suites.</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5 deployment tips and tricks</title><link>/2013/10/09/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-deployment-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 12:02:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/10/09/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-deployment-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Here are some deployment tips and tricks for the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA):
The VMware vCenter Server Appliance is a preconfigured Linux-based virtual machine. The VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) is available as OVF/ OVA It based on Suse Linux Enterprise 11 64-bit Linked Mode, Microsoft SQL or DB2 is not supported As database you can use the embedded vPostgres or external Oracle database The minimal configuration is: 2 vCPUs, 8 GB memory, a 25 GB thin provisioned and 100 GB thick disk.</description></item><item><title>Is the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5 a replacement for the Windows vCenter Server?</title><link>/2013/09/02/is-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-a-replacement-for-the-windows-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 08:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/02/is-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-a-replacement-for-the-windows-vcenter-server/</guid><description>Back in 2012 I wrote a blog post “What about the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) version 5.1 ”. One of the limitations with VCSA 5.1 was that the embedded vPostgres database only supports 5 hosts and 50 VMs. So it was only supported in test and very small environments.
Now with vSphere 5.5 the the embedded vPostgres database of the vCenter Server Appliance supports 500 hosts and 5000 VMs. This is a great improvement!</description></item><item><title>Allocate a static IP address to the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA)</title><link>/2013/01/14/allocate-a-static-ip-address-to-the-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 21:15:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/01/14/allocate-a-static-ip-address-to-the-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</guid><description>When deploying the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) it will default look for a DHCP address. When there is no DHCP server available the following error is displayed:
O NETWORKING DETECTED.
it is possible to manually configure a static IP address by using the command line. Here are the steps:
Open a console session of the VCSA Login as: root Default password is: VMware Execute the following command: /opt/vmware/share/vami/vami_config_net
After executing the command, a menu is displayed.</description></item><item><title>What about the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) version 5.1?</title><link>/2012/10/22/what-about-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-version-5-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 08:20:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/10/22/what-about-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-version-5-1/</guid><description>I get a lot of questions from customers if the could use the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) in there production environments as replacement for the standard vCenter Server. With the standard vCenter Server is based on Microsoft Windows. you know for sure that all the other vSphere products are supported and integrate. But what about vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.1?
The vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.1 is a 64-bit SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 OVF appliance.</description></item></channel></rss>