<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 08:30:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Download the latest Hashicorp Terraform, Packer, and Vault bits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/09/22/download-the-latest-hashicorp-terraform-packer-and-vault-bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 07:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/09/22/download-the-latest-hashicorp-terraform-packer-and-vault-bits/</guid>
      <description>I created a PowerShell Script that downloads the latest version of Terraform, Packer, and Vault, extracts the archives to binaries, and adds the folder of the path environment variable. Running this script ensures you always work with the latest versions of Terraform, Packer, and Vault.&#xA;&amp;lt;# .DESCRIPTION Function to download and extract the latest Packer, Terraform and Vault version from Hashicorp .NOTES Author: Ivo Beerens .NOTES Site: www.ivobeerens.nl .NOTES Version: 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>Some people ask if it is possible to create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer. The answer is YES. The Packer plugin that makes this possible is called “Hyperv”. Version 1.1.1 supports TPM. Enabling TPM in the Hyper-V VM makes it possible to install Windows 11 without any registry hacks.&#xA;So I decided to test Packer with Hyper-V and Windows 11 and create a blog post about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerCLI help install, update and troubleshooting tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/07/16/powercli-installation-updating-and-troubleshooting-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 11:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/07/16/powercli-installation-updating-and-troubleshooting-tips/</guid>
      <description>PowerCLI is a must-have tool for every VMware Administrator when you want to automate something in your VMware environment. In this blog, I highlight the installation, updating, and some troubleshooting tips for deploying and running PowerCLI on Windows OSes.&#xA;PowerCLI installation Uninstall PowerCLI 6.x and earlier from the Add/remove programs or Programs and Features if exist. Make sure you have an internet connection. Check if Windows Management Framework 5.1 is installed for Windows 7,8 and Windows Server 2012 R2 and earlier OSes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
