<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/horizon/</link><description>Recent content in horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/horizon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) 3.4 RADIUS license change</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/02/13/vmware-unified-access-gateway-uag-3-4-radius-license-change/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 07:25:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/02/13/vmware-unified-access-gateway-uag-3-4-radius-license-change/</guid><description>The VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) acts as reverse proxy and tunnels sessions (PCoIP and Blast) to desktops and remote apps. Besides Horizon support, new features are added for AirWatch and Identity Manager. With version 3.4, the VMware Unified Access Gateway is offered in three editions based on the Horizon or Workspace ONE licenses:
Standard Advanced Enterprise Per edition the following features are supported:
One of the new features is high availability support for the Unified Access Gateway.</description></item><item><title>Horizon Access Point / Unified Access Gateway (UAG) implementation tips</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2017/05/16/horizon-access-point-unified-access-gateway-uag-implementation-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 06:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2017/05/16/horizon-access-point-unified-access-gateway-uag-implementation-tips/</guid><description>In 2013 I created a blog post with some tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server (link ). Now the Unified Access Gateway (UAG) is replacing the VMware Security Server. So it’s time for a new blog post with some implementation tips about VMware Access Point / Unified Access Gateway (UAG). Here’s an overview of the tips:
The Unified Access Gateway (UAG) provides secure access to the following environments: VMware Horizon desktops and applications VMware Identity Manager VMware AirWatch or VMware Workspace ONE per-app tunnels and tunnel proxy VMware Content Gateway service to allow VMware Content Locker access to internal file shares and Microsoft SharePoint In version 2.</description></item><item><title>Drive mapping not working with User Environment Manager (UEM)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/12/21/drive-mapping-not-working-user-environment-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 14:25:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/12/21/drive-mapping-not-working-user-environment-manager/</guid><description>During a Horizon View implementation with User Environment Manager (UEM) 9.1 the drive mappings don’t show up for some with a Windows 10 VDI. The flexEngine log shows the drive mapping was successfully.
2016-12-16 15:18:45.084 [INFO ] Successfully mapped drive ‘G:’ to ‘\filesrv-01\apps$’ (‘Applicaties.xml’)
When opening an elevated command prompt and type the command net use the drive mappings where displayed and accessible. The users that didn&amp;rsquo;t get the drive mappings where local administrator in the Windows 10 VDI desktop.</description></item><item><title>What to know about Horizon Instant Clones</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/04/21/instant-clone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 07:12:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/04/21/instant-clone/</guid><description>Horizon 7 introduced the Instant Clone feature leverages the vmFork technology introduced in vSphere 6.0 U1. With Instant Clone technology it is possible to clone and deploy a VDI desktop VMs in seconds. This is called the Just-In-Time Desktop.
Below is an overview how an Instant Clone VM is created:
Master Image. The Master Image or Golden Image is a Windows 7 or 10 optimized image that contains installed software such as the Horizon Agent for example.</description></item><item><title>Horizon View Administrator displays a blank error window</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/03/29/horizon-7-blank-admin-screen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 06:29:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/03/29/horizon-7-blank-admin-screen/</guid><description>After upgrading to VMware Horizon View 7, the administrator webpage displays a blank error window when trying to connect using the IP address of the Connection Server.
Horizon View 7 adds new security features that checks for the original URL for the web request. If not, it rejects the request and display the blank error window.
Steps to resolve this:
Use https://FQDN/admin or
On every Connection Server create a locked.properties text file in c:\Program Files\VMware\VMware View\Server\sslgateway\conf Add the following line: checkOrigin=false Save the file Restart the &amp;ldquo;VMware Horizon View Connection Server&amp;rdquo; service After the modification you&amp;rsquo;re able to connect to the View Administrator URL using the IP address of the Connection Server.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Agent installation order</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/11/11/vmware-horizon-view-agent-installation-order/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 08:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/11/11/vmware-horizon-view-agent-installation-order/</guid><description>When configuring a Windows VDI desktop or RDSH session with Horizon, different software components must be installed such as the VMware Tools and the VMware Horizon View Agent. When using User Environment Manager and App Volumes they require an agent too. All these software components must be installed in the correct order in the master/golden image to prevent problems such as for example a black screen when connecting to a Windows VDI desktop using the PCoIP protocol.</description></item><item><title>What&amp;rsquo;s new in VMware Horizon 6</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 13:33:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/09/vmware-horizon-6-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware Horizon 6 has been today announced. VMware Horizon 6 has five major enhancements:
Cloud Pod Architecture. Remote Desktop Session Host (RDS) Hosted Apps Virtual SAN Application Catalog vCops for View 6 Here is an overview picture of the Horizon 6 architecture:
Cloud Pod Architecture In version 5 Horizon View supports 10.000 desktops in a Pod. If you need to to have more or than 10.000 desktops or needed to span a datacenter another Pod was needed.</description></item><item><title>Install a wildcard certificate on a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 20:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>On a View Security Server I needed to change the default self signed certificate to a signed wildcard certificate. The customer had a wildcard certificate that didn’t include the private key. A certificate that include the private key is a requirement for a VMware View Security server.
If you have the certificate (*.cer or .crt) and private key (.key), convert it to a PCKS#12 (PFX) format before you import the certificate.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Network Port Diagram</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 09:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/11/07/vmware-horizon-view-network-port-diagram/</guid><description>VMware has released a Network Port Diagram diagram for VMware Horizon View 5.2.
This diagram covers an entire VMware View environment with protocols and port numbers used. In earlier blog posts I already create two small diagrams with protocols and port numbers used by VMware View:
VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol). Link The diagram created by VMware can be handy when implementing and troubleshooting VMware Horizon View.</description></item><item><title>Perform ESXi host maintenance on a VMware Horizon View floating desktop pool</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 13:02:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</guid><description>When you need to perform maintenance (planned downtime) on an ESXi host which is part of a floating pool the following steps can be be taken:
These steps are only required when using local storage for the linked clones!
In the VMware Horizon View Administrator, edit the pool and uncheck the datastore for the host on which maintenance is required. By unchecking the datastore no new desktops are provisioned to this host In the pool settings modify the “Delete or refresh desktop on logoff” to “Delete Immediately” Optionally: In the pool settings modify the “Automatically or logoff after disconnect” to 240 minutes or less so that disconnected sessions are removed.</description></item><item><title>Display the maximum concurrent connected users in VMware Horizon View with PowerCLI</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 09:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</guid><description>VMware Horizon View generates everyday at 5 minutes for midnight an event how many concurrent users connected to View that day. This information can be useful for example when when investing trends.
When the Event database in the VMware Horizon View Administrator is configured, this information can be found using the VMware Horizon View Administrator, Monitoring, select Events and filter for “over the past”
With PowerCLI the daily maximum concurrent connected users can be displayed by using the following command from the VMware View Connection server using View PowerCLI:</description></item><item><title>Create a signed certificate for VMware View Connection Servers using a Windows Server 2012 CA</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/19/create-a-signed-certificate-for-vmware-view-connection-servers-using-a-windows-server-2012-ca/</guid><description>For VMware Horizon View it is recommends that you configure your VMware View Horizon Servers with a signed SSL certificate. Default when you install a VMware View Horizon servers, a certificate is generated that is not signed by a CA. Because it is not signed by a CA It is possible to to intercept traffic. So it is highly recommend to replace the default certificate with a signed certificate after the installation.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View and HTML access (Blast protocol)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/20/vmware-horizon-view-and-html-access-blast-protocol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:06:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/20/vmware-horizon-view-and-html-access-blast-protocol/</guid><description>With the release of the VMware Horizon View Feature Pack 1 for VMware Horizon View 5.2 it possible to connect with HTML5 to your View desktop. This without installing additional software. The new HTML5 protocol is called Blast. Connecting by using the Blast HTML protocol can be handy when you are on a device that does not have the VMware View client installed.
The VMware Horizon View Feature Pack 1 contains the following two main components:</description></item><item><title>Tips for implementing a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 09:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/05/tips-for-implementing-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid><description>A security server is a special instance of View Connection Server that runs a subset of View Connection Server functions. You can use a security server to provide an additional layer of security between the internet and your internal network. A security server resides within a DMZ and acts as a proxy host for connections inside your trusted network.
Setting up a VMware Horizon View Security server can be a challenging task because you have to deal with firewalls and some ports that’s need to be opened between the servers.</description></item><item><title>Display the protocol used on the VMware View desktop background</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:49:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/02/21/display-the-protocol-used-on-the-vmware-view-desktop-background/</guid><description>Systinternals has a tool called “BgInfo”. With this tool it is possible to display content on a Windows desktop background. For example environment variable Information such as “computer name” and the “IP address” can be displayed. This can be very handy when testing or for people that do they support for the Windows environment.
VMware View 5.1 has the following environment variables available in a desktop session :
ViewClient_Broker_DNS_Name ViewClient_Broker_DomainName ViewClient_Broker_Remote_IP_Address ViewClient_Broker_Tunneled ViewClient_Broker_Tunnel_URL ViewClient_Broker_URL ViewClient_Broker_UserName ViewClient_IP_Address ViewClient_LoggedOn_Domainname ViewClient_LoggedOn_Username ViewClient_Machine_Name ViewClient_MAC_Address ViewClient_Protocol ViewClient_Type ViewClient_Windows_Timezone The View environment variables can be added to BgInfo using the custom field option.</description></item></channel></rss>