<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>euc on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/euc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in euc on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/euc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The mobile SDDC and EUC lab environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/06/23/sddc-mobile-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 09:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/06/23/sddc-mobile-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>With my company I work for (Ictivity ), we decided to develop a mobile Software Defined Data Center (SDDC) and End User Computing (EUC) lab environment. This mobile lab environment will be used to demo the VMware SDDC and End User Computing (EUC) stack with integration of third party solutions. One of the reasons to use a physical lab environment instead of cloud services was flexibility and having no dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Horizon Q2 2015 announcements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/04/29/vmware-horizon-q2-2015-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 19:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/04/29/vmware-horizon-q2-2015-announcements/</guid>
      <description>VMware announced last week what’s new with Horizon 6 (Q2 2015) as well as some brand new offerings that will help you to deliver and manage apps and end users across physical, virtual and cloud-hosted environments. Here are the announcements:&#xA;User Experience improvements Linux Desktops support (GA in Q2) User Environment Manager (UEM) (GA in Q2) VMware Workspace Environment Management (WEM) Free SysTrack Desktop Assessment tool User Experience Improvements&#xA;Some new improvements for the upcomming Horizon 6 version are:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
