<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scvmm on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/scvmm/</link><description>Recent content in scvmm on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/scvmm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tips for installing System Center Virtual Machine Manager 2012 R2 Update Rollup (UR5)</title><link>/2015/02/17/tips-installing-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-2012-r2-update-rollup-ur5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 18:53:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/02/17/tips-installing-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-2012-r2-update-rollup-ur5/</guid><description>Here are some tips for installing System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager Update Rollup (UR5):
UR5 is available from Microsoft Update or by manual download. If you are not installing UR5 through Microsoft Update (e.g. you’re downloading the update and then installing it), you must install using elevated privileges. If you do not do this the update may fail silently. During the UR5 installion the System Center Virtual Machine Manager &amp;amp; Agent will be stopped After the SCVMM UR5 server component, reboot the VMM server before installing the UR5 console Before Update Rollup 5, you had to manually update the System Center Virtual Machine Manager DHCP Server (x64) component.</description></item><item><title>Installing Update Rollup (UR) 3 for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager</title><link>/2014/08/01/installing-update-rollup-3-system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 12:53:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/08/01/installing-update-rollup-3-system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-manager/</guid><description>Update rollup (UR) 3 for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released this week. This update includes a Linux guest agent upgrade to support the following new operating systems:
Ubuntu Linux 14.04 (32-bit) Ubuntu Linux 14.04 (64-bit) This update also includes the following:
Host DHCP extension driver upgrade Several performance improvements?????? Several Management Pack package improvements And a huge list of issues that are fixed. More information can be found in the Microsoft KB article found here, link .</description></item><item><title>Remove an orphaned VM from SCVMM</title><link>/2014/07/08/remove-an-orphaned-vm-from-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 06:40:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/07/08/remove-an-orphaned-vm-from-scvmm/</guid><description>During a migration of a VM from a different cluster the job failed in SCVMM.
The status of the VM in SCVMM Virtual Machine State is still “Starting”.
In SCVMM I was unable to stop, repair or delete the VM. When looking on the Hyper-V host, the VM didn’t exist in Failover Cluster Manager or Hyper-V manager. After some troubleshooting I was able to use the following PowerShell command to remove the orphaned VM in SCVMM:</description></item><item><title>Unable to perform a Compliance Scan in SCVMM</title><link>/2014/06/19/unable-to-perform-a-compliance-scan-in-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 06:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/06/19/unable-to-perform-a-compliance-scan-in-scvmm/</guid><description>In System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) an Update (WSUS) Server is added, so VMM can be used to update the hosts with Windows patches.When trying to scan a cluster of hosts for compliance the following error occurred:
Error (24035)
Compliance scan failed with error: 80244017.
Recommended Action:
Ensure the WINHTTP proxy settings are correctly configured for the communications with WSUS. If WSUS is configured to use SSL ensure the WSUS certificate is installed in the trusted Root CA for the machine and then try the operation again.</description></item><item><title>SCVMM library is unable to refesh a file because it is in use</title><link>/2014/06/09/scvmm-library-is-unable-to-refesh-a-file-because-it-is-in-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 14:53:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/06/09/scvmm-library-is-unable-to-refesh-a-file-because-it-is-in-use/</guid><description>In the jobs window in the System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) console , the following warning appeared:
Warning (10803)Unable to refresh \\server\share\ISO\Windows2012 R2\SW_DVD5_Windows_Svr_Std_and_DataCtr_2012_R2_64Bit_English_Core_MLF_X19-05182.ISO because the file is in use by another process.Recommended ActionWait for the next automatic library refresh, or manually refresh the library share after the process completes. The warning means that the ISO file is in use by one or more VMs. To find the VMs that are using the ISO file I created the following PowerShell script:</description></item><item><title>Tips for deploying SCVMM 2012 R2 Rollup 2</title><link>/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 06:56:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</guid><description>Last week Update Rollup 2 (UR2) for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released. UR2 contains important fixes for SCVMM2012 R2. Here are some deployment tips for UR2:
Wait a least couple of weeks before deploying Update Rollups in your production environment. It happens that new Update Rollups contains huge bugs and are pulled back! Make sure you have a backup of the SCVMM database before installing UR2 Install the UR2 by download the VMM management server and VMM admin console packages link (or use Windows Update /WSUS to install both packages).</description></item><item><title>Hyper-V Get Snapshot checkpoint file sizes on Cluster Shared Volumes with PowerShell</title><link>/2013/09/17/list-hyper-v-snapshot-file-sizes-on-cluster-shared-volumes-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 13:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/17/list-hyper-v-snapshot-file-sizes-on-cluster-shared-volumes-with-powershell/</guid><description>During a Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V Health Check I needed to know the snapshot file sizes for the all the snapshots on the Clustered Shared Volumes (CSVs). The Get-VMCheckpoint Cmdlet does not report the snapshot size. So I create a PowerShell one-liner that displays the following information:
Location of the snapshot file Date and time that the snapshot file was created Last write access time of the snapshot file File size in MBs The PowerShell one-liner is executed from a Hyper-V 2012 host that has access to all the Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs).</description></item><item><title>Health Check your System Center Virtual Machine Server (SCVMM) 2012 environent with PowerShell</title><link>/2013/01/28/health-check-your-system-center-virtual-machine-server-scvmm-2012-environent-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 10:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/01/28/health-check-your-system-center-virtual-machine-server-scvmm-2012-environent-with-powershell/</guid><description>Last week I created a simple example of a HealtCheck PowerShell script that connects to Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager and displays information about the Hyper-V hosts and VMs managed by this server.
I run the PowerShell script from another Windows Server 2012 host. To make this work make sure the Hyper-V manager and the VMM Console is installed on the server. The VMM console can be installed from the Microsoft System Center 2012 Virtual Machine Manager ISO.</description></item></channel></rss>