<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>powercli on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/powercli/</link><description>Recent content in powercli on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/powercli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PowerCLI cannot be installed or updated because the authenticode signature of the file error</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/03/07/powercli-cannot-be-installed-or-updated-because-the-authenticode-signature-of-the-file-error/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 17:38:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/03/07/powercli-cannot-be-installed-or-updated-because-the-authenticode-signature-of-the-file-error/</guid><description>On a new Windows Server 2022 VM I tried to install a fresh copy of VMware.PowerCLI (13.0.0) with the following PowerShell command:
Install-Module VMware.PowerCLI -Scope CurrentUser The following error occurred:
PackageManagement\Install-Package : The module &amp;lsquo;VMware.VimAutomation.License&amp;rsquo; cannot be installed or updated because the authenticode signature of the file &amp;lsquo;VMware.VimAutomation.License.cat&amp;rsquo; is not valid.</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI help install, update and troubleshooting tips</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/07/16/powercli-installation-updating-and-troubleshooting-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 11:54:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2019/07/16/powercli-installation-updating-and-troubleshooting-tips/</guid><description>PowerCLI is a must-have tool for every VMware Administrator when you want to automate something in your VMware environment. In this blog, I highlight the installation, updating, and some troubleshooting tips for deploying and running PowerCLI on Windows OSes.
PowerCLI installation Uninstall PowerCLI 6.x and earlier from the Add/remove programs or Programs and Features if exist.</description></item><item><title>VIBSearch Finding VIB versions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/12/17/vibsearch-finding-vib-versions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 09:28:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/12/17/vibsearch-finding-vib-versions/</guid><description>VIBSearch is a simple PowerShell script with a GUI that will search for a specified VIB or all the VIBS installed on the ESXi hosts. A VIB stands for vSphere Installation Bundle (VIB). VIBs are used to package and distribute ESXi software such as drivers. The GUI is designed with SAPIEN PowerShell Studio 2014.</description></item><item><title>Display VMware Horizon View Pool information using PowerCLI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 21:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/01/22/display-vmware-horizon-view-pool-information-using-powercli/</guid><description>For a VMware View Horizon Healthcheck I needed to display all VMware View Pools created and export some settings for documentation. The easiest way to do this is using View PowerCLI on a VMware View Connection server.
Here are some examples to use:
Display all the pools and settings: get-pool</description></item><item><title>Backup the ESXi configuration</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/08/09/backup-the-esxi-configuration-and-update-the-status-in-vcenter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:24:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/08/09/backup-the-esxi-configuration-and-update-the-status-in-vcenter/</guid><description>I create a simple PowerCLI script that backups all the VMware ESXi host configurations that are connected to a vCenter Server. This script can be scheduled to make for example every week a backup of the ESXi server configs. You can easily customize the script for your own needs.
#Variables $Folder = &amp;#34;D:\Backup\BCK-ESXi&amp;#34; $FolderOld = &amp;#34;D:\Backup\BCK-ESXi\_old&amp;#34; $vc= &amp;#34;vcenterserver-fqdn&amp;#34; # Connect to local vCenter Server Connect-ViServer # Move existing backup files to the old directory Move-Item ($Folder + &amp;#34;\*.</description></item><item><title>Display the maximum concurrent connected users in VMware Horizon View with PowerCLI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 09:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</guid><description>VMware Horizon View generates everyday at 5 minutes for midnight an event how many concurrent users connected to View that day. This information can be useful for example when when investing trends.
When the Event database in the VMware Horizon View Administrator is configured, this information can be found using the VMware Horizon View Administrator, Monitoring, select Events and filter for “over the past”</description></item><item><title>Enable and disable Remote Tech Support mode (SSH)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/11/11/enable-or-disable-remote-tech-support-mode-ssh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 09:58:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/11/11/enable-or-disable-remote-tech-support-mode-ssh/</guid><description>When you start the Remote Tech Support (TSM) service on a VMware ESXi host a warning and the following message will appear:
Remote Tech Support Mode (SSH) for the host … has been enabled
When the warning appears some Admins get a little nervous. Since VMware ESXi 4.1 Update 2 and VMware ESXi 5 the warning can be suppressed.</description></item><item><title>List VM settings to CSV, HTML, gridview, screen and email</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/06/09/powercli-list-vm-settings-and-export-to-csv-html-gridview-screen-and-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 10:47:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/06/09/powercli-list-vm-settings-and-export-to-csv-html-gridview-screen-and-email/</guid><description>This PowerCLI script will display specified VM settings for all VMs in the vCenter server you specify. If you do an inventory, a health check or need to troubleshoot VMware environment this PowerCLI script can be useful.
The following VM settings will be displayed:
VMName, Hostname, IP address, OS version, Boottime, VMstate, Total vCPUs, CPU afinnity, CPU hot add status, CPU share, CPU limit, Overall CPU usage, CPU reservation, Total memory, Memory share, Memory usage, Memory hot add status, Memory limit, Memory reservation, Memory swap, Memory ballooning, Memory compression, Total NICs, VMware tools status, VMware Tools version, VM hardware version, Timesync status and CBT status.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESX Post installation configuration via PowerCLI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/02/10/vmware-esx-post-installation-configuration-via-powercli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 14:36:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/02/10/vmware-esx-post-installation-configuration-via-powercli/</guid><description>I made a simple example script using the VMware PowerCLI that can be used to do the post installation configuration of a VMware ESX 4 server. This script does the following things:
Connect to VMware ESX server Set the SC memory to 800MB Creates vSwitch2 and add vmnic2 and vmnic3 Add several PortGroups and VLANs to vSwitch2 Remove default PortGroup VM Network Creates a VMkernel VMotion port with IP address, subnetmask and VLAN Add vmnic0 and vmnic1 to vSwitch0, set for the VMotion port vmnic1 active and vmnic0 standby and for the Service Console port vmnic0 active and vmnic1 standby Configure NTP servers and open the firewall Sets advanced settings Disk.</description></item></channel></rss>