<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>horizon-view on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/horizon-view/</link>
    <description>Recent content in horizon-view on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/horizon-view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Define what devices are allowed in a Horizon View desktop with UEM Smart Policies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/08/04/define-devices-allowed-horizon-view-desktop-uem-smart-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2016/08/04/define-devices-allowed-horizon-view-desktop-uem-smart-policies/</guid>
      <description>When designing a new Horizon View environment, one of the design phases is to identify what requirements there are when accessing (redirecting) devices in a Horizon View desktop of published app. In other words what redirection and devices are available and permitted in the VDI desktop or published app such as:&#xA;USB devices Clipboard (copy/paste) redirection Client Drives Redirection (CDR) Printing redirection For the most environments different requirements are needed when accessing devices from inside or outside the company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Horizon View Agent installation order</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/11/11/vmware-horizon-view-agent-installation-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 08:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/11/11/vmware-horizon-view-agent-installation-order/</guid>
      <description>When configuring a Windows VDI desktop or RDSH session with Horizon, different software components must be installed such as the VMware Tools and the VMware Horizon View Agent. When using User Environment Manager and App Volumes they require an agent too. All these software components must be installed in the correct order in the master/golden image to prevent problems such as for example a black screen when connecting to a Windows VDI desktop using the PCoIP protocol.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 with Horizon View Agent generates BSOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/07/16/windows-10-with-horizon-view-agent-generates-bsod/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 13:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/07/16/windows-10-with-horizon-view-agent-generates-bsod/</guid>
      <description>After installing the VMware Horizon View Agent (6.1.1) on a Windows 10 (tested with build 10240), it generates a Blue Screen Of Death (BSOD) when pressing Ctrl+Alt+Del/Ins.&#xA;The error is:&#xA;DRIVER_IRQ_NOT_LESS_OR_EQUAL (kbdclass.sys).&#xA;To fix the problem (The solution was found on the Microsoft Community site, link ):&#xA;RDP to the Windows 10 VM Edit HKLM\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Class\{4D36E96B-E325-11CE-BFC1-08002BE10318}\UpperFilters Put the kbdclass before the vmkbd value Reboot the VM After changing the UpperFilters value I was able to login the Horizon View desktop without BSOD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What VMware Horizon View PowerCLI features you like to see?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/03/18/what-vmware-horizon-view-powercli-features-you-like-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/03/18/what-vmware-horizon-view-powercli-features-you-like-to-see/</guid>
      <description>PowerCLI 6.0 R1 is released with some cool new features. One thing I missed in this announcement is improvements in the PowerCLI support for VMware Horizon View. The latest release of VMware Horizon View 6.1 still has NO PowerCLI improvements! This is a huge bummer because PowerCLI is very limited in VMware Horizon View.&#xA;On the VMware PowerCLI Blog the following statement is written (link ):&#xA;Each new release tends to have several features or enhancements that have been asked for by YOU, our customers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easily fix VMware Horizon View desktop provisioning errors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/02/11/fix-vmware-horizon-view-desktop-provisioning-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 13:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/02/11/fix-vmware-horizon-view-desktop-provisioning-errors/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you are unable to remove linked clones or stale desktop entries from the VMware Horizon View Administrator. In this example we have a missing VM in the VMware Horizon View Administrator.&#xA;When trying to remove the VM from the VMware Horizon View Administrator the following error is generated:&#xA;Failed to remove VM&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; from the View Composer Inventory&#xA;To remove the orphaned missing VM, you need to manually, remove the orphaned records from the ADAM and composer database, AD and vCenter Server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Error occurred during vCenter operation when editing a VMware Horizon View pool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/09/09/error-occurred-vcenter-operation-editing-vmware-horizon-view-pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 10:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/09/09/error-occurred-vcenter-operation-editing-vmware-horizon-view-pool/</guid>
      <description>When editing a VMware Horizon desktop pool in some situations the server error ‘Error occurred during vCenter operation’. appears.&#xA;The error hasn&amp;rsquo;t any useful information that says what is wrong. When this error occurs the vCenter Server is unable to find one or more objects listed in the desktop pool. When changing datacenter, cluster or host settings in vCenter the desktop pool must be updated to. To resolve this error open the desktop pool, select the vCenter settings tab an check or update the Parent VM, Snapshot, Host or cluster, Resource pool and datastores.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware Horizon View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8 white paper update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/07/23/vmware-horizon-view-optimization-guide-windows-7-windows-8-white-paper-update/</guid>
      <description>VMware released an updated version of the “VMware Horizon with View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8” whitepaper. This white paper discuss the necessary information for optimizing a Windows 7 or Windows 8 virtual desktop image for VMware Horizon View using the Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) or use a script-based approach.&#xA;The updated (July 15, 2014) “VMware Horizon with View Optimization Guide for Windows 7 and Windows 8” whitepaper can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install a wildcard certificate on a VMware Horizon View Security Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 20:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/03/20/install-a-wildcard-certificate-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-security-server/</guid>
      <description>On a View Security Server I needed to change the default self signed certificate to a signed wildcard certificate. The customer had a wildcard certificate that didn’t include the private key. A certificate that include the private key is a requirement for a VMware View Security server.&#xA;If you have the certificate (*.cer or .crt) and private key (.key), convert it to a PCKS#12 (PFX) format before you import the certificate.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
