<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>backup on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/backup/</link><description>Recent content in backup on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nakivo Backup and Replication v10 released with support for vSphere 7</title><link>/2020/07/30/nakivo-backup-and-replication-v10-released-with-support-for-vsphere-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 05:20:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/07/30/nakivo-backup-and-replication-v10-released-with-support-for-vsphere-7/</guid><description>Nakivo Backup and Replication released last week version 10. I personally use Nakivo Backup and Replication in my lab environment because it can be installed on my NAS device. This saves me hardware resources of the backup VM (appliance or Windows/Linux) and the deployment is super fast.
In version 10 of Nakivo Backup and Replication the following new improvements are added:</description></item><item><title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication - Multi-Tenancy, licensing and conclusion</title><link>/2018/11/02/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-editions-and-licensing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 10:38:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/11/02/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-editions-and-licensing/</guid><description>In the last part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the Multi-Tenancy option, licensing and the final conclusion.
Multi-Tenancy and branding NAKIVO supports multi-tenancy to deliver Backup-as-a-Service (BAAS) and Disaster-Recovery as a Service (DRaas). The tenants are isolated from each other and cannot access other tenants. Each tenant can access their own environment through a self-service portal and perform all data protection of recovery tasks.</description></item><item><title>Veeam v8 is coming</title><link>/2014/07/14/veeam-v8-coming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 11:38:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/07/14/veeam-v8-coming/</guid><description>The new version of Veeam is called “Veeam Availability Suite v8”.
The Veeam Availability Suite v8 has improvements in the following areas:
High Speed Recovery Data Loss Avoidance Verified Protection Leverage Data Complete Visibility HIGH-SPEED RECOVERY
Enables low recovery time objectives (RTOs) of &amp;lt;15 minutes; enables rapid recovery of the data customers want, in the form that they want it.</description></item><item><title>Backup the ESXi configuration</title><link>/2013/08/09/backup-the-esxi-configuration-and-update-the-status-in-vcenter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:24:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/08/09/backup-the-esxi-configuration-and-update-the-status-in-vcenter/</guid><description>I create a simple PowerCLI script that backups all the VMware ESXi host configurations that are connected to a vCenter Server. This script can be scheduled to make for example every week a backup of the ESXi server configs. You can easily customize the script for your own needs.
#Variables $Folder = &amp;#34;D:\Backup\BCK-ESXi&amp;#34; $FolderOld = &amp;#34;D:\Backup\BCK-ESXi\_old&amp;#34; $vc= &amp;#34;vcenterserver-fqdn&amp;#34; # Connect to local vCenter Server Connect-ViServer # Move existing backup files to the old directory Move-Item ($Folder + &amp;#34;\*.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading the vSphere Data Protection (VDP) appliance</title><link>/2012/12/07/upgrading-the-vsphere-data-protection-vdp-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 10:10:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/12/07/upgrading-the-vsphere-data-protection-vdp-appliance/</guid><description>Here are the steps outlined for upgrading the vSphere Data Protection (VDP) appliance.
1. Check the version of the VDP. SSH to the VDP appliance and use the following command:
rpm –qa | grep vdr
The current version of the VDP appliance is: vdr-1.1.53-53
2. The vSphere (web) client displays version 5.</description></item><item><title>Tested: PHD Virtual Backup 6.0</title><link>/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</guid><description>PHD Virtual Backup is a backup and recovery solution for VMware and Citrix environments. PHD Virtual Backup version 6 is released. We tested this new version with VMware vSpher
What’s new in PHD Virtual Backup version 6: PHD Virtual Backup version 6.0 contains the following major enhancements:
PHD Instant Recovery: Instant Recovery lets you access your backed up data right away.</description></item><item><title>Tested: Altaro Hyper-V Backup</title><link>/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</guid><description>In my LAB environment I tested Altaro Hyper-V Backup version 3. Altaro Hyper-V Backup is software that makes it possible to backup and restore Windows 2008 (R2) Hyper-V VMs.
Editions There are three editions available: The free edition, the standard edition and the unlimited edition. For this test I used the unlimited edition because it supports “Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs)”.</description></item></channel></rss>