<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vCenter on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/vcenter/</link><description>Recent content in vCenter on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/vcenter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Firefox does not trusts vCenter signed CA certificates</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/02/13/firefox-not-trusts-vcenter-ca-signed-certificates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 20:57:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2018/02/13/firefox-not-trusts-vcenter-ca-signed-certificates/</guid><description>For a vCenter Server environment I replaced the default SSL certificates with CA signed SSL certificates. The Platform Service Controller (PSC) is configured as VMCA subordinate CA. When opening the vSphere Web/HTML5 Client, Firefox displays the following warning: Your connection is not secure.
This is because Firefox does not trust root certificates in the Windows certificate store.</description></item><item><title>Deploy an OVA/OVF fails with certificate error</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/10/23/deploy-ovaovf-fails-certificate-error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 20:42:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/10/23/deploy-ovaovf-fails-certificate-error/</guid><description>When trying to deploy an OVA/OVF with the vSphere Web Client the following error is displayed:
The operation failed for an undetermined reason. Typically this problem occurs due to certificates that the browser does not trust. If you are using self-signed or custom certificates, open the URL below in a new browser tab and accept the certificate, then retry the operation.</description></item><item><title>Update the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) without internet</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/03/01/update-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-without-internet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 13:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2017/03/01/update-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-without-internet/</guid><description>In this blog post I highlight how to patch or update a single vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) without having an internet connection. The patch will be stored on a temporarily web server that is installed on a Windows machine. In this example we update the vCenter Server Appliance version from 6.</description></item><item><title>vCenter Server 6 and the vPostgres database</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/03/25/vcenter-server-6-and-the-vpostgres-database/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 13:53:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/03/25/vcenter-server-6-and-the-vpostgres-database/</guid><description>In vCenter Server 5.x the embedded SQL Express database supports a maximum of 5 hosts and 50 Virtual Machines. With vCenter Server 6 the embedded database is changes from SQL Express to a vPostgress database. The vPostgres database supports a maximum of 20 hosts and 200 VMs. In comparison the vPostgres database on the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 6 supports 1000 hosts and 10000.</description></item><item><title>What's new in the vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA) 6.0</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/02/02/whats-new-vsphere-6-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:11:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/02/02/whats-new-vsphere-6-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</guid><description>What’s new in the vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA) 6.0:
ISO with an easy guided Installer Different deployment options possible during the guided installer such as: Install vCenter Server Install Platform Services Controller Install vCenter Server with an Embedded Platform Controller (default) Scripted install. Values can be specified in a template file Embedded vPostgres database.</description></item><item><title>Unable to connect from the vSphere Client or PowerCLI on Windows XP or Windows 2003 to a vCenter Server 5.5</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/11/15/unable-to-connect-from-the-vsphere-client-or-powercli-on-windows-xp-or-windows-2003-to-a-vcenter-server-5-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 07:54:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/11/15/unable-to-connect-from-the-vsphere-client-or-powercli-on-windows-xp-or-windows-2003-to-a-vcenter-server-5-5/</guid><description>In my lab environment I still have a Windows XP with the vSphere Client 5.5 installed. When I try to connect with the vSphere Client or vSphere PowerCLI it faisl to connect to the vCenter Server 5.5 or vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5. The following errors appears (The OS has a Dutch language installed):</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5 deployment tips and tricks</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/09/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-deployment-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 12:02:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/10/09/vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-deployment-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Here are some deployment tips and tricks for the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA):
The VMware vCenter Server Appliance is a preconfigured Linux-based virtual machine. The VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) is available as OVF/ OVA It based on Suse Linux Enterprise 11 64-bit Linked Mode, Microsoft SQL or DB2 is not supported As database you can use the embedded vPostgres or external Oracle database The minimal configuration is: 2 vCPUs, 8 GB memory, a 25 GB thin provisioned and 100 GB thick disk.</description></item><item><title>Is the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 5.5 a replacement for the Windows vCenter Server?</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/09/02/is-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-a-replacement-for-the-windows-vcenter-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 08:42:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/09/02/is-the-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-5-5-a-replacement-for-the-windows-vcenter-server/</guid><description>Back in 2012 I wrote a blog post “What about the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) version 5.1 ”. One of the limitations with VCSA 5.1 was that the embedded vPostgres database only supports 5 hosts and 50 VMs. So it was only supported in test and very small environments.</description></item><item><title>vCenter Single Sign On (SSO) password reset</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/05/30/vcenter-single-sign-on-sso-password-reset/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 09:24:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/05/30/vcenter-single-sign-on-sso-password-reset/</guid><description>During the installation of the Windows vCenter Single Sing On (SSO) service you must provide a password for the SSO admin user named “admin@System-Domain ”.
The password you enter is called the master password. If you change the master password, the password entered during the installation of the SSO service is needed as master password for resetting the “admin@System-Domain ”.</description></item><item><title>Allocate a static IP address to the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/14/allocate-a-static-ip-address-to-the-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 21:15:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/14/allocate-a-static-ip-address-to-the-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa/</guid><description>When deploying the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) it will default look for a DHCP address. When there is no DHCP server available the following error is displayed:
O NETWORKING DETECTED.
it is possible to manually configure a static IP address by using the command line. Here are the steps:</description></item><item><title>What about the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) version 5.1?</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/10/22/what-about-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-version-5-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 08:20:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/10/22/what-about-vmware-vcenter-server-appliance-vcsa-version-5-1/</guid><description>I get a lot of questions from customers if the could use the VMware vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) in there production environments as replacement for the standard vCenter Server. With the standard vCenter Server is based on Microsoft Windows. you know for sure that all the other vSphere products are supported and integrate.</description></item><item><title>Tips for upgrading to VMware vCenter 5.1</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/13/tips-for-upgrading-to-vmware-vcenter-5-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 12:53:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/13/tips-for-upgrading-to-vmware-vcenter-5-1/</guid><description>Before starting the upgrading to version 5.1 of the vCenter Server, the following steps can be taken to be able to successfully upgrade. The first step is reading the upgrade guides. After the RTFM stuff check the following:
Make sure the SQL Server authentication checkbox is set to SQL Server and Windows Authentication mode on the SQL server.</description></item><item><title>vCenter 5.1 Single Sign On error during installation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-error-during-installation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 16:24:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/09/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-error-during-installation/</guid><description>Today vSphere 5.1 is released. I did an upgrade of my existing vSphere 5 vCenter server. During the installation of the vCenter Single Sign On (SSO) software the following warning occurred:
Error 29115: Cannot authenticate to DB.
After this error the installation stops and the rollback begins. To solve this make sure the server authentication checkbox is set to SQL Server and Windows Authentication mode on the SQL server.</description></item><item><title>After upgrading to vCenter Server 5, &amp;ldquo;com.VMware.converter&amp;rdquo; alert</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/23/after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-5-com-vmware-converter-alert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 13:33:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/23/after-upgrading-to-vcenter-server-5-com-vmware-converter-alert/</guid><description>After upgrading to vCenter 5, the vCenter Service Status page displays the following error:
com.VMware.converter alert unable to retrieve health data from https:///converter/health.xml
This error occurs because the integrated vCenter Converter plug-in is no longer available in vSphere 5! To solve this error following the VMware KB article listed below:</description></item><item><title>Unable to join domain when deploy a template using guest customization specification</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/22/unable-to-join-domain-when-deploy-a-template-using-guest-customization-specification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 10:26:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/22/unable-to-join-domain-when-deploy-a-template-using-guest-customization-specification/</guid><description>At a customer I was unable to join a domain when deploying a template from vCenter using a guest customization specification. This only happened with Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7 templates.
To solve this problem, you need the do the following in the guest customization specification:
Enter the FQDN name in Windows Server Domain field (1) Enter the user@domain_FQDN in the username field (2) I used the NetBIOS domain name in the “Windows Server Domain” field and “domain\username” in the username field what doesn’t work with Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7 anymore.</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter 4 and MS SQL Express 2008 R2 bug</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/01/06/vmware-vcenter-4-and-ms-sql-express-2008-r2-bug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 10:02:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/01/06/vmware-vcenter-4-and-ms-sql-express-2008-r2-bug/</guid><description>When looking for performance data in vCenter 4.1 from the past week, month or year, I got the message “Performance data is currently not available for this entry”. Only real time data is visible in vSphere client.
In the vCenter Service Status the warning “Performance statistics rollup from Past Day to Past Week is not occurring in the database” appeared.</description></item><item><title>Add SQL Server Management Studio to Microsoft SQL Server Express 2008 R2</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/08/add-sql-server-management-studio-to-microsoft-sql-server-express-2008-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 12:22:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/08/add-sql-server-management-studio-to-microsoft-sql-server-express-2008-r2/</guid><description>When installing VMware vCenter 5 with the default database engine (Microsoft SQL Server Express 2008 R2) the SQL Management Studio is not installed by default. It can be confusing to add SQL Management studio at a later time. Here are the steps explained:
Download Microsoft SQL Express 2008 R2 or browse the vCenter installation ZIP or ISO.</description></item><item><title>Things to consider when upgrading to vSphere 4.1</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/08/11/things-to-consider-when-upgrading-to-vsphere-4-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 09:10:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/08/11/things-to-consider-when-upgrading-to-vsphere-4-1/</guid><description>The new vSphere 4.1 release offers a lot of new cool features and enhancements. Here’s a list What’s New in vSphere 4.1. When upgrading to vSphere 4.1 there are a couple of things to think about before starting:
Make sure your systems and components are supported, check the Hardware Compatibility Guide .</description></item><item><title>Move the VirtualCenter SQL database or migrate the VirtualCenter SQL database to different server.</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/29/move-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-or-migrate-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-to-different-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 20:39:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2008/11/29/move-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-or-migrate-the-virtualcenter-sql-database-to-different-server/</guid><description>VMware released two new handy KB articles about how to move or migrating the SQL VirtualCenter database to different server.
To move the database
When relocating your SQL database:
To move SQL Server databases to a new location by using Detach and Attach functions in SQL Server, see Microsoft KB article http://support.</description></item></channel></rss>