<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMware-workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vmware-workstation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMware-workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 20:57:31 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/vmware-workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to install Windows 11 on VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 07:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>For testing purposes, I frequently use VMware Workstation to install Operating Systems such as Windows 11. The biggest challenge with Windows 11 is that you need a TPM 2.0 device. When installing Windows 11, if your computer does not meet the hardware requirements, you will see a message stating, “This PC can’t run Windows 11“.&#xA;Windows 11 requires the following minimal hardware specifications:&#xA;CPU: 1 GHz or faster with 2 or more cores on the processor RAM: 4 GB RAM Storage: 64 GB or larger Firmware: UEFI, Secure boot TPM: Trusted Platform Module (TPM) 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a Windows 10 image with Packer using VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/05/31/build-a-windows-10-image-with-packer-using-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/05/31/build-a-windows-10-image-with-packer-using-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>Most of the time I use Packer against a VMware vSphere and Microsoft Azure environment. But sometimes it’s useful to use VMware Workstation for local testing purposes. For building Windows 10 images with Packer and using VMware Workstation there is not much information available. In this blog post, I show how to build a Windows 10 image with Packer and VMware Workstation.&#xA;With Packer, the VMware-iso builder is used for creating images with VMware Workstation or VMware Fusion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Windows Server 2012 in VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/06/04/install-windows-server-2012-in-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 19:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/06/04/install-windows-server-2012-in-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>This procedure describes how to install Windows Server 2012 in VMware Workstation. The following versions are used:&#xA;VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 e.x.p Build-646643 Windows Server 2012 Release Candidate Datacenter Build 8400 In VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 create a new VM with the following settings:&#xA;New Virtual Machine Custom (advanced) Workstation Tech Preview Select “I will install the operating system later” Select “Microsoft Windows” and select as version “Windows 8 x64” Set the Name and Location Minimal 1 processor, 1 core 2048 MB memory Select “Use network address translation (NAT)” Select “LSI Logic SAS” Create a new virtual disk SCSI 60 GB disk size Leave default disk file Finish After the VM is created, edit virtual Machine settings and browse for the Windows Server 2012 ISO in the the CD/DVD option Remove the VM from VMware Workstation by clicking on the X icon Edit the VMX file (i use Notepad++) and add the following line to the end to of the VMX file: vmGenCounter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boot from USB in VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/10/16/boot-from-usb-in-vmware-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 08:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/10/16/boot-from-usb-in-vmware-workstation/</guid>
      <description>I ‘am testing an unattended installation of VMware ESXi from an USB drive. After every change, I needed to test if the unattended still worked. I tried to use VMware workstation to test the unattended installation. VMware Workstation doesn’t support boot from USB. There is an unofficial solution to fix this problem by using the PLOP boot manager (Download link ). The PLOP Boot Manager is a small program to boot different operating systems.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
