<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hyper-v on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/hyper-v/</link><description>Recent content in hyper-v on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/hyper-v/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</guid><description>Some people ask if it is possible to create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer. The answer is YES. The Packer plugin that makes this possible is called “Hyperv”. Version 1.1.1 supports TPM. Enabling TPM in the Hyper-V VM makes it possible to install Windows 11 without any registry hacks.
So I decided to test Packer with Hyper-V and Windows 11 and create a blog post about it.</description></item><item><title>Manage Hyper-V in a workgroup remotely</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/08/28/manage-hyper-v-in-a-workgroup-remotely/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 07:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/08/28/manage-hyper-v-in-a-workgroup-remotely/</guid><description>Managing Hyper-V remotely in a workgroup can be challenging to configure. This is still the case for Windows Server 2016. For a testing environment I needed to remotely manage Windows Server 2016 core server with the Hyper-V role enabled from Windows 10 with the Hyper-V manager. I used the following manual configuration:
Client with Hyper-V Manager (Windows 10). This client is called win10-01 Server with Windows Server 2016 core version with the Hyper-V role enabled.</description></item><item><title>Test Windows Server 2016 Hyper-V with VMware Workstation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/08/25/easy-way-to-test-windows-server-2016-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/08/25/easy-way-to-test-windows-server-2016-hyper-v/</guid><description>Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 3 (TP3) is released with some cool new features. An easy way to test Windows Server 2016 TP3 is to use VMware Workstation. Windows Server 2016 can be installed with the Hyper-V role and have some VMs nested with minimal configuration.
For this test i used the following hard-and software:
Hardware: Dell Latitude E6540 with an Intel i5-4310M CPU and 16 GB memory.
Software: As desktop OS Windows 8.</description></item><item><title>Tips for installing System Center Virtual Machine Manager 2012 R2 Update Rollup (UR5)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/02/17/tips-installing-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-2012-r2-update-rollup-ur5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 18:53:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/02/17/tips-installing-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-2012-r2-update-rollup-ur5/</guid><description>Here are some tips for installing System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager Update Rollup (UR5):
UR5 is available from Microsoft Update or by manual download. If you are not installing UR5 through Microsoft Update (e.g. you’re downloading the update and then installing it), you must install using elevated privileges. If you do not do this the update may fail silently. During the UR5 installion the System Center Virtual Machine Manager &amp;amp; Agent will be stopped After the SCVMM UR5 server component, reboot the VMM server before installing the UR5 console Before Update Rollup 5, you had to manually update the System Center Virtual Machine Manager DHCP Server (x64) component.</description></item><item><title>SCVMM 2012 R2 agent update error</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/01/14/scvmm-2012-r2-agent-update-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 22:28:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/01/14/scvmm-2012-r2-agent-update-error/</guid><description>After updating System Center Virtual Machine Manager to Update Rollup 4 (UR4), one of the post installation tasks is updating the VMM agents on the Hyper-V hosts. Updating the VMM agent can be performed from the VMM console or using PowerShell. On one of the Hyper-V hosts I got the following error when trying to update the VMM agent from the console:
Error (10429) An older version of the Virtual Machine Manager server is installed on .</description></item><item><title>Installing Update Rollup (UR) 3 for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/08/01/installing-update-rollup-3-system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 12:53:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/08/01/installing-update-rollup-3-system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-manager/</guid><description>Update rollup (UR) 3 for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released this week. This update includes a Linux guest agent upgrade to support the following new operating systems:
Ubuntu Linux 14.04 (32-bit) Ubuntu Linux 14.04 (64-bit) This update also includes the following:
Host DHCP extension driver upgrade Several performance improvements?????? Several Management Pack package improvements And a huge list of issues that are fixed. More information can be found in the Microsoft KB article found here, link .</description></item><item><title>Remove an orphaned VM from SCVMM</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/07/08/remove-an-orphaned-vm-from-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 06:40:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/07/08/remove-an-orphaned-vm-from-scvmm/</guid><description>During a migration of a VM from a different cluster the job failed in SCVMM.
The status of the VM in SCVMM Virtual Machine State is still “Starting”.
In SCVMM I was unable to stop, repair or delete the VM. When looking on the Hyper-V host, the VM didn’t exist in Failover Cluster Manager or Hyper-V manager. After some troubleshooting I was able to use the following PowerShell command to remove the orphaned VM in SCVMM:</description></item><item><title>Unable to perform a Compliance Scan in SCVMM</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/06/19/unable-to-perform-a-compliance-scan-in-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 06:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/06/19/unable-to-perform-a-compliance-scan-in-scvmm/</guid><description>In System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) an Update (WSUS) Server is added, so VMM can be used to update the hosts with Windows patches.When trying to scan a cluster of hosts for compliance the following error occurred:
Error (24035)
Compliance scan failed with error: 80244017.
Recommended Action:
Ensure the WINHTTP proxy settings are correctly configured for the communications with WSUS. If WSUS is configured to use SSL ensure the WSUS certificate is installed in the trusted Root CA for the machine and then try the operation again.</description></item><item><title>SCVMM library is unable to refesh a file because it is in use</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/06/09/scvmm-library-is-unable-to-refesh-a-file-because-it-is-in-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 14:53:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/06/09/scvmm-library-is-unable-to-refesh-a-file-because-it-is-in-use/</guid><description>In the jobs window in the System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) console , the following warning appeared:
Warning (10803)Unable to refresh \\server\share\ISO\Windows2012 R2\SW_DVD5_Windows_Svr_Std_and_DataCtr_2012_R2_64Bit_English_Core_MLF_X19-05182.ISO because the file is in use by another process.Recommended ActionWait for the next automatic library refresh, or manually refresh the library share after the process completes. The warning means that the ISO file is in use by one or more VMs. To find the VMs that are using the ISO file I created the following PowerShell script:</description></item><item><title>Tips for deploying SCVMM 2012 R2 Rollup 2</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 06:56:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</guid><description>Last week Update Rollup 2 (UR2) for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released. UR2 contains important fixes for SCVMM2012 R2. Here are some deployment tips for UR2:
Wait a least couple of weeks before deploying Update Rollups in your production environment. It happens that new Update Rollups contains huge bugs and are pulled back! Make sure you have a backup of the SCVMM database before installing UR2 Install the UR2 by download the VMM management server and VMM admin console packages link (or use Windows Update /WSUS to install both packages).</description></item><item><title>Check for duplicate MAC Address pools in your Hyper-V environment</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/01/13/check-for-duplicate-mac-address-pools-in-your-hyper-v-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 14:27:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/01/13/check-for-duplicate-mac-address-pools-in-your-hyper-v-environment/</guid><description>When enabling the Hyper-V role on a Windows 2012 (R2) server, it creates a dynamic MAC address pool of 256 MAC addresses available for VMs. The MAC Address Pool configuration can be found in the Virtual Switch Manager under the Global Network Settings.
The MAC address pool is generated as follows:
The first three octets are Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s IEEE organizationally Unique Identifier, 00:15:5D (which is common on all Hyper-V hosts) The next two octets are derived from the last two octets of the server&amp;rsquo;s IP address The last octet is automatically generated from the range 0x0 - 0xFF.</description></item><item><title>Identify LUN IDs in Windows Server 2012 R2</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/26/identify-lun-ids-in-windows-server-2012-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 19:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/26/identify-lun-ids-in-windows-server-2012-r2/</guid><description>During a Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V implementation I needed to identify all the iSCSI disks (LUNs) presented by an EMC VNX SAN to the Hyper-v Failover cluster. Each presented iSCSI disk has a unique LUN ID. To View the LUN ID of a disk, you can use the diskpart command. Here are the steps to view the LUN ID of a disk:
View the disks list disk
Select a disk select disk &amp;lt;number&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Running Hyper-V and VMware Workstation on Windows 8.x</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 19:40:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</guid><description>For testing I use Hyper-V and VMware Workstation 10 on my laptop. One restriction of VMware Workstation is that it does not support VHDX disk files (yet). VMware Workstation support VHD files, so the VHDX files must be converted to a VHD first. After the conversion VMware Workstation can select the VHD as Hard Disk. This can takes some time.
1. VHD disk2. Convert options in Hyper-VThat’s why I use Hyper-V on my laptop sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Hyper-V Get Snapshot checkpoint file sizes on Cluster Shared Volumes with PowerShell</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/09/17/list-hyper-v-snapshot-file-sizes-on-cluster-shared-volumes-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 13:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/09/17/list-hyper-v-snapshot-file-sizes-on-cluster-shared-volumes-with-powershell/</guid><description>During a Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V Health Check I needed to know the snapshot file sizes for the all the snapshots on the Clustered Shared Volumes (CSVs). The Get-VMCheckpoint Cmdlet does not report the snapshot size. So I create a PowerShell one-liner that displays the following information:
Location of the snapshot file Date and time that the snapshot file was created Last write access time of the snapshot file File size in MBs The PowerShell one-liner is executed from a Hyper-V 2012 host that has access to all the Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs).</description></item><item><title>What&amp;rsquo;s new in Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/05/whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-r2-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 17:30:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/06/05/whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-r2-hyper-v/</guid><description>On TechEd Windows Server 2012 R2 is announced. Here are some highlights of “Hyper-V – What’s New in Windows Serve 2012 R2” session (MDC-B330):
Windows Azure IaaS compatibility—Windows Azure IaaS uses exactly the same virtualization as Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V. So VM’s on-premise can be moved to Azure (Iaas) without problems Generation 2 Virtual Machines (VMs). In the generation 2 VM are many emulated devices removed and it boots from virtual SCSI or synthetic network adapters.</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V Best Practices</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/21/windows-server-2012-hyper-v-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/21/windows-server-2012-hyper-v-best-practices/</guid><description>Roger Osborne has create a huge checklist form of best practices on Microsoft Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V. The Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V or Hyper-V 3 best practices focuses on the following topics:
Host settings Anti-virus exclusions Physical NICs settings, NIC teaming, VLANS, Virtual Network Adapters (NICs) Disk settings, VHDX Memory, dynamic memory Cluster settings Hyper-V replica Cluster aware updating SMB 3.0 File shares Virtual Domain Controllers Integration Services The best practice checklist form can be found here</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager has now Hyper-V 2012 support</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/19/vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager-has-now-hyper-v-2012-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:52:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/03/19/vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager-has-now-hyper-v-2012-support/</guid><description>VMware has released the beta the public beta of VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager 1.1. This beta supports Microsoft Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V or Hyper-V Server 2012. Another new capability is to migrate VMs from your Hyper-V to your VMware vSphere environment .
The VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager 1.1 is a minor release which introduces the following new capabilities:
Migration of virtual machines from Hyper-V to ESX or ESXi hosts. Support for the latest Microsoft Hyper-V hypervisor (as well as earlier Hyper-V versions).</description></item><item><title>Health Check your System Center Virtual Machine Server (SCVMM) 2012 environent with PowerShell</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/01/28/health-check-your-system-center-virtual-machine-server-scvmm-2012-environent-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 10:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/01/28/health-check-your-system-center-virtual-machine-server-scvmm-2012-environent-with-powershell/</guid><description>Last week I created a simple example of a HealtCheck PowerShell script that connects to Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager and displays information about the Hyper-V hosts and VMs managed by this server.
I run the PowerShell script from another Windows Server 2012 host. To make this work make sure the Hyper-V manager and the VMM Console is installed on the server. The VMM console can be installed from the Microsoft System Center 2012 Virtual Machine Manager ISO.</description></item><item><title>Switch between Windows Server 2012 core and Windows Server 2012 GUI</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/01/22/why-switch-between-windows-server-2012-core-and-windows-server-2012-gui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 08:55:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/01/22/why-switch-between-windows-server-2012-core-and-windows-server-2012-gui/</guid><description>In Windows Server 2012 you can choose between a Server Core and Server with a GUI (full) during the installation. The Full Server GUI has all the tools and options to configure and troubleshoot. Server core is a minimal Windows installation with less tools and options.
Server Core has the following advantages over Server Full:
Smaller footprint (disk and memory). It is more secure because the smaller attack surface. For example the Server core version has no Internet Explorer included.</description></item><item><title>Manage Hyper-V from vSphere with VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/11/22/manage-hyper-v-from-vsphere-with-vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 18:42:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/11/22/manage-hyper-v-from-vsphere-with-vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager/</guid><description>VMware released the first version (1.0) of the vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager (MHM). MHM makes it possible to manage multiple heterogeneous hypervisors in VMware vCenter server.
MHM supports only Microsoft Hyper-V Server 2008 and Microsoft Hyper-V Server 2008 R2 as hypervisor! MHM requires vCenter Server 5.1 and can manage 20 Hyper-V hosts with up to 500 VMs running.
As minimum vCenter Server Standard edition is needed. The vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager is not available with the vCenter Server Foundation or Essentials edition!</description></item><item><title>Tested: Altaro Hyper-V Backup</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</guid><description>In my LAB environment I tested Altaro Hyper-V Backup version 3. Altaro Hyper-V Backup is software that makes it possible to backup and restore Windows 2008 (R2) Hyper-V VMs.
Editions There are three editions available: The free edition, the standard edition and the unlimited edition. For this test I used the unlimited edition because it supports “Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs)”. More info can be found here.
Installation Altaro Hyper-V Backup needs to be installed on the Hyper-V host.</description></item><item><title>Convert VMware to Hyper-V VMs with Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 12:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</guid><description>Last week Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter RC is released. Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter is a stand-alone tool that makes it possible to convert and deploys VMware based VMs to Hyper-V based VMs. It’s coverts the VMware VM and virtual disks (VMDK) to Hyper-V VMs and Virtual Hard Disks (VHDs). As virtualization consultant I got “sometimes“ involved in migrating VMware to Hyper-V VMs, so I tried Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter.
What’s supported Supported VMware platforms to convert from :</description></item><item><title>Nest Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V in VMware ESXi 5</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/06/28/nest-windows-server-2012-hyper-v-in-vmware-esxi-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 09:57:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/06/28/nest-windows-server-2012-hyper-v-in-vmware-esxi-5/</guid><description>In this blog post I explain how you can install Windows 2012 Server Release Candidate (RC) in VMware ESXi and enable the Hyper-V role. It is possible to build a Hyper-V cluster LAB and live migrate VMs between the virtual Hyper-V nodes on one VMware ESXi 5 host.
Before you begin make sure:
Windows 2012 Server RC ISO is place on a datastore VMware ESXi 5 Update 1 is installed with the latest updates To be able to boot 64bit guest OSes, make sure that on the VMware ESXi host the line below is added to the /etc/VMware/config file on your physical ESXi 5.</description></item><item><title>Identify NICs in Hyper-V 2012</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/26/identify-nics-in-windows-server-8-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 12:49:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/26/identify-nics-in-windows-server-8-hyper-v/</guid><description>In a Hyper-V cluster are normally a lot of NICs involved. Identifying the right can be challenging. It is important to consequently label your network adapters on all the servers in the Hyper-V cluster.
In Windows Server 2012 there are PowerShell Cmdlets that can be used for identifying NICs. Once you identified the NIC, rename it to meaningful name. The PowerShell Cmdlets listed below can be executed on the following versions:</description></item><item><title>Enable Windows Server 8 Hyper-V in VMware Workstation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 21:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 is available as download. The Technology Preview makes it possible for example to install and operate Windows 8 and Windows Server 8 in a VM and the possibility to nest VMs.
I tested the installation of Windows Server 8 in VMware Workstation TP, enabled the Hyper-V role and run a Windows 7 64-bit VM in Hyper-V. Here are some screenshots (Hyper-V manager and the Windows 7 64 bit running in Hyper-V): To make the above configuration work, add to following options to the end of the VMX file before starting the Windows Server 8 installation:</description></item><item><title>Intel X79 whitebox for vSphere 5 and Hyper-V 3</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</guid><description>In an earlier blog post (found here ) I mentioned that it is time for a new homebrew whitebox based on the Intel X79 chipset. With the X79 chipset it is possible to install 64GB of memory (8 x 8 GB). Because the 8 GB DIMMs are expensive on the moment, I decided to use 8 x 4GB DIMMs (total 32GB).
I decided to create one physical host for testing VMware vSphere 5, vCloud Director, VMware SRM, VMware View 5 etc.</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2012 PowerShell Cmdlets for Hyper-V help</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/07/windows-server-8-powershell-cmdlets-for-hyper-v-help/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 14:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/07/windows-server-8-powershell-cmdlets-for-hyper-v-help/</guid><description>In Windows 2008 &amp;amp; Windows2008 R2 there were no official PowerShell Cmdlets available for Hyper-V. This is changed in Windows 2012 and Windows 8. Windows Server 2012 and 8 has 162 or more PowerShell Cmdlets available for Hyper-V. Windows 8 uses PowerShell version 3.
Cmdlets are very powerful, that lets you automate all aspects of Hyper-V. Here some guidance how-to find the Cmdlets you need.
To view all the Hyper-V PowerShell Cmdlets:</description></item><item><title>Watch out installing SP1 on your Hyper-V R2 cluster</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/25/watch-out-installing-sp1-on-your-hyper-v-r2-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 20:20:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/25/watch-out-installing-sp1-on-your-hyper-v-r2-cluster/</guid><description>Yesterday I spoke a customer who has problems after applying Windows 2008 R2 SP1 on his 5 node Hyper-V cluster. When validating the storage on the cluster, the following error “disk with identifier “2ef8c0……” has a persistent reservation” is displayed on multiple cluster disks.
The problem can occur in the following scenario:
**- You configure a failover cluster that has three or more nodes that are running Windows Server 2008 R2 Service Pack 1 (SP1).</description></item><item><title>Hyper-V and hibernate</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/21/hyper-v-and-hibernate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 09:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/21/hyper-v-and-hibernate/</guid><description>For my MS Hyper-V home server I want to hibernate every day between 12.30 and 07.00 am. When the Hyper-V role is installed, it is not possible to use the hibernate function. The following steps make it possible to automatic hibernate the system and when it wake up, the Hyper-V service and the VM(s) are started.
Steps:
1. Download “PowerShell Management Library for Hyper-V” file found here . Unblock the zone information from this zip, extract it and run the install file.</description></item><item><title>Homebrew / Whitelist Hyper-V R2 home server NAS</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/18/homebrew-whitelist-hyper-v-home-server-nas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 10:30:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/03/18/homebrew-whitelist-hyper-v-home-server-nas/</guid><description>For my home lab i was looking for a home server with NAS functionality. My current Iomega IX2 (2x500GB) NAS is replaced by this server. For this server I had the following requirements
Low power consumption (24x7) Low noise Flexibly and room to expand with extra hard drive(s),hardware RAID and a NIC Home server functionality for sharing photos, music, documents and films NAS functionality with iSCSI and NFS protocol FTP server Hypervisor enabled Backup server Print server Active Directory DNS server Download server Wake-on-LAN functionality to start other virtualization hosts I selected the following components:</description></item><item><title>Test Microsoft Hyper-V R2 server on your laptop with Virtual Hard Disk (VHD)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/03/test-microsoft-hyper-v-r2-server-on-your-laptop-with-virtual-hard-disk-vhd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 09:29:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/12/03/test-microsoft-hyper-v-r2-server-on-your-laptop-with-virtual-hard-disk-vhd/</guid><description>When you want to test some Microsoft Hyper-V R2 stuff it’s handy to do that on your laptop. I test a lot stuff on my laptop equipped with Microsoft Windows 7, 8GB RAM and VMware Workstation. Installing Microsoft Hyper-V R2 for example in VMware Workstation is possible, but it is not possible to start any Virtual Machines (VMs). Microsoft Hyper-V requires a processor with Intel-VT or AMD-V with the No-Execute (NX) feature.</description></item><item><title>Create a bootable USB to install Windows 8 Server or Hyper-V Server 8</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and install for example Windows Server 8. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable for the following OS versions:
Windows Server 8 Hyper-V Server 8 Server 2008 R2 Hyper-V Server R2 Preparation: Need a 4 GB USB memory stick or more Download the desired ISO and save it Stick the USB stick on a free USB port on your computer equipped with a Windows OS.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft TechDays Belgium</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/03/12/microsoft-techdays-belgium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 20:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2009/03/12/microsoft-techdays-belgium/</guid><description>The last three days i attended Microsoft TechDays in Antwerpen (Belgium). The first day (pre-conference) was dedicated to Windows 2008 R2. The other 2 days I attended sessions such as Windows 7, Powershell V2, SYSVOL replication and Remote Desktop Services (former Terminal Services). Here is an short overview:
Windows 2008 R2 will be released in 64-bit version only. - All new Windows server product can be managed through PowerShell PowerShell 2 is default installed on Windows 2008 R2 and Windows 7.</description></item><item><title>Offline Virtual Machine Servicing tool 2.0 released</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2008/11/28/offline-virtual-machine-servicing-tool-20-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 18:36:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2008/11/28/offline-virtual-machine-servicing-tool-20-released/</guid><description>The Offline Virtual Machine Servicing Tool 2.0 helps organizations maintain virtual machines that are stored offline in a Microsoft® System Center Virtual Machine Manager library. While stored, virtual machines do not receive operating system updates. The tool provides a way to keep offline virtual machines up-to-date so that bringing a virtual machine online does not introduce vulnerabilities into the organization’s IT infrastructure.
The Offline Virtual Machine Servicing Tool combines the Windows Workflow programming model with the Windows PowerShell™ interface to bring groups of virtual machines online just long enough for them to receive updates from either System Center Configuration Manager 2007 or Windows Server Update Services.</description></item></channel></rss>