<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vSphere5 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/vsphere5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vSphere5 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 22:28:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/vsphere5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure the Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP) in vSphere 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/16/configure-the-link-layer-discovery-protocol-lldp-in-vsphere-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 07:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/16/configure-the-link-layer-discovery-protocol-lldp-in-vsphere-5/</guid>
      <description>Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP)is a vendor-neutral open standard discovery protocol that is supported by multiple vendors such as Cisco, HP and Juniper for example. LLDP displays for example on what network switch and port the NIC in the ESXi hosts is connected. Prior VMware vSphere 5 only Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP) was supported.&#xA;In vSphere 5 Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP) is supported. CDP and LLDP can be handy for example when you want to know that the correct network switch port is used when installing or troubleshooting ESXi hosts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VM snapshot needs consolidation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/10/vm-snapshot-needs-consolidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 07:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/05/10/vm-snapshot-needs-consolidation/</guid>
      <description>When a snapshot didn’t commit properly, it can happen that the snapshot manager in the vCenter server shows no snapshot(s), but that there are still active delta files on the datastore. These ‘hidden’ snapshot can cause the datastore to run out of space.&#xA;To report these ‘hidden’ snapshots (prior vSphere 5), I created a script that searches all the datastores for ‘*.delta’ files and reported them by mail.&#xA;In vSphere 5 you have a new feature that reports and make it possible to consolidate these ‘hidden’ snapshot(s).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to VMware ESXi 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/08/18/upgrading-to-vmware-esxi-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 14:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/08/18/upgrading-to-vmware-esxi-5/</guid>
      <description>The following three supported upgrade methods to VMware ESXi 5 are available:&#xA;Upgrade Method ESX or ESXI to ESXi5 Upgrade or Patch from ESXi 5 to ESXi 5.x vSphere Update Manager yes yes Interactive upgrade from CD, DVD, or USB drive yes yes Scripted upgrade yes yes vSphere Auto Deploy no yes esxcli no yes It is not supported to directly upgrade ESX(i) 3.x to ESXi 5. You must first upgrade ESX(i) 3 to ESX(i) 4 before upgrading to ESXi 5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere 5 licensing update explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/07/15/vmware-vsphere-5-licensing-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 12:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2011/07/15/vmware-vsphere-5-licensing-explained/</guid>
      <description>With the announcement of VMware vSphere 5 a complete new license model is introduces.&#xA;In VMware vSphere 4 the licensing model was per physical processor based on the number of cores per CPU and the physical memory.&#xA;The VMware vSphere 5 license model is based per physical processor and the allocated memory (vRAM) across the entire vSphere environment for a particular vSphere 5 edition (pool).&#xA;Update August 27, 2012&#xA;Today VMware announced the end of the vRAM entitlement.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
