<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>azure on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/azure/</link><description>Recent content in azure on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The latest technology news week 32-2023</title><link>/2023/08/15/the-latest-technology-news-week-32-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:02:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/08/15/the-latest-technology-news-week-32-2023/</guid><description>The latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, VMware, and other partners with a focus on End User Computing (EUC).
Microsoft Azure
Generally available: Azure Blob Storage Cold Tier. Link Public preview: Azure Storage Mover support for SMB and Azure Files. Link Subscribe to the Azure Stack HCI Newsletter. Link Azure managed disk types overview.</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 28-31 2023</title><link>/2023/08/07/the-latest-technology-news-week-28-till-31-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:13:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/08/07/the-latest-technology-news-week-28-till-31-2023/</guid><description>After a great holiday an overview of the latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, VMware, and other partners with a focus on End User Computing (EUC).
Microsoft Azure
Hot patching is now available for Windows Server VMs on Azure with Desktop Experience! Link Windows Server end-of-support (EOS): Upgrade seamlessly with Azure Migrate (Public preview).</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 27–2023</title><link>/2023/07/11/the-latest-technology-news-week-27-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 05:52:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/07/11/the-latest-technology-news-week-27-2023/</guid><description>Here’s the latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, including updates on Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD), Windows 365, VMware, and IaC.
Microsoft Azure
Check This Out! (CTO!) Guide (June 2023). Discover the latest innovations in core infrastructure &amp;amp; security! Link What is Azure Virtual Network encryption (Preview)? Link Microsoft Events and where to find them (v1.</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 25–2023</title><link>/2023/06/25/the-latest-technology-news-week-25-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 19:53:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/06/25/the-latest-technology-news-week-25-2023/</guid><description>Here’s the latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, including updates on Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD), Windows 365, VMware, and HashiCorp Terraform.
Microsoft Azure
Azure AD Security Config Analyzer (AADSCA). Link Graph PowerShell Conversion Analyzer. Get help converting your MSOnline and Azure AD PowerShell script to Graph PowerShell. Link Azure AD Application Activity Report Analysis.</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 24-2023</title><link>/2023/06/16/the-latest-technology-news-week-24-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 07:51:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/06/16/the-latest-technology-news-week-24-2023/</guid><description>Here’s the latest weekly technology news from Microsoft, including updates on Azure, Windows 10 and 11, Microsoft Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD), Windows 365, VMware, and HashiCorp Terraform.
Azure
Azure Service Retirement workbook. Link Azure Reliability workbook. You can evaluate the reliability of the posture of your applications, assess risks and plan improvements using the new Reliability workbook template, which is available in Azure Advisor.</description></item><item><title>The latest technology news week 23-2023</title><link>/2023/06/10/the-latest-technology-news-week-23-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 06:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/06/10/the-latest-technology-news-week-23-2023/</guid><description>Here’s the weekly latest technology news from Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD), Windows 365, and VMware. The main focus is based on Cloud and End User Computing (EUC) technology.
Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD)
Nerdio Modeler for Azure Virtual Desktop. Modeler prompts for a handful of inputs and produces an easy-to-understand cost analysis, including auto-scale savings.</description></item><item><title>Perform an Azure Virtual Machine (VM) inventory with PowerShell</title><link>/2023/05/16/perform-an-azure-vm-inventory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 17:48:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/05/16/perform-an-azure-vm-inventory/</guid><description>To generate quickly an overview of all the Virtual Machines (VMs) in an Azure subscription I made a PowerShell script that uses the Azure Az PowerShell module. This script will do an inventory of all VMs in a subscription.
The following VM information is displayed per subscription:
Name PowerState Region Resource Group VM Size CPU Cores Memory (MB) License Type Operating System Offer SKU Publisher VM Generation VM Agent version OS Name OS Version NIC Name VNet Private IP address Public IP address OS disk name OS disk size (GB) OS storage type OS disk caching Data disks count Data disks names Admin username If boot diagnostics is enabled Boot diagnostics storage account Tags The time the VM was created The output will be displayed in the PowerShell console, to a PowerShell GridView output, and saved to a delimited CSV file.</description></item><item><title>Create Windows VMs in Azure with Terraform</title><link>/2023/03/27/create-windows-vms-in-azure-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 17:42:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/03/27/create-windows-vms-in-azure-with-terraform/</guid><description>With Terraform you can easily create new VMs in an existing Azure environment in a couple of minutes. For example, when I want to test an application, I create a new VM and install the application. When I finish testing I remove the VM with a single command. The VM creation only takes a couple of minutes.</description></item><item><title>Quick tip: Reset the password of an Azure Virtual Machine</title><link>/2023/02/01/quick-tip-reset-the-password-of-a-azure-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 11:55:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/02/01/quick-tip-reset-the-password-of-a-azure-virtual-machine/</guid><description>In my Azure test tenant, I forgot the password of an Azure Windows Domain Controller VM. In Azure, there is a Reset Password option available in the VM options.
The password reset update failed. The password reset option uses a VM Access extension. When digging into the activity log I found the following error:</description></item><item><title>Create a Site-to-Site VPN to Microsoft Azure</title><link>/2021/11/08/create-a-site-to-site-vpn-to-microsoft-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/11/08/create-a-site-to-site-vpn-to-microsoft-azure/</guid><description>I have a Visual Studio Enterprise subscription in Azure. I use this subscription for testing new Azure stuff. From my on-premises environment, I want to create a Site-To-Site (S2S) VPN connection to Microsoft Azure. I have a physical Ubiquiti Edge Router in my on-premises network. When searching the internet I found a lot of information that was outdated or not completed.</description></item><item><title>Manage Azure VMs with System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM)</title><link>/2015/07/15/manage-azure-vms-with-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 09:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/07/15/manage-azure-vms-with-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-scvmm/</guid><description>With Update Rollup 6 it is possible to add one or more Azure subscriptions to SCVMM 2012 R2. When the Azure subscription is added in SCVMM, it is possible to perform some basic actions such as:
Add and Remove one or more Azure subscriptions by using the VMM console. See a list view with details and status of all role instances in all deployments in that subscription.</description></item></channel></rss>