<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure virtual desktop on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/azure-virtual-desktop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure virtual desktop on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:30:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/azure-virtual-desktop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New Microsoft Teams Client throw an error in AVD - The parameter is incorrect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/02/new-teams-parameter-is-incorrect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 15:44:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/02/new-teams-parameter-is-incorrect/</guid>
      <description>After deploying new Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) session hosts with the new Teams Client installed, users getting the following error after the login:&#xA;C:\Program Files\WindowsApp\MSTeams_24004.1307.2669.7070_x64_8wekyb..\msteams_autostarter.exe&#xA;The parameter is incorrect&#xA;In the picture the error The parameter is incorrect is displayed as de parameter is onjuist because the AVD host has a Dutch language pack installed.&#xA;To solve this issue I performed the following steps:&#xA;Install FSLogix 2210 hotfix 3 (2.9.8784.63912). link on the AVD image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot your Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) or Remote Desktop Environment with the MSRD-Collect tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/12/22/troubleshoot-your-azure-virtual-desktop-avd-or-remote-desktop-environment-with-msrd-collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/12/22/troubleshoot-your-azure-virtual-desktop-avd-or-remote-desktop-environment-with-msrd-collect/</guid>
      <description>I recently stumbled on a cool tool called “MSRD-Collect”. MSRD stands for Microsoft CSS Remote Desktop Data Collection and Diagnostic Script. MSRD-Collect is a PowerShell script with separate modules designed to collect information that will help Microsoft Customer Support Services (CSS) to troubleshoot issues in Azure Virtual Desktop or Remote Desktop Services environments.&#xA;MSRD-Collect is not only a handy tool for Microsoft CSS but can be used by AVD or RDS administrators having issues or who want to check the health of their session hosts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip - Download the Azure Virtual Desktop RDPW files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/10/04/quick-tip-download-the-azure-virtual-desktop-rdpw-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 14:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/10/04/quick-tip-download-the-azure-virtual-desktop-rdpw-files/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need the RDPW files when having for example remote apps listed in a central portal application integration. Here is a quick tip on how to download the Azure Virtual Desktop RDPW files for desktops and remote apps.&#xA;1. Log in using the AVD WebClient using the following URL: https://client.wvd.microsoft.com/arm/webclient/index.html 2. In the right corner click on the Settings wheel&#xA;3. Select in &amp;ldquo;Resources Launch Method&amp;rdquo; section for &amp;ldquo;Download the rdp file&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimize the Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) golden image automatically</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/03/25/azure-virtual-desktop-avd-optimization-script-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2022/03/25/azure-virtual-desktop-avd-optimization-script-automation/</guid>
      <description>For Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD) there is an Optimization Tool available called Virtual Desktop Optimization Tool (VDOT). With this tool/script you optimize the following categories within an Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD):&#xA;Universal Windows Platform (UWP) app cleanup Optional Features cleanup Local policy settings System services Scheduled tasks Apply Windows (and other) updates Automatic Windows traces Windows Defender optimization Client network performance tuning by registry settings Additional settings from the &amp;ldquo;Windows Restricted Traffic Limited Functionality Baseline&amp;rdquo; guidance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
