<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware Horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/vmware-horizon/</link><description>Recent content in VMware Horizon on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/vmware-horizon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get the highest concurrent license usage from a VMware Horizon environment</title><link>/2022/03/09/get-the-highest-concurrent-license-usage-from-a-vmware-horizon-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 12:57:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/03/09/get-the-highest-concurrent-license-usage-from-a-vmware-horizon-environment/</guid><description>In some managed VMware Horizon environments, I wanted to know the highest concurrent users per month. This information can be found in the Horizon Administrator Console under Settings -&amp;gt; Product Licensing and Usage -&amp;gt; Usage.
Using the VMware Horizon Administrator console is a manual task. I wanted to automate this. To automated this use VMware PowerCLI which supports access to the View API.</description></item><item><title>Tested: VDI End User Experience monitoring tools</title><link>/2016/08/26/tested-vdi-end-user-experience-monitor-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 07:28:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/08/26/tested-vdi-end-user-experience-monitor-tools/</guid><description>The success and effectiveness of a VDI environment depends on the End User Experience (UX). When the End User Experience isn’t good, users will complain and the VDI project will fail. So the ability to analyze, report and troubleshoot when a problem occurs is critical in a VDI environment. To get this insight I tested ControlUp v6 and VMware vRealize Operations for Horizon v6.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon Q2 2015 announcements</title><link>/2015/04/29/vmware-horizon-q2-2015-announcements/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 19:51:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/04/29/vmware-horizon-q2-2015-announcements/</guid><description>VMware announced last week what’s new with Horizon 6 (Q2 2015) as well as some brand new offerings that will help you to deliver and manage apps and end users across physical, virtual and cloud-hosted environments. Here are the announcements:
User Experience improvements Linux Desktops support (GA in Q2) User Environment Manager (UEM) (GA in Q2) VMware Workspace Environment Management (WEM) Free SysTrack Desktop Assessment tool User Experience Improvements</description></item><item><title>Create a VMware Horizon View self signed certificate with makecert</title><link>/2014/06/24/create-a-vmware-horizon-view-self-signed-certificate-with-makecert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 07:03:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/06/24/create-a-vmware-horizon-view-self-signed-certificate-with-makecert/</guid><description>With the command line Windows utility makecert.exe it is possible to create quickly a self-signed (private) certificate that can be used with VMware Horizon View. Makecert is part of the Windows Software Deployment Kit (SDK)for Windows 7 and 8. Below are the steps outlined to create a self-signed certificate using makecert.</description></item></channel></rss>