<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>upgrade on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/upgrade/</link><description>Recent content in upgrade on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick tip: VMware VCSA installer page is blank when selecting a datastore</title><link>/2022/08/24/quick-tip-vmware-vcsa-installer-page-is-blank-when-selecting-a-datastore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/08/24/quick-tip-vmware-vcsa-installer-page-is-blank-when-selecting-a-datastore/</guid><description>While upgrading a vCenter Server 6.7 to version 7 Update 3 using the vCenter Server 7 UI installer, I was not able to select a datastore for installing the new vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA).
The datastore selection was blank as shown in the following image.
This issue still exists in the vCenter Server 7 UI installer.
Here are the steps to solve this:
Go to the %appdata% folder (it opens the C:\Users&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming folder) Delete the installer folder.</description></item><item><title>After upgrading vSphere 4 to 5 the Fusion-IO card is in minimal mode</title><link>/2013/12/03/upgrading-vsphere-5-x-fusion-io-card-disappeared/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:49:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/12/03/upgrading-vsphere-5-x-fusion-io-card-disappeared/</guid><description>Last week I did a VMware vSphere and VMware View 4 to 5 upgrade. The ESXi servers for the VMware View environment uses Fusion-IO (HP IO Accelerators) PCI flash cards for there non-persistent VDI pools. After the upgrade to vSphere 5.1 I imported the latest Fusion-IO drivers and created a baseline in vSphere Update Manager (VUM) and deployed the new drivers to the cluster.
After the installation of the Fusion-IO drivers on the ESXi hosts, the Fusion-IO card was not listed in the vSphere (Web) client.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to vSphere 5.1? Check your third party software</title><link>/2012/11/28/upgrading-to-vsphere-5-1-check-your-third-party-software/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 13:29:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/11/28/upgrading-to-vsphere-5-1-check-your-third-party-software/</guid><description>Before upgrading to vSphere 5.1 it is important to check your existing hardware, firmware levels, drivers, vSphere versions, other VMware products that integrates and third party software if it is compatible with vSphere 5.1. Here is a list of third party software and it’s support for vSphere 5.1 .
Software Version vSphere 5.1 Support Comment Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication 6.5 yes CommVault 9 SP8 yes 3 extra SP8 post patches needed PHDVB 6.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade Windows Server 2012 Release Candidate (RC) to RTM</title><link>/2012/09/07/upgrade-windows-server-2012-release-candidate-rc-to-rtm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 09:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/09/07/upgrade-windows-server-2012-release-candidate-rc-to-rtm/</guid><description>Now Windows Server 2012 is release I tried to upgrade my lab environment from Microsoft Windows Server 2012 RC 8400 to Windows 2012 RTM. It is not officially supported to upgrade from Windows Server 2012 RC to Windows Server 2012 RTM by Microsoft.
I did the following steps to upgrade:
Downloaded the Windows Server 2012 ISO Mount or extract the ISO Executed setup.exe After several screens it is possible to choose for “Upgrade: Install Windows and keep files, settings and applications” option Now the he following error appeared: The upgrade cannot continue.</description></item><item><title>Post checks after upgrading to VMware vSphere 4.1</title><link>/2010/12/17/post-checks-after-upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-4-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 12:09:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/12/17/post-checks-after-upgrading-to-vmware-vsphere-4-1/</guid><description>Memory Limits When adding existing VMware ESX servers (for example 3.5) to the VMware vCenter 4.1 server, all the VMs got a memory limit.
To reset the memory limits to unlimited for all VMs, use the following PowerCLI script:
Connect-VIServer &amp;lt;servername&amp;gt; Get-VM | Get-VMResourceConfiguration | Where-Object {$\_.MemLimitMB -ne ‘-1‘} | Set-VMResourceConfiguration -MemLimitMB $null VMware ESX NICs as fixed Already mentioned earlier in the “Change NIC speed and duplex setting to AUTO in ESX4 using PowerCLI” blogpost.</description></item></channel></rss>