<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows-11 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/windows-11/</link><description>Recent content in windows-11 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/windows-11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer</title><link>/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</guid><description>Some people ask if it is possible to create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer. The answer is YES. The Packer plugin that makes this possible is called “Hyperv”. Version 1.1.1 supports TPM. Enabling TPM in the Hyper-V VM makes it possible to install Windows 11 without any registry hacks.</description></item><item><title>Customize the Windows 11 Start Menu</title><link>/2022/12/13/customize-the-windows-11-start-menu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 07:37:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/12/13/customize-the-windows-11-start-menu/</guid><description>Start Menu management in Windows 11 is different than Windows 10. Microsoft recommended an MDM provider such as Microsoft Intune to manage the Windows 11 Start Menu.
There are many environments (such as VDI and Azure Virtual Desktop(AVD) that don&amp;rsquo;t use an MDM provider to manage their Windows 11 workspace environment.</description></item><item><title>How to install Windows 11 on VMware Workstation</title><link>/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 07:26:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/10/17/how-to-install-windows-11-on-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>For testing purposes, I frequently use VMware Workstation to install Operating Systems such as Windows 11. The biggest challenge with Windows 11 is that you need a TPM 2.0 device. When installing Windows 11, if your computer does not meet the hardware requirements, you will see a message stating, “This PC can’t run Windows 11“.</description></item><item><title>Disable the little drawing (known as search highlights) in the Windows 10/11 search bar</title><link>/2022/06/27/disable-the-little-drawing-known-as-search-highlights-in-the-windows-10-11-search-bar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/06/27/disable-the-little-drawing-known-as-search-highlights-in-the-windows-10-11-search-bar/</guid><description>After deploying new Windows 10/11 images with the latest updates, Microsoft has included Search highlights. You can see if you have search highlights enabled when having a little drawing in the search bar. When clicking on the search bar it extends with graphics and more crap.
So what are search highlights?</description></item><item><title>Use Packer to install Windows 11 and enable vTPM and VBS</title><link>/2021/10/22/use-packer-to-install-windows-11-and-enable-vtpm-and-vbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 07:30:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/22/use-packer-to-install-windows-11-and-enable-vtpm-and-vbs/</guid><description>I use Packer for building images for VMware VDI environments. With the latest version (when writing this blog Packer version 1.7.7 is the latest version) it is not possible to configure a TPM in the Hashicorp Configuration Languag (HCL) config file. TPM 2.0 is required to install Windows 11. A vTPM emulates a physical TPM 2.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows 11 on VMware vSphere with a virtual TPM</title><link>/2021/10/07/install-windows-11-on-vmware-vsphere-with-a-virtual-tpm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 20:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/07/install-windows-11-on-vmware-vsphere-with-a-virtual-tpm/</guid><description>Yesterday I wrote a blog called “Install Windows 11 as VM on VMware vSphere / Workstation without TPM 2.0 chipset“. In this blog article, I explained how to install Windows 11 without having a TPM 2.0 chipset by using a registry hack. Paul Braren from tinkertry.com created a cool video (link) about installing Windows 11 on VMware vSphere using my blog article.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows 11 as VM on VMware vSphere / Workstation without TPM 2.0</title><link>/2021/10/06/install-windows-11-as-vm-in-vmware-vsphere-workstation-without-tpm-2-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 10:18:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/06/install-windows-11-as-vm-in-vmware-vsphere-workstation-without-tpm-2-0/</guid><description>Yesterday Windows 11 is officially released. Windows 11 require a Trusted Platform Module (TPM) version 2.0 (link). . My VMware ESXi servers at home don’t have a TPM 2.0. During the installation, Windows will check for the presence of a TPM 2.0, if not available the installation will fail. There is a registry hack available to bypass the TPM 2.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip: Download the latest Windows 11 ISO files</title><link>/2021/05/19/quick-tip-download-the-latest-windows-10-iso-file/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 18:55:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/05/19/quick-tip-download-the-latest-windows-10-iso-file/</guid><description>In my lab environment, I use the latest Windows 10 or Windows 11 versions (for example the new Windows 11 23H2) for creating and testing golden images for VDI environments.
To download the latest Windows ISOs file I use the Windows Media Creation Tool. This is a Windows-based tool. When starting the Windows Media Creation Tool it opens a Graphical User Interface and you are able to download Windows Home (N), Education (N), and the Pro (N) ISO.</description></item></channel></rss>