<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>controlup on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/tags/controlup/</link><description>Recent content in controlup on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/controlup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ControlUp 8.1 Native VMware Horizon integration</title><link>/2020/01/16/controlup-8-1-native-vmware-horizon-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 08:22:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/16/controlup-8-1-native-vmware-horizon-integration/</guid><description>In part 2 we highlight the native support for VMware Horizon 7 and higher environments in ControlUp 8.1. The integration is based on the SOAP API. Adding a VMware Horizon environment is easy, click on the Add EUC environment and enter the name a Horizon Connection Server and click ‘OK’. ControlUp discovers Horizon components such as Connection Servers, Cloud Pod Architecture (CPA), desktop pools and sessions automatically.</description></item><item><title>ControlUp 8.1 Monitor Cluster</title><link>/2020/01/14/controlup-8-1-monitor-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 13:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/14/controlup-8-1-monitor-cluster/</guid><description>Today ControlUp version 8.1 is released with two new major features:
Monitor Cluster. This new cluster model adds support for monitoring more VDI endpoints per site. VMware Horizon integration. ControlUp has now native integration with VMware Horizon environments. In this part of the blog post, I explain the basics of the new Monitor Cluster.</description></item><item><title>Tested: VDI End User Experience monitoring tools</title><link>/2016/08/26/tested-vdi-end-user-experience-monitor-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 07:28:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/08/26/tested-vdi-end-user-experience-monitor-tools/</guid><description>The success and effectiveness of a VDI environment depends on the End User Experience (UX). When the End User Experience isn’t good, users will complain and the VDI project will fail. So the ability to analyze, report and troubleshoot when a problem occurs is critical in a VDI environment. To get this insight I tested ControlUp v6 and VMware vRealize Operations for Horizon v6.</description></item></channel></rss>