<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vpshere on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/vpshere/</link><description>Recent content in vpshere on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/categories/vpshere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>After upgrading vSphere 4 to 5 the Fusion-IO card is in minimal mode</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/03/upgrading-vsphere-5-x-fusion-io-card-disappeared/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:49:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/03/upgrading-vsphere-5-x-fusion-io-card-disappeared/</guid><description>Last week I did a VMware vSphere and VMware View 4 to 5 upgrade. The ESXi servers for the VMware View environment uses Fusion-IO (HP IO Accelerators) PCI flash cards for there non-persistent VDI pools. After the upgrade to vSphere 5.1 I imported the latest Fusion-IO drivers and created a baseline in vSphere Update Manager (VUM) and deployed the new drivers to the cluster.</description></item><item><title>Tested: PHD Virtual Backup 6.0</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 09:50:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/21/tested-phd-virtual-backup-6-0/</guid><description>PHD Virtual Backup is a backup and recovery solution for VMware and Citrix environments. PHD Virtual Backup version 6 is released. We tested this new version with VMware vSpher
What’s new in PHD Virtual Backup version 6: PHD Virtual Backup version 6.0 contains the following major enhancements:
PHD Instant Recovery: Instant Recovery lets you access your backed up data right away.</description></item><item><title>What about VMware Virtual Machine hardware versions</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/29/what-about-vmware-virtual-machine-hardware-versions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 14:44:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/12/29/what-about-vmware-virtual-machine-hardware-versions/</guid><description>It depends on the features you need. If you want for example use the “Changed Blocked Tracking (CBT)” feature, you need at least hardware version 7.
In ESX 3.x hardware version 4 is introduced, in vSphere 4.x hardware version 7 is introduced and in vSphere 5 hardware version 8 is introduced.</description></item><item><title>Enable and disable Remote Tech Support mode (SSH)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/11/11/enable-or-disable-remote-tech-support-mode-ssh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 09:58:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/11/11/enable-or-disable-remote-tech-support-mode-ssh/</guid><description>When you start the Remote Tech Support (TSM) service on a VMware ESXi host a warning and the following message will appear:
Remote Tech Support Mode (SSH) for the host … has been enabled
When the warning appears some Admins get a little nervous. Since VMware ESXi 4.1 Update 2 and VMware ESXi 5 the warning can be suppressed.</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere 5 licensing update explained</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/07/15/vmware-vsphere-5-licensing-explained/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 12:25:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/07/15/vmware-vsphere-5-licensing-explained/</guid><description>With the announcement of VMware vSphere 5 a complete new license model is introduces.
In VMware vSphere 4 the licensing model was per physical processor based on the number of cores per CPU and the physical memory.
The VMware vSphere 5 license model is based per physical processor and the allocated memory (vRAM) across the entire vSphere environment for a particular vSphere 5 edition (pool).</description></item><item><title>Unable to commit snapshot after VADP backup</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/05/02/unable-to-commit-snapshot-after-vadp-backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/05/02/unable-to-commit-snapshot-after-vadp-backup/</guid><description>hen doing a health check I found the following error during the remove if a snapshot in vCenter:
Unable to access file since it is locked
There is a problem when committing the snapshot after the vStorage APIs for Data Protection (VADP) backup of the VM.
In the snapshot manager in vCenter there was no snapshot visible.</description></item></channel></rss>