<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware-horizon-view on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/vmware-horizon-view/</link><description>Recent content in VMware-horizon-view on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/vmware-horizon-view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enable Touch ID Authentication in VMware Horizon</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/10/05/enable-touch-id-authentication-in-vmware-horizon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 06:47:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/10/05/enable-touch-id-authentication-in-vmware-horizon/</guid><description>In Horizon 6.2 it is possible to authenticate with Apples Touch ID. Touch ID is not enabled by default and has the following minimal requirements:
iPhone 5S, 6, and 6 Plus iPad Air 2 and iPad mini 3 IOS 8 Horizon 6 version 6.2 The View Connection Server must present a valid root-signed certificate to the Horizon Client Horizon 3.</description></item><item><title>The end of Tera1 zero client support in VMware Horizon View 6</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 14:01:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/11/the-end-of-the-tera1-zero-client-support-in-vmware-horizon-view-6/</guid><description>The Tera1 zero clients has reached their limits on new features that can be added and the ability to support new features of Horizon View such as RDSH. Teradici supports the following combinations:
ProcessorFirmwareHorizon View Version supportVMware CertifiedTera24.8.06.1YesTera24.7.16.0YesTera14.7.16.0.1No (*2)(*2) Tera1 zero clients are certified on VMware Horizon View 5.3 and earlier.</description></item><item><title>VMware tools update fails on ESXi 6 hosts with Dutch Operating System VMs</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/04/vmware-tools-update-fails-on-esxi-6-hosts-with-dutch-operating-systems-vms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 09:35:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/05/04/vmware-tools-update-fails-on-esxi-6-hosts-with-dutch-operating-systems-vms/</guid><description>After upgrading all the hosts in the lab environment to VMware ESXi 6, I tried to upgrade the VMware tools version of a Dutch Windows 7 golden VM used by VMware Horizon View. The VMware tools upgrade fails with the following message:
VMware Tools Setup Wizard ended prematurely
This is a known bug in VMware ESXi 6.</description></item><item><title>Tested SMS PASSCODE multi-factor authentication with VMware Horizon View</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/blog/2015/04/tested-sms-passcode-multi-factor-authentication-with-vmware-horizon-view/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 06:42:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/blog/2015/04/tested-sms-passcode-multi-factor-authentication-with-vmware-horizon-view/</guid><description>Citrix Web Interface Protection RADIUS Protection Cloud Application Protection IIS Web Site Protection ISA/TMG Web Site Protection Windows Logon Protection Secure Device Provisioning (for ActiveSync devices) In this review we test how-to integrate SMS PASSCODE with the latest version of VMware Horizon View using RADIUS authentication.
What is SMS PASSCODE Unlike traditional hardware-token based solutions, SMS PASSCODE works without distribution of any hardware-tokens.</description></item><item><title>Monitor VMware Horizon View environments with ControlUp</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/10/09/controlup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 07:47:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/10/09/controlup/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago ControlUp released version 4.0 with support for VMware Horizon View. In this blog post I share my experience with ControlUp 4.0 monitoring VMware vSphere and VMware Horizon View.
What is ControlUp
ControlUp is a real-time performance monitor for Microsoft Remote Desktop Services (RDS), Citrix, and physical- and virtual server environments.</description></item><item><title>Perform ESXi host maintenance on a VMware Horizon View floating desktop pool</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 13:02:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/08/19/perform-esxi-host-maintenance-on-a-vmware-horizon-view-floating-desktop-pool/</guid><description>When you need to perform maintenance (planned downtime) on an ESXi host which is part of a floating pool the following steps can be be taken:
These steps are only required when using local storage for the linked clones!
In the VMware Horizon View Administrator, edit the pool and uncheck the datastore for the host on which maintenance is required.</description></item><item><title>Display the maximum concurrent connected users in VMware Horizon View with PowerCLI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 09:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/07/23/display-the-maximum-concurrent-connected-users-in-vmware-horizon-view-with-powercli/</guid><description>VMware Horizon View generates everyday at 5 minutes for midnight an event how many concurrent users connected to View that day. This information can be useful for example when when investing trends.
When the Event database in the VMware Horizon View Administrator is configured, this information can be found using the VMware Horizon View Administrator, Monitoring, select Events and filter for “over the past”</description></item></channel></rss>