<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hyper-v-2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/hyper-v-2/</link><description>Recent content in hyper-v-2 on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 09:43:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/tags/hyper-v-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2023/08/31/create-a-windows-11-vm-in-hyper-v-with-packer/</guid><description>Some people ask if it is possible to create a Windows 11 VM in Hyper-V with Packer. The answer is YES. The Packer plugin that makes this possible is called “Hyperv”. Version 1.1.1 supports TPM. Enabling TPM in the Hyper-V VM makes it possible to install Windows 11 without any registry hacks.</description></item><item><title>Run VMware Workstation and Microsoft Hyper-V together in Windows 10</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/09/17/run-vmware-workstation-and-microsoft-hyper-v-together-on-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 14:51:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2020/09/17/run-vmware-workstation-and-microsoft-hyper-v-together-on-windows-10/</guid><description>In 2013 I wrote a blog post that it was not possible to run VMware Workstation when the Hyper-V role was enabled (link ). Since VMware Workstation 15.5 it is possible to run VMware Workstation and the Hyper-V role together.
Requirements:
Windows 10 2004 or newer VMware Workstation 15.5.5 or newer Supported CPU: Intel Sandy Bridge or an AMD Bulldozer or newer I tested this with my Windows 10 laptop with the Hyper-V role enabled, the Windows Subsystem for Linux running, and VMware Workstation 16 Pro.</description></item><item><title>Manage Hyper-V in a workgroup remotely</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/08/28/manage-hyper-v-in-a-workgroup-remotely/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 07:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/08/28/manage-hyper-v-in-a-workgroup-remotely/</guid><description>Managing Hyper-V remotely in a workgroup can be challenging to configure. This is still the case for Windows Server 2016. For a testing environment I needed to remotely manage Windows Server 2016 core server with the Hyper-V role enabled from Windows 10 with the Hyper-V manager. I used the following manual configuration:</description></item><item><title>Test Windows Server 2016 Hyper-V with VMware Workstation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/08/25/easy-way-to-test-windows-server-2016-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/08/25/easy-way-to-test-windows-server-2016-hyper-v/</guid><description>Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 3 (TP3) is released with some cool new features. An easy way to test Windows Server 2016 TP3 is to use VMware Workstation. Windows Server 2016 can be installed with the Hyper-V role and have some VMs nested with minimal configuration.
For this test i used the following hard-and software:</description></item><item><title>Tips for installing System Center Virtual Machine Manager 2012 R2 Update Rollup (UR5)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/02/17/tips-installing-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-2012-r2-update-rollup-ur5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 18:53:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/02/17/tips-installing-system-center-virtual-machine-manager-2012-r2-update-rollup-ur5/</guid><description>Here are some tips for installing System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager Update Rollup (UR5):
UR5 is available from Microsoft Update or by manual download. If you are not installing UR5 through Microsoft Update (e.g. you’re downloading the update and then installing it), you must install using elevated privileges. If you do not do this the update may fail silently.</description></item><item><title>SCVMM 2012 R2 agent update error</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/01/14/scvmm-2012-r2-agent-update-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 22:28:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/01/14/scvmm-2012-r2-agent-update-error/</guid><description>After updating System Center Virtual Machine Manager to Update Rollup 4 (UR4), one of the post installation tasks is updating the VMM agents on the Hyper-V hosts. Updating the VMM agent can be performed from the VMM console or using PowerShell. On one of the Hyper-V hosts I got the following error when trying to update the VMM agent from the console:</description></item><item><title>New whitebox for extending my home lab</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/01/05/new-whitebox-extending-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 11:48:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2015/01/05/new-whitebox-extending-home-lab/</guid><description>For a couple of months I’m searching for an extra whitebox host for extending my home lab environment. My current lab whitebox is a Haswell based whitebox (see: link). Here is an overview of the new lab environment:
For the new whitebox I had the following requirements:
Hardware such as NICs must be recognized by VMware ESXi Use 32 GB memory or more Low power consumption Expandable Small form factor Quiet Possibility to run nested hypervisors such as VMware ESXi and Hyper-V Remote Management Possibility to create a VMware Cluster and use vMotion, HA, DRS and DPM with the existing Haswell host I reviewed the following popular home lab systems:</description></item><item><title>Installing Update Rollup (UR) 3 for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/08/01/installing-update-rollup-3-system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 12:53:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/08/01/installing-update-rollup-3-system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-manager/</guid><description>Update rollup (UR) 3 for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released this week. This update includes a Linux guest agent upgrade to support the following new operating systems:
Ubuntu Linux 14.04 (32-bit) Ubuntu Linux 14.04 (64-bit) This update also includes the following:
Host DHCP extension driver upgrade Several performance improvements?</description></item><item><title>Veeam v8 is coming</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/07/14/veeam-v8-coming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 11:38:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/07/14/veeam-v8-coming/</guid><description>The new version of Veeam is called “Veeam Availability Suite v8”.
The Veeam Availability Suite v8 has improvements in the following areas:
High Speed Recovery Data Loss Avoidance Verified Protection Leverage Data Complete Visibility HIGH-SPEED RECOVERY
Enables low recovery time objectives (RTOs) of &amp;lt;15 minutes; enables rapid recovery of the data customers want, in the form that they want it.</description></item><item><title>Remove an orphaned VM from SCVMM</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/07/08/remove-an-orphaned-vm-from-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 06:40:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/07/08/remove-an-orphaned-vm-from-scvmm/</guid><description>During a migration of a VM from a different cluster the job failed in SCVMM.
The status of the VM in SCVMM Virtual Machine State is still “Starting”.
In SCVMM I was unable to stop, repair or delete the VM. When looking on the Hyper-V host, the VM didn’t exist in Failover Cluster Manager or Hyper-V manager.</description></item><item><title>Unable to perform a Compliance Scan in SCVMM</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/06/19/unable-to-perform-a-compliance-scan-in-scvmm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 06:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/06/19/unable-to-perform-a-compliance-scan-in-scvmm/</guid><description>In System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) an Update (WSUS) Server is added, so VMM can be used to update the hosts with Windows patches.When trying to scan a cluster of hosts for compliance the following error occurred:
Error (24035)
Compliance scan failed with error: 80244017.
Recommended Action:
Ensure the WINHTTP proxy settings are correctly configured for the communications with WSUS.</description></item><item><title>SCVMM library is unable to refesh a file because it is in use</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/06/09/scvmm-library-is-unable-to-refesh-a-file-because-it-is-in-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 14:53:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/06/09/scvmm-library-is-unable-to-refesh-a-file-because-it-is-in-use/</guid><description>In the jobs window in the System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) console , the following warning appeared:
Warning (10803)Unable to refresh \\server\share\ISO\Windows2012 R2\SW_DVD5_Windows_Svr_Std_and_DataCtr_2012_R2_64Bit_English_Core_MLF_X19-05182.ISO because the file is in use by another process.Recommended ActionWait for the next automatic library refresh, or manually refresh the library share after the process completes.</description></item><item><title>Tips for deploying SCVMM 2012 R2 Rollup 2</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 06:56:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</guid><description>Last week Update Rollup 2 (UR2) for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released. UR2 contains important fixes for SCVMM2012 R2. Here are some deployment tips for UR2:
Wait a least couple of weeks before deploying Update Rollups in your production environment. It happens that new Update Rollups contains huge bugs and are pulled back!</description></item><item><title>Check for duplicate MAC Address pools in your Hyper-V environment</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/01/13/check-for-duplicate-mac-address-pools-in-your-hyper-v-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 14:27:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2014/01/13/check-for-duplicate-mac-address-pools-in-your-hyper-v-environment/</guid><description>When enabling the Hyper-V role on a Windows 2012 (R2) server, it creates a dynamic MAC address pool of 256 MAC addresses available for VMs. The MAC Address Pool configuration can be found in the Virtual Switch Manager under the Global Network Settings.
The MAC address pool is generated as follows:</description></item><item><title>Identify LUN IDs in Windows Server 2012 R2</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/26/identify-lun-ids-in-windows-server-2012-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 19:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/26/identify-lun-ids-in-windows-server-2012-r2/</guid><description>During a Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V implementation I needed to identify all the iSCSI disks (LUNs) presented by an EMC VNX SAN to the Hyper-v Failover cluster. Each presented iSCSI disk has a unique LUN ID. To View the LUN ID of a disk, you can use the diskpart command.</description></item><item><title>Running Hyper-V and VMware Workstation on Windows 8.x</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 19:40:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</guid><description>For testing I use Hyper-V and VMware Workstation 10 on my laptop. One restriction of VMware Workstation is that it does not support VHDX disk files (yet). VMware Workstation support VHD files, so the VHDX files must be converted to a VHD first. After the conversion VMware Workstation can select the VHD as Hard Disk.</description></item><item><title>Hyper-V Get Snapshot checkpoint file sizes on Cluster Shared Volumes with PowerShell</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/09/17/list-hyper-v-snapshot-file-sizes-on-cluster-shared-volumes-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 13:39:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/09/17/list-hyper-v-snapshot-file-sizes-on-cluster-shared-volumes-with-powershell/</guid><description>During a Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V Health Check I needed to know the snapshot file sizes for the all the snapshots on the Clustered Shared Volumes (CSVs). The Get-VMCheckpoint Cmdlet does not report the snapshot size. So I create a PowerShell one-liner that displays the following information:
Location of the snapshot file Date and time that the snapshot file was created Last write access time of the snapshot file File size in MBs The PowerShell one-liner is executed from a Hyper-V 2012 host that has access to all the Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs).</description></item><item><title>Haswell low power whitebox for ESXi and Hyper-V</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/25/haswell-low-power-whitebox-for-esxi-and-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/25/haswell-low-power-whitebox-for-esxi-and-hyper-v/</guid><description>I was searching for a new whitebox for my home lab. I had the following requirements for the new whitebox:
Low power consumption for 24x7 running &amp;gt;16 GB memory Expansion slots for PCI(-E) cards Good performance Low noise A couple of weeks ago Intel released the new 4th generation Haswell CPUs that consumes less power.</description></item><item><title>What&amp;rsquo;s new in Windows Server 2012 R2 Hyper-V</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/05/whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-r2-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 17:30:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/06/05/whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-r2-hyper-v/</guid><description>On TechEd Windows Server 2012 R2 is announced. Here are some highlights of “Hyper-V – What’s New in Windows Serve 2012 R2” session (MDC-B330):
Windows Azure IaaS compatibility—Windows Azure IaaS uses exactly the same virtualization as Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V. So VM’s on-premise can be moved to Azure (Iaas) without problems Generation 2 Virtual Machines (VMs).</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V Best Practices</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/03/21/windows-server-2012-hyper-v-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/03/21/windows-server-2012-hyper-v-best-practices/</guid><description>Roger Osborne has create a huge checklist form of best practices on Microsoft Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V. The Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V or Hyper-V 3 best practices focuses on the following topics:
Host settings Anti-virus exclusions Physical NICs settings, NIC teaming, VLANS, Virtual Network Adapters (NICs) Disk settings, VHDX Memory, dynamic memory Cluster settings Hyper-V replica Cluster aware updating SMB 3.</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager has now Hyper-V 2012 support</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/03/19/vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager-has-now-hyper-v-2012-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:52:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/03/19/vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager-has-now-hyper-v-2012-support/</guid><description>VMware has released the beta the public beta of VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager 1.1. This beta supports Microsoft Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V or Hyper-V Server 2012. Another new capability is to migrate VMs from your Hyper-V to your VMware vSphere environment .
The VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager 1.1 is a minor release which introduces the following new capabilities:</description></item><item><title>Health Check your System Center Virtual Machine Server (SCVMM) 2012 environent with PowerShell</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/28/health-check-your-system-center-virtual-machine-server-scvmm-2012-environent-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 10:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/28/health-check-your-system-center-virtual-machine-server-scvmm-2012-environent-with-powershell/</guid><description>Last week I created a simple example of a HealtCheck PowerShell script that connects to Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager and displays information about the Hyper-V hosts and VMs managed by this server.
I run the PowerShell script from another Windows Server 2012 host. To make this work make sure the Hyper-V manager and the VMM Console is installed on the server.</description></item><item><title>Switch between Windows Server 2012 core and Windows Server 2012 GUI</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/22/why-switch-between-windows-server-2012-core-and-windows-server-2012-gui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 08:55:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2013/01/22/why-switch-between-windows-server-2012-core-and-windows-server-2012-gui/</guid><description>In Windows Server 2012 you can choose between a Server Core and Server with a GUI (full) during the installation. The Full Server GUI has all the tools and options to configure and troubleshoot. Server core is a minimal Windows installation with less tools and options.
Server Core has the following advantages over Server Full:</description></item><item><title>Manage Hyper-V from vSphere with VMware vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/11/22/manage-hyper-v-from-vsphere-with-vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 18:42:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/11/22/manage-hyper-v-from-vsphere-with-vmware-vcenter-multi-hypervisor-manager/</guid><description>VMware released the first version (1.0) of the vCenter Multi-Hypervisor Manager (MHM). MHM makes it possible to manage multiple heterogeneous hypervisors in VMware vCenter server.
MHM supports only Microsoft Hyper-V Server 2008 and Microsoft Hyper-V Server 2008 R2 as hypervisor! MHM requires vCenter Server 5.1 and can manage 20 Hyper-V hosts with up to 500 VMs running.</description></item><item><title>Tested: Altaro Hyper-V Backup</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/08/02/tested-altaro-hyper-v-backup/</guid><description>In my LAB environment I tested Altaro Hyper-V Backup version 3. Altaro Hyper-V Backup is software that makes it possible to backup and restore Windows 2008 (R2) Hyper-V VMs.
Editions There are three editions available: The free edition, the standard edition and the unlimited edition. For this test I used the unlimited edition because it supports “Cluster Shared Volumes (CSVs)”.</description></item><item><title>Convert VMware to Hyper-V VMs with Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 12:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/07/30/convert-vmware-to-hyper-v-vms-with-microsoft-virtual-machine-converter/</guid><description>Last week Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter RC is released. Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter is a stand-alone tool that makes it possible to convert and deploys VMware based VMs to Hyper-V based VMs. It’s coverts the VMware VM and virtual disks (VMDK) to Hyper-V VMs and Virtual Hard Disks (VHDs). As virtualization consultant I got “sometimes“ involved in migrating VMware to Hyper-V VMs, so I tried Microsoft Virtual Machine Converter.</description></item><item><title>Nest Windows Server 2012 Hyper-V in VMware ESXi 5</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/28/nest-windows-server-2012-hyper-v-in-vmware-esxi-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 09:57:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/06/28/nest-windows-server-2012-hyper-v-in-vmware-esxi-5/</guid><description>In this blog post I explain how you can install Windows 2012 Server Release Candidate (RC) in VMware ESXi and enable the Hyper-V role. It is possible to build a Hyper-V cluster LAB and live migrate VMs between the virtual Hyper-V nodes on one VMware ESXi 5 host.
Before you begin make sure:</description></item><item><title>Identify NICs in Hyper-V 2012</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/26/identify-nics-in-windows-server-8-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 12:49:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/26/identify-nics-in-windows-server-8-hyper-v/</guid><description>In a Hyper-V cluster are normally a lot of NICs involved. Identifying the right can be challenging. It is important to consequently label your network adapters on all the servers in the Hyper-V cluster.
In Windows Server 2012 there are PowerShell Cmdlets that can be used for identifying NICs. Once you identified the NIC, rename it to meaningful name.</description></item><item><title>Enable Windows Server 8 Hyper-V in VMware Workstation</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 21:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 is available as download. The Technology Preview makes it possible for example to install and operate Windows 8 and Windows Server 8 in a VM and the possibility to nest VMs.
I tested the installation of Windows Server 8 in VMware Workstation TP, enabled the Hyper-V role and run a Windows 7 64-bit VM in Hyper-V.</description></item><item><title>Intel X79 whitebox for vSphere 5 and Hyper-V 3</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/13/intel-x79-whitebox-for-vsphere-5-and-hyper-v-3/</guid><description>In an earlier blog post (found here ) I mentioned that it is time for a new homebrew whitebox based on the Intel X79 chipset. With the X79 chipset it is possible to install 64GB of memory (8 x 8 GB). Because the 8 GB DIMMs are expensive on the moment, I decided to use 8 x 4GB DIMMs (total 32GB).</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2012 PowerShell Cmdlets for Hyper-V help</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/07/windows-server-8-powershell-cmdlets-for-hyper-v-help/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 14:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2012/03/07/windows-server-8-powershell-cmdlets-for-hyper-v-help/</guid><description>In Windows 2008 &amp;amp; Windows2008 R2 there were no official PowerShell Cmdlets available for Hyper-V. This is changed in Windows 2012 and Windows 8. Windows Server 2012 and 8 has 162 or more PowerShell Cmdlets available for Hyper-V. Windows 8 uses PowerShell version 3.
Cmdlets are very powerful, that lets you automate all aspects of Hyper-V.</description></item><item><title>Hyper-V and hibernate</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/21/hyper-v-and-hibernate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 09:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2011/03/21/hyper-v-and-hibernate/</guid><description>For my MS Hyper-V home server I want to hibernate every day between 12.30 and 07.00 am. When the Hyper-V role is installed, it is not possible to use the hibernate function. The following steps make it possible to automatic hibernate the system and when it wake up, the Hyper-V service and the VM(s) are started.</description></item><item><title>Test Microsoft Hyper-V R2 server on your laptop with Virtual Hard Disk (VHD)</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/12/03/test-microsoft-hyper-v-r2-server-on-your-laptop-with-virtual-hard-disk-vhd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 09:29:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/12/03/test-microsoft-hyper-v-r2-server-on-your-laptop-with-virtual-hard-disk-vhd/</guid><description>When you want to test some Microsoft Hyper-V R2 stuff it’s handy to do that on your laptop. I test a lot stuff on my laptop equipped with Microsoft Windows 7, 8GB RAM and VMware Workstation. Installing Microsoft Hyper-V R2 for example in VMware Workstation is possible, but it is not possible to start any Virtual Machines (VMs).</description></item><item><title>Create a bootable USB to install Windows 8 Server or Hyper-V Server 8</title><link>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://demo.gethugothemes.com/logbook/site/2010/10/21/install-microsoft-hyper-v-server-r2-from-usb/</guid><description>Not all servers nowadays have DVD player installed. Sometimes it is handy to boot from USB and install for example Windows Server 8. Here’s a example how to make the USB stick bootable for the following OS versions:
Windows Server 8 Hyper-V Server 8 Server 2008 R2 Hyper-V Server R2 Preparation: Need a 4 GB USB memory stick or more Download the desired ISO and save it Stick the USB stick on a free USB port on your computer equipped with a Windows OS.</description></item></channel></rss>