<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Runecast Analyzer makes hardware checking against the VMware HCL easy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/08/13/runecast-analyzer-makes-hardware-checking-against-the-vmware-hcl-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 07:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/08/13/runecast-analyzer-makes-hardware-checking-against-the-vmware-hcl-easy/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer is a tool that helps VMware administrators to proactive manage there vSphere environment. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. It uses best practices, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STIG, PCI-DSS v3.2.1 and HIPAA) and known issues found in the VMware Knowledge Base to protect the Software Defined Data Center (SDDC). Runecast Analyzer supports the following VMware products:&#xA;VMware vSphere VMware vSAN VMware NSX-V VMware Horizon Runecast Analyzer introduced a new feature called &amp;ldquo;Automated VMware HCL&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ESXi Compatibility Simulation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor vSAN with ControlUp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</guid>
      <description>One of the new enhancements of ControlUp 7.3 is vSAN monitoring support. ControlUp will detect the vSAN cluster(s), objects and displays real-time vSAN specific metrics and metadata. In this blog post I highlight the features of the new vSAN integration in ControlUp 7.3.&#xA;Installation The vSAN cluster is automatically recognized by ControlUp when the following requirements are met:&#xA;PowerShell minimum Version 5.0 VMware PowerCLI 10.1.1.x .NET framework version 4.5 vSAN Performance service should be turned on on the cluster The user account configured for the hypervisor connection requires the “storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New enhancements in Runecast Analyzer 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 09:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer provides proactive management for VMware environments. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. In 90% of the outages with VMware environments, the root cause is based on a known issue that is already available in the VMware knowledge base. Runecast Analyzer uses information from the VMware knowledge base, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STG and PCI-DSS), and best practices to proactively identify problems or outages before they occur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Replication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/23/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 18:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/23/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-replication/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the replication feature. With the replication feature you can replicate VMs. The source VMs are copied, a VM replica is created of each and replicated to the target VMware environment (also known as the recovery site).&#xA;VM Replication protects for example against the following type of disasters:&#xA;Natural disasters (earthquakes, floods, tornados etc.) Data center problems such as power losses, fire and water damage Hardware problems such as host, network and storage failures Human errors VM failures caused by updates or patches, virus or manually removal The replication feature can be used for business continuity as part of you&amp;rsquo;re disaster recovery plan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/01/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 15:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/01/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-released/</guid>
      <description>NAKIVO announced today that NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication v7.5 is out of beta and available. This new version includes the following new features:&#xA;Support for VMware vSphere 6.7: It&amp;rsquo;s now officially compatible with the latest version of VMware vSphere. Cross-Platform Recovery: With the Cross-Platform Recovery feature, users can export VM data from VMware and Hyper-V backups into VMDK, VHD, or VHDX format. The exported files can then be used for recovery across different hypervisors, cross-platform VM data migration, long-term archival, or sandbox testing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
