<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nakivo on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/nakivo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nakivo on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/nakivo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Replication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/23/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 18:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/23/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-replication/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the replication feature. With the replication feature you can replicate VMs. The source VMs are copied, a VM replica is created of each and replicated to the target VMware environment (also known as the recovery site).&#xA;VM Replication protects for example against the following type of disasters:&#xA;Natural disasters (earthquakes, floods, tornados etc.) Data center problems such as power losses, fire and water damage Hardware problems such as host, network and storage failures Human errors VM failures caused by updates or patches, virus or manually removal The replication feature can be used for business continuity as part of you&amp;rsquo;re disaster recovery plan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Backup and Recovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/16/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-backup-and-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 06:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/16/review-nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-backup-and-recovery/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review the backup and recovery options will be highlighted.&#xA;Backup To begin with backup and recovery we first need a backup job. Configuring a backup job contains the following five steps:&#xA;1. VMs: Select the VMs to backup from the inventory of the vCenter Server or ESXi host. 2. Destination: Select the destination to store the VMs. Select the onboard repository with deduplication and compression enabled for storage space savings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 - Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/03/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 07:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/03/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-installation/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication review I highlight the installation and basic configuration.&#xA;For the installation of NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication you have several options. NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication can be installed as&#xA;Windows or Linux installation package Virtual Appliance for VMware (OVF) In the Amazon AWS cloud Directly installed on NAS devices such as QNAP, Synology and NETGEAR In my test environment I installed NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication as Virtual Appliance (VA) on my VMware vSphere 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review NAKIVO Backup &amp; Replication v7.5 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/01/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 15:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/08/01/nakivo-backup-replication-v7-5-released/</guid>
      <description>NAKIVO announced today that NAKIVO Backup &amp;amp; Replication v7.5 is out of beta and available. This new version includes the following new features:&#xA;Support for VMware vSphere 6.7: It&amp;rsquo;s now officially compatible with the latest version of VMware vSphere. Cross-Platform Recovery: With the Cross-Platform Recovery feature, users can export VM data from VMware and Hyper-V backups into VMDK, VHD, or VHDX format. The exported files can then be used for recovery across different hypervisors, cross-platform VM data migration, long-term archival, or sandbox testing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
