<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Horizon-View on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>/categories/horizon-view/</link><description>Recent content in Horizon-View on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/horizon-view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows 10 with Horizon View Agent generates BSOD</title><link>/2015/07/16/windows-10-with-horizon-view-agent-generates-bsod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 13:18:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/07/16/windows-10-with-horizon-view-agent-generates-bsod/</guid><description>After installing the VMware Horizon View Agent (6.1.1) on a Windows 10 (tested with build 10240), it generates a Blue Screen Of Death (BSOD) when pressing Ctrl+Alt+Del/Ins.
The error is:
DRIVER_IRQ_NOT_LESS_OR_EQUAL (kbdclass.sys).
To fix the problem (The solution was found on the Microsoft Community site, link ):
RDP to the Windows 10 VM Edit HKLM\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Class\{4D36E96B-E325-11CE-BFC1-08002BE10318}\UpperFilters Put the kbdclass before the vmkbd value Reboot the VM After changing the UpperFilters value I was able to login the Horizon View desktop without BSOD.</description></item><item><title>VMware Horizon View Client Drive Redirection</title><link>/2015/06/05/vmware-horizon-view-client-drive-redirection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 09:42:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/06/05/vmware-horizon-view-client-drive-redirection/</guid><description>On of the new features of VMware Horizon 6 version 6.1.1 is Client Drive Redirection (CDR). Microsoft RDS and Citrix already have CDR for many years in there product. Now this handy feature is available in Horizon View. CDR is supported on VDI desktops (single-user) and RDS desktops and applications on Windows and as Tech Preview on Mac OS X clients.</description></item><item><title>What VMware Horizon View PowerCLI features you like to see?</title><link>/2015/03/18/what-vmware-horizon-view-powercli-features-you-like-to-see/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/03/18/what-vmware-horizon-view-powercli-features-you-like-to-see/</guid><description>PowerCLI 6.0 R1 is released with some cool new features. One thing I missed in this announcement is improvements in the PowerCLI support for VMware Horizon View. The latest release of VMware Horizon View 6.1 still has NO PowerCLI improvements! This is a huge bummer because PowerCLI is very limited in VMware Horizon View.</description></item></channel></rss>