<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/workstation/</link><description>Recent content in workstation on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Workstation Device/Credential Guard are not compatible</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/12/13/vmware-workstation-device-credential-guard-are-not-compatible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 07:36:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/12/13/vmware-workstation-device-credential-guard-are-not-compatible/</guid><description>When using VMware Workstation 15 Pro with on Windows 10 with the Hyper-V role enabled I’ve got the following error when trying to install or start Windows 10 in VMware Workstation:
VMware Workstation and Device/Credential Guard are not compatible. VMware Workstation can be run after disabling Device/Credential Guard. Please visit http://www.VMware.com/go/turnoff _CG_DG for more details.
In 2013 I did a post about using VMware Workstation and Hyper-V together on Windows 8, link .</description></item><item><title>Running Hyper-V and VMware Workstation on Windows 8.x</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 19:40:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2013/12/16/running-hyper-v-and-vmware-workstation-on-windows-8-x/</guid><description>For testing I use Hyper-V and VMware Workstation 10 on my laptop. One restriction of VMware Workstation is that it does not support VHDX disk files (yet). VMware Workstation support VHD files, so the VHDX files must be converted to a VHD first. After the conversion VMware Workstation can select the VHD as Hard Disk. This can takes some time.
1. VHD disk2. Convert options in Hyper-VThat’s why I use Hyper-V on my laptop sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Enable Windows Server 8 Hyper-V in VMware Workstation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 21:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2012/03/13/enable-windows-server-8-hyper-v-in-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>VMware Workstation Technology Preview 2012 is available as download. The Technology Preview makes it possible for example to install and operate Windows 8 and Windows Server 8 in a VM and the possibility to nest VMs.
I tested the installation of Windows Server 8 in VMware Workstation TP, enabled the Hyper-V role and run a Windows 7 64-bit VM in Hyper-V. Here are some screenshots (Hyper-V manager and the Windows 7 64 bit running in Hyper-V): To make the above configuration work, add to following options to the end of the VMX file before starting the Windows Server 8 installation:</description></item></channel></rss>