<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>update on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in update on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:39:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The new way to patch the vCenter Server Appliance 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/07/30/the-new-way-to-patch-the-vcenter-server-appliance-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 09:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2015/07/30/the-new-way-to-patch-the-vcenter-server-appliance-6/</guid>
      <description>The patching process in vCenter Server Appliance (vCSA) version 6 is changed from previous versions. It is not possible anymore to use the Virtual Appliance Management Interface (VAMI) and update the appliance using the User Interface. The new way to patch the vCenter Server Appliance involves the following steps:&#xA;Download the patch from the VMware Patch Download Center, link . Choose vc and select version 6.x Download the latest patch ISO Attach the *.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for deploying SCVMM 2012 R2 Rollup 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 06:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2014/04/30/tips-for-deploying-scvmm-2012-r2-rollup-pack-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week Update Rollup 2 (UR2) for System Center 2012 R2 Virtual Machine Manager is released. UR2 contains important fixes for SCVMM2012 R2. Here are some deployment tips for UR2:&#xA;Wait a least couple of weeks before deploying Update Rollups in your production environment. It happens that new Update Rollups contains huge bugs and are pulled back! Make sure you have a backup of the SCVMM database before installing UR2 Install the UR2 by download the VMM management server and VMM admin console packages link (or use Windows Update /WSUS to install both packages).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ways to patch your VMware ESX(i) hosts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/03/11/ways-to-patch-your-vmware-esxi-hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 11:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2010/03/11/ways-to-patch-your-vmware-esxi-hosts/</guid>
      <description>There are different ways to patch your VMware ESX(i) 4 hosts. The most common utilities are VMware Update Manager (VUM), vSphere Host Update Utility and the esxupdate command line utility (run from the Service Console) to patch your VMware environment. Here’s explained the differences between them.&#xA;VUM can be used to automated patch your complete environment without user intervention. ESX(i) host are automatically placed in maintenance mode and VM’s are migrated to other VMware ESX(i) host using VMotion and DRS techniques, the host is patched, rebooted and exiting maintenance mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 VM&#39;s spontaneously reboot.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2008/11/19/VMware-esx-35-update-3-vms-spontaneously-reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2008/11/19/VMware-esx-35-update-3-vms-spontaneously-reboot/</guid>
      <description>A week ago i upgraded a customers environment to VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 and VC 2.5 Update 3. After the upgrade some Virtual Machines (VM) spontaneously rebooted. After investing the problem we saw that after a VMotion action the spontaneously reboot occurred.&#xA;We disabled in HA the option &amp;ldquo;Virtual Machine Monitoring&amp;rdquo; and set DRS to manual. The problem with Virtual Machine monitoring is:&#xA;The Virtual Machine heartbeats are being dropped which is triggered by vMotion and the VM gets reset by the HA feature as it thinks it has gone offline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESX/ESXi Update 3 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2008/11/07/VMware-esxesxi-update-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 07:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2008/11/07/VMware-esxesxi-update-3-released/</guid>
      <description>VMware has released Update 3 for ESX/ESXi.&#xA;This new release of ESX/ESXi 3.5 comes with the following enhancements:&#xA;Increase number of vCPUs per Core Limit (from 8 to 20) New supported servers, NICs and storage IO controllers New supported Guest Operating Systems &amp;hellip; and many more improvements and bug fixes. Please refer to the product release notes for the details on improvements and bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
