<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 15:53:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/categories/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pass a GitHub Actions secret variable to a Packer PowerShell provider</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/06/pass-github-variable-to-packer-powershell-provisioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 19:16:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/06/pass-github-variable-to-packer-powershell-provisioner/</guid>
      <description>Automating image deployment with HashiCorp Packer using GitHub Actions is a powerful way to streamline your workflow.&#xA;Sometimes, you need to pass a GitHub Actions (secret) variable to a PowerShell provisioner script in Hashicorp Packer.&#xA;A use case example is if you want to use an Azure Storage Blob Shared Access Signature (SAS) URI as secret in a PowerShell script that downloads software from the Blob storage to the Packer image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for the GitHub Foundations exam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/03/prepare-for-the-github-foundations-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 08:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/blog/2024/03/prepare-for-the-github-foundations-exam/</guid>
      <description>In january 2024 GitHub launched his certification program. There are 4 certifications available:&#xA;GitHub Foundations. Designed to introduce learners new to the GitHub platform fundamental concepts and products of GitHub. GitHub Actions. Designed to learn how to build CI/CD pipelines, manage GitHub Actions for enterprises. GitHub Advanced Security (GHAS). Designed to teach you how to secure your code with advanced security features at every stage of your development lifecycle. GHAS is specific to GitHub Enterprise!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
