<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on IvoBeerens.NL | All about End User Computing, AVD, W365 and Infrastructure as Code (IaC)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:57:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monitor vSAN with ControlUp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2019/03/11/easily-monitor-vsan-with-controlup/</guid>
      <description>One of the new enhancements of ControlUp 7.3 is vSAN monitoring support. ControlUp will detect the vSAN cluster(s), objects and displays real-time vSAN specific metrics and metadata. In this blog post I highlight the features of the new vSAN integration in ControlUp 7.3.&#xA;Installation The vSAN cluster is automatically recognized by ControlUp when the following requirements are met:&#xA;PowerShell minimum Version 5.0 VMware PowerCLI 10.1.1.x .NET framework version 4.5 vSAN Performance service should be turned on on the cluster The user account configured for the hypervisor connection requires the “storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New enhancements in Runecast Analyzer 2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 09:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logbook/site/2018/09/05/new-enhancements-in-runecast-analyzer-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Runecast Analyzer provides proactive management for VMware environments. It discovers potential risks in the VMware environment before they can cause a major outage. In 90% of the outages with VMware environments, the root cause is based on a known issue that is already available in the VMware knowledge base. Runecast Analyzer uses information from the VMware knowledge base, security hardening guides (VMware, DISA STG and PCI-DSS), and best practices to proactively identify problems or outages before they occur.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
